<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Judson L Moore</title>
    <description>Live an adventurous and happy life by pursuing your &quot;what if&quot; in your lifestyle, career, and travel with tips from the author of Exponential Happiness.</description>
    <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.judsonlmoore.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 07:28:45 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 07:28:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Do it while you're young</title>
        <description>Albert Einstein wisely said, “Compound interest is the eighth wonder of the world. He who understands it earns it… he who doesn’t… pays it.” Compound interest is what time gives your financial investments. It is the exponential growth of accumulated interest over time. It is essentially free money awarded to those who start investing while young. In the same way that this principle works in finance, I believe that happiness compounds. Happiness is awarded to those who start living their what if while young. The result is exponential happiness. Those formative younger years, when we have not yet amassed responsibilities to others or crushing debts, gives us the ability to live life for ourselves. We get this one chance to...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-sixth-philosophy-do-it-while-youre-young</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-sixth-philosophy-do-it-while-youre-young</guid>
        
        <category>happiness</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Be flexible in your planning and goals</title>
        <description>Your work isn’t over once you’ve written a plan for accomplishing your life goals. As I said there, “The most important aspect to any plan is the flexibility to change.” This philosophy is critical. A long-term plan will not help you if you do not allow yourself the flexibility to make changes as you go. Having a plan is great and all, but remember, life is complicated. You are always getting new information, and the circumstances are ever-changing. The ability to be flexible is paramount. Flexibility is not about flip-flopping or even changing your mind. It is about allowing yourself and your plan to adapt to a continually evolving environment to ensure success in accomplishing your goals. How...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-fifth-philosophy-be-flexible</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-fifth-philosophy-be-flexible</guid>
        
        <category>happiness</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A bad plan is better than no plan</title>
        <description>Now that you have your what if in mind, you are energized to show up, and you have learned from others around you, what comes next? Well, you need a plan! Just as I draft an outline for my books before I start writing paragraphs, you need to have an idea about the steps necessary to take to reach your goal. As children, we are asked many times about what we want to be when we grow up. Rarely does that conversation continue to discuss how we can live that life. In Chapter 4 of my book, Exponential Happiness, I reveal best practices for discovering the how behind every type of goal. The book walks you through a planning...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-fourth-philosophy-a-bad-plan-is-better-than-no-plan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-fourth-philosophy-a-bad-plan-is-better-than-no-plan</guid>
        
        <category>happiness</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Suffering does not make you stronger; learning does.</title>
        <description>“I had to suffer when I was your age, so you do too; it builds character!” Does this sound familiar to you? I’m afraid I have to disagree with this sentiment. “Character” can be learned in any number of ways, and struggles of the previous generation should not be the struggles of today’s generation. There are plenty of ways to build character. There is no reason to repeat preventable mistakes when they are easily avoidable. Believing that the repetition of the previous generation’s struggles is a rite of passage seems to be more like a way to stifle human progress and creativity than to advance it. When we learn from others’ mistakes without having to repeat them ourselves, it allows...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-third-philosophy-suffering-does-not-make-you-stronger</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-third-philosophy-suffering-does-not-make-you-stronger</guid>
        
        <category>happiness</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Showing up puts you in command of your destiny</title>
        <description>Opportunities are all around us. They take all forms, shapes, and sizes. Sometimes showing up is about going to class prepared with your homework complete. Other times, showing up is about accepting an invitation. Often in life, showing up is about applying for that job you’ve been interested in, the scholarship that will pay for your education, or a fellowship program you think might impact your world-view. Regardless of the form an opportunity takes, it is a wasted chance if you do not show up. There is also something brilliant about showing up. It is the prerequisite of every opportunity. And the fact of the matter is that most people do not bother showing up at all. They have the...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-second-philosophy-show-up</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-second-philosophy-show-up</guid>
        
        <category>happiness</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Find your &quot;what if&quot; and live it every day</title>
        <description>We all have dreams about our future. The places we might visit. The jobs we might have. People with whom we might fall in love. The successes we hope to achieve. Many of these dreams are lofty, as they should be. Dreams are the most significant ambitions of our life. Because dreams are big, they come with a sense of challenge, even sacrifice, which we must make to accomplish them. Many dreams come to us in the form of a what if question. As in, “what if I [insert dream here].” Many people only think about this in hindsight. They ponder, “I wonder what could have been if I had tried to _____.” I find it tragic when people have...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-first-philosophy-find-your-what-if</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-first-philosophy-find-your-what-if</guid>
        
        <category>happiness</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to organize the Jira backlog and Kanban board</title>
        <description>One of my career goals is to work at Atlassian one day because I want to learn how the people who built the Jira project management software use it themselves. I’ve used Jira in a variety of team environments and often get the feeling that it isn’t used correctly, or at the minimum, it isn’t being used very efficiently. Of course, probably the only entity capable of knowing how the software can best be used for a team is by that team itself. How a team works with Jira is dependent on how Jira is set up and what practices of organizing tasks the team incorporates into their general way of working. In this article, I will provide examples of...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jira-backlog-organization</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jira-backlog-organization</guid>
        
        <category>product management</category>
        
        <category>jira</category>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get organized with these Jira task templates</title>
        <description>One of the primary responsibilities of the product management role is to organize a team’s backlog. The more organized the backlog is, and the more detailed the tasks are, the more productive your refinement and planning meetings will be. Having a well-structured set of task templates is a great way to maintain consistency in your tasks, streamlining the foundational step of the team’s way of working. Every team is organized differently, and so these tasks, their structure, and their labels will likely need to be tweaked to best fit your team’s way of working. In fact, with my primary team, we use the hierarchical structure described here but frequently deviate from the task content. The value in these templates is...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jira-task-templates</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jira-task-templates</guid>
        
        <category>product management</category>
        
        <category>jira</category>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I never thought this would happen to me</title>
        <description>Terrible things happen in the world; to individuals, communities, and society as a whole. These events transpire all the time, everywhere. No one is invincible or invulnerable from suffering tragedy. This is hard to acknowledge, and many people ignore these hard realities to their undoing when the inevitable catch them off-guard. By recognizing the possibility that these challenging topics could affect you, you will be better prepared to respond to them if they should happen in your or your loved ones’ lives. It is impossible to be prepared for or have a premeditated response to every single scenario you will face in life. But there are many common scenarios that everyone should spend at least a little effort thinking their...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/i-never-thought-this-would-happen-to-me</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/i-never-thought-this-would-happen-to-me</guid>
        
        <category>disaster</category>
        
        <category>planning</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>COVID-19 Life in Berlin</title>
        <description>The world is in a place of uncertainty right now, and many people are suffering, with their futures unknown. One glimmer of hope throughout this has been the outpouring of messages, checking-in, and a general uptick in (distant) contact we’ve all experienced from those we care for and are cared by but may not have been in touch with for a while. Zoom, Skype, and Facebook Live have quickly taken over the way we communicate with each other. Though those are no replacement for face to face interactions, we do find ourselves now in a position to more easily get in touch with people who we’ve not seen in a while. Thanks to my nomadic lifestyle, it’s been especially meaningful...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/covid-19-life-in-berlin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/covid-19-life-in-berlin</guid>
        
        <category>berlin</category>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>covid-19</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ultimate reading list for product managers</title>
        <description>I’ve been reading product management and other business books, articles, blogs, and listening to industry podcasts for years, even before I was a product manager. Here is a list of some of my favorites that I’ve found or had shared with me. I hope that you will find this ultimate reading list for product managers to be of value to you. Have something to add? Please leave me a comment at the bottom of this page to suggest additions to this list. Books This list contains general management and product management books. Yes, reading in-depth about product management is very valuable. Still, part of what makes a good product manager is broad knowledge, which is why I include general...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ultimate-reading-list-for-product-managers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ultimate-reading-list-for-product-managers</guid>
        
        <category>product management</category>
        
        <category>reading</category>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The consequences of Rotary Youth Programs</title>
        <description>For those who know me and much of my personal story, you’ve probably heard me talk more than a few times about Rotary International. If you’re not fully aware of what Rotary is and does, well, it’s a lot. Rotary is an international service organization focused on addressing community needs and supporting programs that make the world a more connected and healthier place for everyone. At the international level, Rotary is well-known for their End Poilo Now program, which has very nearly accomplished its goal of eradicating polio from this world. As of this writing, only 17 cases of polio remain on Earth. Amazing! Rotary also supports various scholarships, study abroad programs, cultural exchanges, and peace fellowships, all under...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/consequences-of-rotary-youth-programs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/consequences-of-rotary-youth-programs/</guid>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>youth exchange</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three lies about Rome uncovered</title>
        <description>Rome has been my #1 must-see European destination since I moved to Germany nearly four years ago and yet I only recently made my first trip to the ancient metropolis. It was Valentine’s weekend and the weather was picture-perfect for making memories in the city. As is now my custom when visiting new cities, I started the first morning with a free walking tour to get my bearings and to gain some quick local insights. The tour started at the Spanish Steps and ended at Castel Sant’Angelo with a Vatican View. Along the way, we stopped off at the Column of Marcus Aurelius, the Temple of Hadrian, the Pantheon and Piazza Navona. Our guide, Laura, did a fantastic job...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/three-lies-about-rome-uncovered/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/three-lies-about-rome-uncovered/</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>italy</category>
        
        <category>rome</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A sensible definition of &quot;Ready for Dev&quot;</title>
        <description>The desired outcome of a product backlog refinement meeting is to move tasks from the backlog into the Ready for Dev column. But what is the best “Definition of Ready?” Reading around the interwebs leads to many definitions to this term, “ready,” but none of the ones I’ve found are quite as straightforward or as exacting as the definition I use with my teams. Therefore, I’d like to share my simple philosophy about defining “Ready for Dev” with you here and now. Just note that this is more a philosophy for building team culture than it is merely a way to advance the work of a product. My goal for refinement meetings is not only to move tasks around but...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ready-for-dev</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ready-for-dev</guid>
        
        <category>product management</category>
        
        <category>jira</category>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to migrate from Wordpress to Jekyll with CircleCI and AWS</title>
        <description>By migrating my blog from Wordpress to Jekyll, I decreased my page load time from 7.5 seconds to .380ms. Furthermore, I learned a lot of useful web development technical skills in the process. The steps outlined here are somewhat involved, but if you have an interest in seeing this through to the end and are willing to read several how-to guides for the various steps, then migrating from Wordpress to Jekyll is something anyone can do. Find the source code on this GitHub repository Why I wanted to migrate my blog from Wordpress to Jekyll My daytime profession is as a software product manager. This means that I am sitting web engineer adjacent but don’t need any technical...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/how-to-migrate-wordpress-to-jekyll</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/how-to-migrate-wordpress-to-jekyll</guid>
        
        <category>product management</category>
        
        <category>web development</category>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        
        <category>career</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My interview on LeanPub's Frontmatter Podcast</title>
        <description>Just before I published my first book, Exponential Happiness, my publisher, LeanPub, honored me with a feature on their podcast for authors. We had quite a long chat, but it is pretty interesting if I may say so myself. Len Epp is Leanpub’s co-founder. During his interview, we discussed:  My background The Rotary summer camp that changed my life My youth exchange year abroad in Germany My parents’ activism for the rights of people with disabilities and their families My time in the Peace Corps in Kyrgyzstan where I established a network for journalists My brief high-rise construction career in India My eventual return to Germany My book (of course!) My experience as a self-published author ...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-leanpub-frontmatter-podcast/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-leanpub-frontmatter-podcast/</guid>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
        <category>life story</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips for how to successfully find work abroad as an American</title>
        <description>The whole reason I started this blog was to publicly answer the question I have been asked for many years, “Judson, how do you get to travel so much?” The answer to that is varied and complicated if you want it to be. On one side, it is as simple as saying that I just packed my bag and went for it, but of course, there is a lot of planning that goes into making the plans that lead to a successful experience abroad. I don’t regret any of my moves abroad, but not all of them have worked out as hoped. For many years, Europe seemed to be a black box as an American trying to work there. I...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/working-abroad-tips</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/working-abroad-tips</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>inspiration</category>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Lost City of Petra is More Amazing Than I Ever Imagined</title>
        <description>The lost city of Petra, of Indiana Jones fame, sits in the southern territories of Jordan, between Amman and Wadi Rum. This UNESCO World Heritage Site has been on my bucket list for a long time and I am glad to report that it does not disappoint. All I really knew about Petra was The Treasury building, which is famous for being the resting place of the Holy Grail in the 1989 film Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade. I was thrilled to descend the long and winding Siq, or path, into Petra, where The Treasury is not the first thing you see along the path, and as it turns out, it is not nearly the last thing either. Petra In...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/petra-jordan-destination-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/petra-jordan-destination-guide</guid>
        
        <category>mena</category>
        
        <category>jordan</category>
        
        <category>petra</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mars on Earth - The Wadi Rum Desert in Jordan</title>
        <description>Wadi Rum’s Hollywood Fame and Tourism Wadi Rum is an iron-rich desert in the south of Jordan which is famous for its Mars-like landscapes. The iron and mineral content of the sand here gives the desert a red coloring which is unlike anything you can see elsewhere on the planet. Because of this, Wadi Rum has become a popular destination for Hollywood to film. Films such as Lawrence of Arabia, which kickstarted the tourism industry in this area of Jordan, and more recently, The Martian, have brought fame and tourism to the desert for decades. Getting to Wadi Rum is actually a lot easier than you might suspect. If you are already in the area, visiting other parts of...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/wadi-rum-jordan-destination-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/wadi-rum-jordan-destination-guide</guid>
        
        <category>mena</category>
        
        <category>jordan</category>
        
        <category>wadi rum</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DRUMSON performs live at the trivagoVibe</title>
        <description>I love working at trivago! The company embodies many of my core passions: technology and innovation, travel, multiculturalism, and on occasion, music! The trivagoVibe is a bi-annual concert of trivago’s musically-talented employees. It is the activity where I have the most fun at work (and yes, that includes the famed trivago on Tour annual trip. Nothing beats live music in my book, and at trivago, live music means trivagoVibe! trivago recently moved into a new spaceship-like campus in Düsseldorf, an incredible facility in every way, including lots of open-air spaces which are perfect for music. During the past trivagoVibes, I didn’t have the opportunity to perform, and so this time, I was as proactive as possible to make sure...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/trivagovibe-summer-2018</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/trivagovibe-summer-2018</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Without a Path Podcast asked me to share travel advice in Kyrgyzstan</title>
        <description>The Without a Path Podcast with the American writer, traveler, and meddler Joe Baur is chock full of intriguing chats with creative types, adventurers, and the occasional story of hope for humanity. Guests share stories about the travels, which have helped define their lives in this weekly travel podcast. I highly encourage you to subscribe to the Without A Path Podcast on iTunes. My interview on the podcast focuses on stories from Kyrgyzstan, how I got there, what I was doing there, and what has happened in the country since I left in 2015. To learn more about Joe Baur, the Without a Path Podcast, or even suggest yourself or someone else as a guest of the show, check out &lt;a...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/without-a-path-podcast</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/without-a-path-podcast</guid>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Edinburgh Castle Walking Tour</title>
        <description>After having spent my morning taking a free walking tour, I decided it was worth buying a ticket to one of the afternoon paid tours. The tour organizer, SANDEMANs, had several to chose from but I was most interested in getting to know the Edinburgh Castle. So after a quick lunch on my own, I rejoined my trusty (and awesome) guide, Dave, and off we went together on the Edinburgh Castle walking tour. This tour runs daily in the afternoon. Check the SANDEMANs website for schedules and ticket information. Keeping things simple, our meeting point was at the same location as the free walking tour, on The Royal Mile. Our group was small, just 7 of us....</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/edinburgh-castle-walking-tour</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/edinburgh-castle-walking-tour</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>scotland</category>
        
        <category>edinburgh</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Edinburgh Free Walking Tour</title>
        <description>I am believing more and more that the very best way to start any trip is with a free walking tour. These tours are offered in many of the world’s top destinations and are a great way to quickly orient yourself to the highlights a city has to offer. Most walking tours do not go inside of the sites, churches, and castles, but rather offer stories and a local’s perspective on what makes the city unique. If you kick off a weekend trip with a free walking tour, then you will be well-equipped to spend the next days getting to know the city in greater detail on your own. There are many Edinburgh free walking tours to choose from but...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/edinburgh-free-walking-tour</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/edinburgh-free-walking-tour</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>scotland</category>
        
        <category>edinburgh</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things to Do in Dublin - A 3-day Weekend Itinerary</title>
        <description>There are an incredible array of things to do in Dublin, so if you are visiting for a short weekend, it can be a bit overwhelming to figure out how to best make use of your time. I recently had the good fortune of spending a week in Dublin. While there, I visited a lot of places, some were undeniably incredible, while others I could have lived without. In this article, I highlight the very best from my time in Dublin and schedule it out for you in an easy to follow guide which can serve as an outline for things to do in Dublin as you plan your trip there. Should you have feedback, additions, or questions, please leave...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dublin-weekend-itinerary</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dublin-weekend-itinerary</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>ireland</category>
        
        <category>dublin</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Visiting the Guinness Storehouse in Dublin</title>
        <description>The Guinness Storehouse in Dublin is the traditional home of the world’s most famous stout beer: Guinness. This 200+ year-old city within a city is a major contributor to modern Irish history and to the island’s economy and world fame. Guinness is known the world over as a premium stout. It’s not the kind of beer you drink every day or in large quantity. It stands out as being quite different from any other beer you will find because it is black, creamy, and served on nitro, which means you also have to have a fairly sophisticated setup just to pour it properly. So how does a beer with so many complications and which is so limited in drinkability end...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/guinness-storehouse-dublin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/guinness-storehouse-dublin</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>ireland</category>
        
        <category>dublin</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jameson distillery tour and whiskey tasting experience in Dublin</title>
        <description>When visiting Dublin there are a few staple must-do activities and tourist traps you simply have to fall in to. Drink a Guinness? Check! Go for a hike? Check! Have a whiskey distillery tour and whiskey taste testing? Check check! Welcome to the home of Ireland’s most famous whiskey: The Jameson Distillery on Bow St. There are a number of activities and tours you can take while visiting The Jameson Distillery but I am going to focus on two: The Jameson Distillery Tour, and the Premium Whiskey Tasting. Now, don’t get me wrong, I was raised in Kentucky (hint, that is foreshadowing..) but I have never been to a proper whiskey taste testing. I have done more than my share...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jameson-distillery-tour-dublin</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jameson-distillery-tour-dublin</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>ireland</category>
        
        <category>dublin</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My most traveled year. A photo review of 2017.</title>
        <description>America inaugurated a new president, Brittan triggered article 50, and North Korea tested ballistic missiles, all the while, the globe continues to get warmer. With headlines like those, it makes any accomplishments or activities in my life seem hardly worth noting. Perhaps the best thing about being an Expat in Germany is that it is like living on cloud 9, so despite being a news and politics junkie, I maintain a high degree of happiness. So what am I doing with my abundance of happiness? Well, 2017 was my most-traveled year, having visited 11 countries. I also started a new job at trivago as a product owner overseeing the trivago website’s development. This was a significant career change as it...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/annual-photo-review-2017</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/annual-photo-review-2017</guid>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
        <category>holiday</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I have learned about my Peace Corps legacy in Kyrgyzstan</title>
        <description>I just returned from a 2-week trip to Kyrgyzstan. “Kyrgyz-what???” you say? Exactly. Well, if you have been paying attention to my writings the last years then you will recall that I served in the US Peace Corps from 2011-2013 in Kyrgyzstan. Kyrgyzstan is a gorgeous and remote country in the heart of Central Asia. Europeans who visit the country refer to it as the Switzerland of Central Asia. The history of the country is steeped in nomadic traditions, and it was once a major route along the Silk Road. During my time there, I came to truly love the country and adore its people and culture. I had not been back since the end of my service over...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/my-peace-corps-legacy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/my-peace-corps-legacy</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>service above self</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to spend a day in Denmark - A bike tour of Copenhagen</title>
        <description>Biking my heritage in Copenhagen Many moons ago, my family made the treacherous journey across the Atlantic Ocean to immigrate to the United States. What they left behind was a life in Denmark. Now, much to my surprise, and thanks to a company cruise I took with trivago, I find myself arriving at the shores of my forefathers. I only have a day to get to know this land, and I can’t think of a better way to do it than a bike tour of Copenhagen! #yeahbike! My bike tour group had 15 people in it and we were led by an awesome guide name Julia. It was clear from the start that Julia understands that she lives...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bike-tour-copenhagen</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bike-tour-copenhagen</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>scandinavia</category>
        
        <category>denmark</category>
        
        <category>copenhagen</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to spend a day in Norway - Hiking in Baneheia Park in Kristiansand</title>
        <description>I never thought I would spend 6-hours in Norway Recently, I had the opportunity to visit Kristiansand, Norway for the first time thanks to a company trip I took with trivago. Not only was this my first time to Norway, but it was also the furthest north I had ever been. As excited as I was for this opportunity, there was one catch: we were on a cruise. This means that I had to figure out how to spend just 1 day in Norway. Luckily, there wasn’t much for me to figure out, as our organizers did all the heavy lifting. For anyone else who only gets to spend a day in Norway, you might have some problems...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/baneheia-kristiansand-norway</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/baneheia-kristiansand-norway</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>scandinavia</category>
        
        <category>norway</category>
        
        <category>kristiansand</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What happened when I traveled alone in Beijing</title>
        <description>Breaking Through the Fear of Travel I sat on a bench just at the end of the thick stone bridge overlooking the icy, white Houhai Lake. The day was bright. Even brighter with the hazy sky against it. The iced lake looked like a thick layer of clouds and I was at the edge of a cliff. Just to the left of me was a line of trees hugging the edge I imagined I was on. The famous Marble Boat of Beijing’s Summer Palace was docked just near the edge of the bridge, anchored in by the thick ice. Just a year before, I added this place, this moment, to a long list of things I wanted to...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/traveling-alone-beijing</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/traveling-alone-beijing</guid>
        
        <category>guest author</category>
        
        <category>female travel</category>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 reasons why giving thanks is good for you</title>
        <description>There are many reasons to work on improving how we give thanks. Ranging from health benefits, feeling good, and changing the world, expressions of gratitude go a long way in helping us live more fulfilling and joyous lives. I am very grateful for many things. But if I am honest, I don’t express my gratitude to others nearly as often as I should. I don’t often express gratitude out loud to others, even when that gratitude is conscious in my mind at the moment. This is an area where I know I can become better, and I bet I am not alone. Let me start with this: I am grateful for you.  That felt great! And now, what benefits can we...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/giving-thanks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/giving-thanks</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>inspiration</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>trivago on Tour - Cruise 2017 to Norway and Denmark</title>
        <description>trivago on Tour: The Pinnacle of Office Culture I have had the good fortune to work at one of Europe’s best companies for employee satisfaction: trivago. The hotel metasearch, known worldwide for its guerilla television marketing tactics and services for helping travelers find their ideal hotel at the best available rate, is a German-based company with a fantastic workplace culture. The cultural highlight of the year for trivago employees is trivago on Tour. Read more: How metasearch saves me loads of time and money What is trivago on Tour? trivago on Tour is an annual trip for all trivago employees. The activities and destination are closely guarded secrets, leaving employees with only rumors, gossip, and dreaming of...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/trivago-tour-2017</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/trivago-tour-2017</guid>
        
        <category>copenhagen</category>
        
        <category>denmark</category>
        
        <category>norway</category>
        
        <category>road trip</category>
        
        <category>travel tale</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Expat Sandwich Podcast features my story of serving humanity.</title>
        <description>The Expat Sandwich Podcast features Americans living abroad and the crazy antics they encounter worldwide. The show’s producer, Marty Walker, and I had a wonderful time talking, and she did a brilliant job of presenting my story on her podcast. You can play the episode below, but I highly encourage you to subscribe to the podcast and leave it a 5-star review on iTunes. Please listen, share, and comment below with your thoughts!  Show Notes I talked about a lot in this episode of Expat Sandwich. Here are some notes and links to things I discussed in my conversation with Marty Walker.  ...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/expat-sandwich-podcast</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/expat-sandwich-podcast</guid>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Interview with Aniko Villalba of the Viajando Por Ahí Travel Blog</title>
        <description>Aniko Villalba is an Argentinean-Hungarian author and true citizen of the world. She has spent the last decade traveling the world and sharing her experiences as the author of three books and the Viajando Por Ahi Blog. I had an opportunity to meet Aniko in Düsseldorf, Germany, where she gave a presentation at trivago about her life and career as a digital nomad. After the presentation, I was invited to join her and a small group to dinner. We got to talking and I became deeply captivated by the rest of her story and candor. In a world full of dreamers, she fits right in, but she is not afraid to tell it like it is and shed...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/aniko-villalba-interview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/aniko-villalba-interview</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>argentina</category>
        
        <category>guest author</category>
        
        <category>female travel</category>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In the south of Brazil, find Germany in the town of Blumenau</title>
        <description>Far from Germany, Blumenau is all Deutsch In the southern Brazilian state of Santa Catarina is a city called Blumenau, which is as German as any city in Germany (and I know, I live in Germany!) From the cobblestone streets, to the post-and-beam architecture, and the bakeries on every corner, you wouldn’t know you are not in Germany if you just woke up here one day. A buddy of mine, Leo, who I was visiting in Florianópolis, had a family apartment in Blumenau, so we decided to go spend a few days there. He and I met while we were both Rotary Youth Exchange students in Germany, so getting to experience the German culture together again was quite special....</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/blumenau-brazil-travel-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/blumenau-brazil-travel-guide</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>brazil</category>
        
        <category>santa catarina</category>
        
        <category>blumenau</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beach, innovation, and majestic views. Welcome to Florianopolis, Brazil.</title>
        <description>An island of the land Florianopolis has received accolades from The New York Times, Newsweek and others ranging from marking the city as the party destination of the year to being in the top ten most dynamic cities worldwide. I was visiting a friend in Florianopolis who I got to know while in Germany as a Rotary Youth Exchange student. His family lived on the beach-facing side of the island, so I really got to experience the beach life of Florianopolis more than anything else. Though I am starting to feel a bit repetitive in my describing of Brazilian beaches, like that of Porto Seguro in the north of Brazil, this beach has a totally different vibe. Now that we are further...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/florianopolis-brazil-travel-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/florianopolis-brazil-travel-guide</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>brazil</category>
        
        <category>santa catarina</category>
        
        <category>florianopolis</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Visit Brazil - A guide to when, where, and how to visit Brazil</title>
        <description>Imagine yourself going on an adventure in the Amazon Forest or in the Pantanal, being amazed by the beauty of the nature in Foz do Iguaçu or Bonito, living the culture of São Luís or Ouro Preto, trying the hustle and bustle of great centers such as Rio de Janeiro or São Paulo, or simply relaxing and enjoying the sun and the breeze of the ocean in Fernando de Noronha or Trancoso. This is what you can discover when you visit Brazil. Brazil is a continental country: Its 3.3 million square miles make up almost half of South America. Containing six biomes, the country holds the largest biodiversity on the planet, not to mention...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/visit-brazil-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/visit-brazil-guide</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>brazil</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Porto Seguro is the best beach town in the whole world. Here is why.</title>
        <description>Porto Seguro: My favorite beach in the world As a ginger kid, beaches and I don’t usually get along so well. I rarely find that the exposure to so much direct sunlight is worth the payoff of the activities which come along with being at the beach. Despite its proximity to the Equator, Porto Seguro in the state of Bahia in Brazil is somehow the perfect beach setup for a ginger like me. There are ample shaded sitting areas directly on the beach and lots of historic sites and tours to occupy yourself with during the peak sun hours. After spending a week in the mountain town of Diamantina for Carnival, visiting the beach scene of Porto Seguro was quite...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/porto-seguro-brazil-travel-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/porto-seguro-brazil-travel-guide</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>brazil</category>
        
        <category>bahia</category>
        
        <category>porto seguro</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Diamantina Brazil is a sleepy town with a party spirit</title>
        <description>From New Orleans to Diamantina Brazil, Carnival reigns supreme Diamantina Brazil is a tiny town about 4 hours north of Belo Horizonte, the capital of the state of Minas Gerais. I visited this unlikely party town during the Carnival season and it was full of energy and excitement. I come from the state of Louisiana in the southern part of the USA. In Louisiana, we celebrate Mardi Gras, which is just the French name for Carnival. Needless to say, I felt right at home amongst the street dancing, live music, and historic architecture. Of course, this was no New Orleans Mardi Gras. This was something totally new to me. The conditions more rustic, the air more breathable, the...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/diamantina-brazil-travel-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/diamantina-brazil-travel-guide</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>brazil</category>
        
        <category>minas gerais</category>
        
        <category>diamantina</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Belo Horizonte is a historic and cultural capital of Brazil</title>
        <description>Belo Horizonte Travel Guide Belo Horizonte is Brazil’s sixth-largest city and the capital of the state of Minas Gerais. This well-planned city has sprawling tree-lined boulevards and ample green space to enjoy. The surrounding area is full of colonial historical sites and other great destinations, such as Ouro Preto. If you are into nature, history, art, or nightlife, Belo Horizonte is a great destination to include on your next trip to Brazil. I came to Belo Horizonte to visit my friend Lilian and her now husband, Glauco. I knew Lilian from my Rotary Youth Exchange year in Germany. Lilian and her family would later host me for 6-weeks while I explored Belo Horizonte and the surrounding area. It came to...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/belo-horizonte-travel-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/belo-horizonte-travel-guide</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>brazil</category>
        
        <category>minas gerais</category>
        
        <category>belo horizonte</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Interview with Jenna Davis of Give For Granted</title>
        <description>GIVE FOR GRANTED FOUNDER JENNA DAVIS I came to know Jenna Davis while living in Düsseldorf Germany where I work, and where she has perfected the art of making play, work. Jenna is a rare breed. She is one who stood up and said, “yes!” Her story is truly one of living ones’ “what if,” and I am thrilled to have had the opportunity to interview her and learn about her journey in life. Enjoy the interview, get inspired, and leave Jenna a comment below. Connect with Jenna Davis and with Give For Granted:    GiveForGranted.com   Facebook   Twitter   YouTube   Instagram    MANY PEOPLE DREAM OF QUITTING THEIR 9-5 JOB AND...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jenna-davis-give-for-granted-interview</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jenna-davis-give-for-granted-interview</guid>
        
        <category>guest author</category>
        
        <category>female travel</category>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Weekend Trips - Quick Tips for the Jetsetter and Novice Traveler Alike</title>
        <description>So this is kind of a comprehensive mini-guide to traveling, inspired by my travels around Southeast Asia. These are the best tips and tricks for quick, easy, and affordable travel; good for everything from studying abroad to weekend trips and road-tripping around your state. Special thanks to Michelle, Annie, Britt, and Eileen for contributing ♥ you guys are great. You can also check out my photo journals for Indonesia, Malaysia, Taiwan, Thailand, and Cambodia! Preparing for a weekend trip 1. Get a good credit card - This is a good contingency plan to have for emergencies. Of course, if it’s just a one-time trip, it may not justify committing to...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/weekend-trips-quick-tips</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/weekend-trips-quick-tips</guid>
        
        <category>guest author</category>
        
        <category>female travel</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Interview with Global Skier Laura Davies of the ForeverWinter Project</title>
        <description>I recently had the opportunity to sit down with Laura Davies as she pursues an epic journey chasing winter around the world. The ForeverWinter Project is Laura’s dream to spend a year skiing a different country every month. As ambitious as that may sound, as you will read in the following interview, she is set to far surpass her goal and to experience many other unknowable things. Be sure to follow The ForeverWinter Project on Instagram @ForeverWinterProject. “ForeverWinter Project” is a unique name for your adventure. What inspired this name? I always loved the name Never Summer and thought it would be cool to have a skier brand with a similarly clever name. My friend Tim and I...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-foreverwinter-project-laura-davies</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-foreverwinter-project-laura-davies</guid>
        
        <category>guest author</category>
        
        <category>female travel</category>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Questions to Ask Before You Book a Riad in Morocco</title>
        <description>The allure of Morocco Morocco is among the most alluring and mystical destinations in the world. Its easy access from Europe and North America place it as a great port of entry into the MENA region and the rich and colorful cultures of the Arab world. The former French colonial influences of Morocco provide some hints of Western familiarity, while still being genuinely its own place, with parts seemingly untouched for a thousand years. Part of what makes a trip to Morocco particularly worthwhile is the ability to safely explore nearly any part of the country without fear of dangers. From the High Atlas Mountains to the Sahara Desert, and the relaxed beaches of Casablanca and Rabat, this North...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/book-a-riad-morocco</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/book-a-riad-morocco</guid>
        
        <category>mena</category>
        
        <category>morocco</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Young, free, and female. How to be happy in a world full of choice and pressure.</title>
        <description>Being happy starts and ends with you Life is short. Sometimes I feel like it was just yesterday that I was a freshman moving into my dorm room, and sometimes that feels like forever ago (even though it was only four and a half years ago). Some days I’d give anything to go back and relive my freshman year of college, and others, I cringe at the thought of having to relive that period of my life. There are days when I still feel like a little kid who just needs her mom and days when I feel like an independent woman just trying to make her way in the world. But when it comes down to it, no matter...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/young-free-female-happy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/young-free-female-happy</guid>
        
        <category>guest author</category>
        
        <category>female travel</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Best podcast 2017 - What I listen to for my daily dose of inspiration</title>
        <description>Since I was a teenager, I have been a bit of a political junkie. I grew up in a politically active family, studied political science at university, and lobbied Congress more times than I can recall. So as you might imagine, I absorbed every ounce of news coverage and reading that I could during the last U.S. presidential election. By the time the party conventions arrived in July 2016, I was so burned out on the divisive and toxic nature of the whole thing that I was desperate for something new. I turned to podcasts. Podcasts were the perfect way for me to stay engaged, get inspired, and continue the pursuit of knowledge while on the go or while busy with...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/best-podcast-2017</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/best-podcast-2017</guid>
        
        <category>podcasts</category>
        
        <category>top list</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ouro Preto Brazil is the heart of Brazil, Revolution, and an economic explosion</title>
        <description>Ouro Preto is a small colonial town in the heart of the Brazilian state of Minas Gerais, near to Belo Horizonte. The entire town was Brazil’s first place to be designated a UNESCO world heritage site, due to its vast historical significance from the early days of Portuguese colonization of Brazil and for its high quality of architectural preservation. Similar to the “go west young man” slogans in America which were inspired by the California Gold Rush, colonial settlers were jumping over each other to get to Ouro Preto first to unearth the rich gold and mineral resource found there. ‘Ouro Preto’ means ‘black gold,’ and it is this gold which spurred an explosion of colonial exploration away from...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ouro-preto-brazil-travel-guide</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ouro-preto-brazil-travel-guide</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>brazil</category>
        
        <category>minas gerais</category>
        
        <category>ouro preto</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 10 American Cities for Living Without a Car in 2017</title>
        <description>Living without a car in America: First Impressions Are you tired of sitting in traffic every day and wish you could be set free in a place where the city moves you around, rather than sticks you in place? Walkable paths, bikeable streets, and public transit which is as dependable as it is affordable is just one part of what makes great cities great, but a very important element indeed! In addition to promoting physical and mental health, these elements go a long way to making living without a car possible. So where are these centers of car-less freedom? Redfin’s latest report combines Walk, Transit and Bike score data to determine the best cities in the U.S. for...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/top-10-american-cities-living-without-car</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/top-10-american-cities-living-without-car</guid>
        
        <category>north america</category>
        
        <category>united states of america</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Enjoy the taste of crow - an interview with Scott Holiday of the Rival Sons</title>
        <description>Scott Holiday and the Taste of Crow I caught up with rock band Rival Sons while on tour in Europe to get a sense of life on the road, the band’s creative spirit, and where they are headed next with their music. Guitarist Scott Holiday sat down with me for an interview backstage on February 21, 2017, in Cologne, Germany. Scott tells me some hilarious stories from touring with Black Sabbath and opens up his heart about the pain of being away from family while on the road. But above all, we get some insights into how Rival Sons teaches that rock how to roll eight years on. How is the tour going? Where are you all at right now? Scott...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-scott-holiday-rival-sons</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-scott-holiday-rival-sons</guid>
        
        <category>celebrity encounter</category>
        
        <category>interview</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 simple tips to prepare your phone for travel</title>
        <description>Phone Travel in a Nutshell Everyone who travels has a phone. This is a fact of modern life. As accustomed as we are to carrying around these devices in our pockets, even the most frequent flyers can get a little squeamish about switching them on abroad. What is worse: to have no phone access abroad, or to pay through the nose for it? Follow these 5 simple steps to use your phone abroad and spend your money on more interesting things. 1. Check Your Phone Status First, make sure the iPhone is unlocked. Most are; Verizon automatically are; you may have to request it from AT&amp;amp;T. You’ll want to make sure it is unlocked before leaving the US. 2. Change Your...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/phone-travel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/phone-travel</guid>
        
        <category>iphone</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is metasearch and how it saves you loads of time and money</title>
        <description>I recently started a new job working at trivago as their B2B spokesperson for the United States. trivago is the world’s largest hotel metasearch, helping travelers find their ideal hotel at the best available rate. Since I started working there, I have found myself thinking many times that most people probably do not know what metadata is, and therefore do not know what is metasearch or why they should care. So let me take a moment to explain what this term means and how these tools can save you loads of time and money. Related Post: 20 Essential Travel Apps Since I am working at trivago, I should mention that this post is not a sponsored post, the content is...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/what-is-metasearch</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/what-is-metasearch</guid>
        
        <category>trivago</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Must Write A Book! A Review Of Honorée Corder's Latest Inspiration</title>
        <description>YOU must write a book, and with Honorée Corder’s 50th and most recent book self-published, you will not only learn how to write a book, but you will also get inspired to put pen to paper. You Must Write A Book is the fastest book I have ever read, finishing it in just two sittings. I walked away, smarter, inspired, and empowered. Give this book a read, and even if you’ve never considered the notion, you might just find yourself writing a book! In A Nutshell Highlights - Covers every aspect of what it means to write a book: ideation, structuring, planning, publishing, promoting, and more. Details are as in-depth as they are wide while still being an easy book to digest....</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/honoree-corder-review-must-write-book</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/honoree-corder-review-must-write-book</guid>
        
        <category>reading list</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Iguazu Falls Are More Than The World's Largest Waterfall System</title>
        <description>Iguazu Falls Recap My journey to the Iguazu Falls is woven with the most thrilling story I have to tell. The majestic landscape of the Falls is nearly indescribable. I will do my best here to not only describe the experience I had, but to also convince you to make a visit as soon as possible. The story I will tell is one of a desperate, young (clueless), American backpacker and the most beautiful place with a surprise lurking around every corner. Buckle up, this ride is going to get a little bumpy! In A Nutshell Highlights - The Iguazu Falls Park is clean, well-organized, affordable, and unbelievably breathtaking. The border crossings between Brazil, Argentina, and Paraguay give...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/iguazu-falls-largest-waterfall-system</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/iguazu-falls-largest-waterfall-system</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>argentina</category>
        
        <category>brazil</category>
        
        <category>parana</category>
        
        <category>foz do iguacu</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>German Wine Country - A Taste of Landau and the Pfirmann Weingut</title>
        <description>A Weekend In The German Wine Country After a short 3 hour drive south on the German Autobahn from Düsseldorf, just past Frankfurt, I found myself standing in a rolling green field of my favorite plant: the Vitis! More commonly known as grapevines! Yes, I am in Landau, the heart of German Wine Country. I am here this weekend with some friends to do some wine tasting at the Weingut Pfirmann (on Facebook). The winery is a small, 4th generation family-owned and operated establishment with chic style on every inch of the bottle, the equipment, and the tasting room. If you are able to make a trip to Landau I recommend staying at the Heiligenthaler Hof Apartments and Rooms which are super nice and come at...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/german-wine-country</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/german-wine-country</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>pfalz</category>
        
        <category>landau</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lost or Stolen Passport? Stay Calm and Follow These Instructions.</title>
        <description>You’re planning your next adventure, or perhaps you are out somewhere in the world discovering new sights, smells, and sounds. Then you come to a panicked realization: I have lost my passport! Yes, this is bad news. But do not panic! This happens all the time and there are clear guidelines for how to replace your lost or stolen passport. Contact The Authorities Immediately First and foremost, you must contact the passport issuing authorities that issued your passport. In the United States, that is the State Department. In other countries, it will be your respective Foreign Ministry. I have thankfully never misplaced my passport, but in response to a comment left by another reader of this blog, I thought that...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lost-stolen-passport-instructions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lost-stolen-passport-instructions</guid>
        
        <category>response plan</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three ways travel changed my life when I was young</title>
        <description>I am thrilled to have my father, Bob Moore, be the first guest author on my blog. The following is an account of how travel changed his life at an early age. Maybe this is where I got it from? It’s a beautiful story, with a great lesson for each of us. I hope you enjoy it and that you will leave a comment below. You can also reach me directly at @judsonlmoore. Three ways travel changed my life  Travel changed my college major and career aspirations. Travel enabled me to overcome recalcitrant racist feelings. Travel precipitated a break-up with the girl I thought I would marry.  When I was 21 years old, I had an...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/three-ways-travel-changed-life</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/three-ways-travel-changed-life</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips For Overcoming Language Barriers</title>
        <description>There is no such thing as an “easy Language” to learn. After all, a language is an inherently huge thing. That said, there are a lot of things you can do to quickly overcome language barriers and rapidly ascend to fluency. Common Tricks for Overcoming Language Barriers    There are some simple self-study activities most people try when studying a language. Flashcards are easy to make and are a great way to study vocabulary by yourself or with a friend. I use sticky notes to label everything at home with its definition in the language I am studying. Devices like your cell phone, computer, and TV have language settings which you can configure to give you that next level...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/overcoming-language-barriers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/overcoming-language-barriers</guid>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel Advice To Rajasthan India</title>
        <description>Rajasthan India is one of the most sought after destinations in the world. This dusty desert plain is a throwback to a more magical time when sultans ruled and where the unbelievable power of mystics can still be felt today. Related Post: India Travel Advice In Under 10 Minutes I traveled to three places in Rajasthan: Jaipur, Ajmer and Pushkar. I tell my story here. If you have a story to share, please drop me a line in the comments section below. Jaipur, Rajasthan  The Pink City, as Jaipur is known, is called as such because...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/travel-advice-rajasthan-india</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/travel-advice-rajasthan-india</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>rajasthan</category>
        
        <category>jaipur</category>
        
        <category>ajmer</category>
        
        <category>pushkar</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why travel while young?</title>
        <description>The most significant advantage I have had in life is that when I was young, many adults I respected told me to “do it while you’re young.” Of course, “it” could mean anything: take a risk, start a business, save for retirement, but for me, it involved travel. After years of hearing their advice, I started listening, and I’ve been on a grand adventure ever since. This poses the question: Why travel While Young? Why Travel? This is Why. People say carpe diem like as if you don’t know what the future holds. Though you can’t know if this is your last day in good health or not, life can be somehow predictable for many people. I’ve made this infographic representing an average American’s life,...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/why-travel-while-young</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/why-travel-while-young</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ultimate list of international fellowship programs that can change your life</title>
        <description>International fellowship programs are an excellent way to see the world and learn valuable lessons while others pay for it. I once believed that all fellowships are for current degree-seeking students and researchers, therefore not something I could qualify for after graduation. You might also reasonably assume that when you read “fellowship,” you need to be in school. This is not true. There are many professional fellowships, as well as opportunities for mid-career international education and research. Here are a few programs from which I have personal experience. I’m happy to offer tips for applying to these, and I would love to expand this list if you leave a comment below with any other programs that should be on it. 1. East-West: The...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/international-fellowship-programs</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/international-fellowship-programs</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Living Without A Car in America</title>
        <description>After living abroad for a few years, I found myself coming home to America for a new job. I was headed to Texas, home of big trucks and vast expanses between places. I thought to myself that the first order of business would be to purchase a new vehicle, seeing as how I didn’t own one at the time. On arrival, the guy who hired me offered me a challenge: try living without a car for 30 days; if you hate it, buy a vehicle. I took his challenge and am happy to report that three years later, I am still blissfully living without a car! Living Without A Car: The Setup I am not one to back down from...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/living-without-a-car-in-america</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/living-without-a-car-in-america</guid>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>20 Essential Travel Apps from My Life on the Road</title>
        <description>With tens of millions of apps out there in the world, it is hard to see the forest through the trees. Travels Apps are only a fraction of all apps, but still one of the largest categories of apps which you will find. I am either currently traveling, or thinking about traveling, literally all the time. Whether sitting on a plane, trying to cross a city or laying in bed at night dreaming of my next trip, these are the travel apps that I rely on the most.  Please also share your favorite travel apps in the comments below, or let me know what they are directly at @judsonlmoore! My Top Travel Apps Google Maps There are many maps apps...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/essential-travel-apps</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/essential-travel-apps</guid>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The secret to my success</title>
        <description>Throughout my life, I’ve been asked many times about my success. “How do you get to travel so much?” “How are you able to convince others to pay for your travel?” “How are you so lucky?” How. How. How. The answer to all of this is exceedingly simple. I did not grow up in a wealthy family, and I did not have very extraordinary circumstances. But it was also most certainly not just luck. The secret to my success is that I showed up. But showing up can be trickier than it sounds. Let me tell you the story of when I first started showing up. Showing up: my first time So what is the big deal about showing...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/showing-up-secret-to-success</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/showing-up-secret-to-success</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A nomad's philosophy to relationships</title>
        <description>For many years, I have had a philosophy regarding the quality of relationships. I have shared it with many people along my journey, but I have never written about it. Recent events in my life make this philosophy seem increasingly relevant, so I would like to share this with the world. First, I will note that when I use the term “relationship,” I am not narrowing the focus to romantic relationships. You can apply this philosophy to friendships, business partnerships, and romantic relationships. A creative mind can also see that this applies in its extreme form of the relationship between you and someone you have never even had contact with (like a celebrity or politician). The philosophy is straightforward. It states that all relationships’ quality,...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/relationships-a-nomads-philosophy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/relationships-a-nomads-philosophy</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips for negotiating travel at your job</title>
        <description>For many, the dream job often comes with at least a little bit of travel. The truth is, traveling for work is not a vacation. When someone else is floating the bill and watching the bottom line, they tend to care for the ROI more than they do for your experience. That said, many companies are glad to make you a happy employee if you take the initiative of negotiating travel by putting together a plan that demonstrates the benefits to all concerned. Top tips for negotiating travel I can tell a lot of stories on this topic, but here are the two most relevant points to negotiating an excellent travel policy with your employer:  Ask Early - If you don’t ask,...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/negotiating-travel-at-your-job</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/negotiating-travel-at-your-job</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>8 Things to Tell Your Family Before You Travel</title>
        <description>All travel has a lot of moving parts (pun intended). For you, the traveler, you have thought a lot about where you are going, what you will be doing and when you will be doing it. You’ve no doubt committed a lot of time and thought into the decisions around your travel and you understand the rationale which informed these decisions. However, for every detail you’ve decided, there are likely to be a number of questions which others might ask. This begs the question, “what should you tell others before you travel?”  The most inquisitive and interested folks in all things regarding your whereabouts is likely to be your family.  So, how do you keep your family informed...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/things-to-tell-family-before-you-travel</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/things-to-tell-family-before-you-travel</guid>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>travel tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>High tech tips for any resume</title>
        <description>The purpose of a resume is to get you an interview. It needs to be catchy (but not tacky), impressive (but not long), and most importantly: well-organized (yet still creative). Everyone has a style preference in writing a resume, so I will not get into that here. The purpose of this article is to provide some high-tech resume tips you can apply to any resume. However, you can access my awesome high-tech resume template along with lots of useful notes when you subscribe to my e-mail list. So do that now. It’s ok. I will stay here and wait for you to come back. Use Google Docs If you are not already a user of Google Docs, you should...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/high-tech-resume-tips</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/high-tech-resume-tips</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kyrgyzstan Travel Guide and 2-Week Itinerary Recommendation</title>
        <description>I’ve done a lot of sharing my experience in Kyrgyzstan and I often find myself repeating my travel advice for the country. Where to go? What to see? Who to meet? So I have decided to put together a sample itinerary. This is designed for someone who has limited time in the country, just 1-2 weeks. Of course, I was here for two years and I think there is no such thing as a “maximum” amount of time you should spend in one location, but the reality is that most of you will have to budget your time. Getting Around Kyrgyzstan Firstly, how do you get around this beautiful country? Artiom, is how! Artiom - Is a Bishkek-based guide and has...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/travel-advice-kyrgyzstan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/travel-advice-kyrgyzstan</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Shafik Gabr's East-West - The Art of Dialogue Fellowship Notes</title>
        <description>M. Shafik Gabr is a prominent Egyptian businessman and philanthropist. He has established charitable foundations in Egypt and the United States to perform good humanitarian works of various sorts. In 2013, he began a fellowship program that encourages East-West dialogue. Each year, the fellowship brings 20 young professionals together for a month of travel, dialogue, and stimulating meetings with top leaders in Egypt and the United States. I am a 2015 fellow. In this article, I share my notes from the fellowship to record my learnings from my participation and hope that these notes might help future fellowship applicants understand what they are signing up for. My notes are as comprehensive as I could get them, but the most meaningful...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/shafik-gabr-2015-fellowship-notes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/shafik-gabr-2015-fellowship-notes</guid>
        
        <category>fellowship</category>
        
        <category>egypt</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to visit the Suez Canal in a presidential yacht</title>
        <description>The Suez Canal isn’t exactly a tourist destination, but that can’t keep me from taking a leisure cruise on a presidential yacht on a beautiful day! The Suez Canal, a modern engineering marvel of staggering proportions, is a highly militarized zone in eastern Egypt, connecting the Mediterranean Sea and the Red Sea. Originally opened in 1869, the canal became the primary artery for goods to flow between east and west for over a hundred years. With so much trade traversing the canal, the capacity was deemed in need of a boost and so in 2014 work commenced which would increase the canal’s capacity from 50 transits a day to 97, and cut waiting times from 18 to 11 hours. If...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/suez-canal-egypt-cruise/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/suez-canal-egypt-cruise/</guid>
        
        <category>mena</category>
        
        <category>egypt</category>
        
        <category>suez canal</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gabr Fellowship Has Selected Me As A 2015 Fellow</title>
        <description>The 2015 Gabr Fellowship I am thrilled to announce that I have been awarded the 2015 Gabr Fellowship! The program is broken down into two parts: the first part will be six weeks of travel throughout Egypt and the United States with a group of twenty young professionals; the second part is a six-month window in which to complete a development project in Egypt. The participants come from a wide variety of professional sectors and are all emerging leaders in their field. There are ten fellows from Egypt, nine from America, and one from England. While traveling, we will meet daily with economic, political, civic, and arts leaders to better understand Egyptian and American cultures. In Egypt, we will visit...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/gabr-fellowship</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/gabr-fellowship</guid>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>art</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        <category>exchange</category>
        
        <category>fellowship</category>
        
        <category>gabr</category>
        
        <category>orientalist</category>
        
        <category>service</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Hurricane Katrina Changed My Life 10 Years Later</title>
        <description>I often reflect on events in my life for being the pivotal moments when the trajectory of my life changed. Incredible moments like my Rotary Youth Exchange year and not so great moments like appendicitis in Kyrgyzstan have led me to who I am today. I am glad for all of these things because my life is truly a fortunate one, and I wouldn’t change how I got here. Hurricane Katrina is one of those events, and now after a decade has passed since that fateful day, I reflect on the impact it had on my life. Hurricane Katrina: A Decade Later On this 10th anniversary of Hurricane Katrina, I take note that I rarely consider this event to...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/10-years-after-hurricane-katrina</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/10-years-after-hurricane-katrina</guid>
        
        <category>american red cross</category>
        
        <category>anniversary</category>
        
        <category>disaster</category>
        
        <category>hurricane katrina</category>
        
        <category>memories</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Open Letter To The Rotary Club of Alexandria</title>
        <description>Dear Rotary Club of Alexandria As read by Ed Caplan to the Rotary Club of Alexandria members at their regular Tuesday lunch meeting. Tuesday August 18, 2015 16 years ago, the Rotary Club of Alexandria sponsored Judson Moore to participate in Camp RYLA. Literally half a lifetime later, he is at this moment being introduced to the Rotary Club of Austin Texas as their newest member. Judson asked that I take a moment to recount his journey over these last 16 years as a testament to that investment we made in him, and to encourage us to continue making similar investments in CENLA youth. Here is what Judson writes to our club today: Dear Rotary Club of Alexandria, Today is a...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/open-letter-rotary-club-alexandria</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/open-letter-rotary-club-alexandria</guid>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Have Joined The Rotary Club of Austin</title>
        <description>I’ve hit a significant milestone in my life today: I am a Rotarian! I’ve been part of the Rotary Family since I was in high school, and anyone who knows me knows that this is a very significant moment for me. The club I joined is the Rotary Club of Austin in District 5870. We meet Tuesdays for lunch at St. David’s Episcopal Church in downtown Austin. If you are ever in the area, join us! Here are some photos of the pinning ceremony, followed by a letter I wrote to the folks that got me started down this path 16 years ago.     &lt;a class=&quot;example-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/2015/08/Judson-Joining-Rotary-of-Austin-001.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;example-set&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/im-a-rotarian</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/im-a-rotarian</guid>
        
        <category>membership</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>rotary international</category>
        
        <category>service above self</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DragonForce Performs live at the Mohawk in Austin Texas</title>
        <description>I’ve waited to see the English power metal band DragonForce for more than ten years! These guys came on to the pop culture radar by having the featured and impossible to play bonus song at the end of the Guitar Hero video game. They performed in Austin, Texas, at the outdoor stage of The Mohawk, one of my favorite venues and conveniently located just a few blocks away from my office. After work, some colleges and I walked down the hill to catch the show in the rain. It was an epic evening! DragonForce Performs Through The Fire and Flames! This is THE song! Best known for being the closing credits song at the end of the original Guitar...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dragonforce</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dragonforce</guid>
        
        <category>concert</category>
        
        <category>live</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My New 2015 Kona Jake The Snake Cyclocross Bicycle</title>
        <description>I’ve had road bikes and mountain bikes, now I am settling into something right in the middle: a cyclocross bike. There is a vibrant cyclocross race culture here in Austin, and it’s a whole other world of biking, which I think I will love. This bike is my first cyclocross bike, and so far, I love it. Kona’s 2015 Jake The Snake cyclocross bike offers lots of higher-end amenities at a very reasonable price point. Here are the specs on the bike. 2015 Kona Jake The Snake Specs            FRAME MATERIAL Kona Race Light 7005 Aluminum Butted   SIZES 47, 49, 53, 56, 59, 61, 63cm   REAR...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jake-the-snake</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jake-the-snake</guid>
        
        <category>biking</category>
        
        <category>cx</category>
        
        <category>cyclocross</category>
        
        <category>phenom</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Photo Tour of the Niederaltaich Abbey</title>
        <description>First Impressions of the Niederaltaich Abbey Church Niederalteich is a tiny town of fewer than 2000 people on the Danube River in Bavaria, Germany. It is best known for its main church, the Niederaltaich Abbey Church. The abbey is part of the Benedictine Order and was founded in the 8th century. I stopped by the abbey to see if I could get a tour and what came next exceeded any dreams. I met Father Stephan, one of the deacons of the brotherhood and he took me around parts of the Abbey that are rarely seen by anyone. &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2015/10/IMG_5374.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_290/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2015/10/IMG_5374.jpg 290w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_610/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2015/10/IMG_5374.jpg 610w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_930/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2015/10/IMG_5374.jpg 930w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded mb-2 mt-3 w-100&quot; alt=&quot;My friend Martin and I with Father Stephan...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/niederaltaich-abbey</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/niederaltaich-abbey</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>bavaria</category>
        
        <category>niederalteich</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Walk Through Brühl's Countryside and Palaces</title>
        <description>I recently had the chance to reunite with a dear friend in his hometown of Brühl Germany. Mark and I worked together in Kyrgyzstan to develop skills of journalists and media professionals. His trainings are one of the reasons why kyrgyzmedia.kg has become so sustainable over the years, so clearly I am very grateful for his skill and friendship! First Impressions of Brühl Brühl is a small town in west Germany between Cologne and Bonn. The well-manicured paths through surrounding fields and nature make exploring the countryside estates and palaces a breeze. Germany is well known for ease of access and walkability, but Brühl stood out from the crowd in this regard. Though I was visiting in the dead of...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bruhl-walking-tour</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bruhl-walking-tour</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>bruehl</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reunion, Kölsch and Architecture of Köln (Cologne)</title>
        <description>After spending 5-months in India building out a new facility for Mutual Mobile, I get to take a few weeks of vacation! I am returning to Germany for the first time since my high school Rotary Youth Exchange year in Oldenburg and am very excited to reconnect with old friends. My first stop on this journey is Köln, known in English-speaking circles as Cologne. After flying Hyderabad &amp;gt; Abu Dhabi &amp;gt; Frankfurt, I got a first-class ticket on the ICE 102 to Köln and began my relaxing 3-week tour of central Europe. Here is a preview of the beauty to come.  &amp;lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ha9seYZ6DPE&quot; %} ## First Impressions of Köln (and beer!) Upon arriving in Köln...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/reunion-koln</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/reunion-koln</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>reunion</category>
        
        <category>train</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>India Travel Guide - What I Learned After 6 Months On The Road</title>
        <description>I have seen so much of India at this point that I feel like I can give you some good advice and connect you with folks in each area of the country. In the event that you visit India, I think the below India travel guide will be very helpful. Please, add your comments below! How to get around India    For regional travel, trains are a great way to get around. The official online train ticket portal is here, but that site is difficult to work with, and you have to create an account before you can even see what the schedules are. The better way to book train tickets is with Cleartrip (iOS  Android) or with &lt;a...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/travel-advice-india</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/travel-advice-india</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>agra</category>
        
        <category>dehli</category>
        
        <category>jaipur</category>
        
        <category>rajasthan</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Its Made - The Mutual Mobile Office in Hyderabad India</title>
        <description>It’s no secret that I’ve spent some time in India, but I am frequently asked, “why were you there?” I know that I am better at documenting my weekends and time off, but I don’t just travel the world for fun. I do have a job to get done! It is now my great pleasure to unveil to you the new office of Mutual Mobile in Hyderabad, India! If you have ever built a space in another country or were part of creating this space, please tell me about it in the comments below, or message me directly at @judsonlmoore! Mutual Mobile sends me to India In India, my job was to launch a new facility for Mutual...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/mutual-mobile-hyderabad</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/mutual-mobile-hyderabad</guid>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
        <category>challenge</category>
        
        <category>construction</category>
        
        <category>facility</category>
        
        <category>hyderabad</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>mutual mobile</category>
        
        <category>success</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Satsang Vihar - The Religious Center of Hyderabad India</title>
        <description>The Satsang Temple This weekend I accompanied my colleague and dear friend, Abin, with his family, to the Satsang Vihar - Hyderabad. This ashram is home to a large Satsang temple. Satsang is an Indian philosophy, which teaches a process of spiritual meditation, which encourages people to listen to, talk about, and assimilate the truth. This typically involves listening to or reading scriptures, reflecting on, discussing and assimilating their meaning, meditating on the source of these words, and bringing their meaning into one’s daily life. The ashram is a beautiful building of white marble surrounded by massive boulders, forest, and a compound of living quarters and facilities that accommodate Satsang pilgrims who travel here for periods of spiritual reflection. The Satsang Festival...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/satsang</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/satsang</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>telangana</category>
        
        <category>hyderabad</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pushkar - A Camel Safari In The Heart of Rajasthan India</title>
        <description>The Town of Pushkar In the heart of Rajasthan is a small town called Pushkar. To get to Pushkar, we took a train from Jaipur to Ajmer, then walked two miles to a taxi stand where we hired a car to take us the rest of the way, about a 30 minute drive. Pushkar is one of the most significant pilgrimage sites for Hindus. Hindus believe that Lord Brahma, the Hindu god of creation, created Pushkar. Despite the significance of Lord Brahma, there are very few temples in the world are dedicated to him, thanks to the Curse of Savitri. The Pushkar temple is, however, the most significant of the Brahma temples and viewed by many as...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/pushkar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/pushkar</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>rajasthan</category>
        
        <category>pushkar</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jaipur - Home of Royalty, Castles and the Kama Sutra</title>
        <description>The Pink City The Pink City is called as such because all the buildings here are painted a reddish pinkish color to imitate the red sandstone architecture of Mughal cities, from which Jaipur is fashioned. Jaipur is the largest city in Rajasthan, and it is the place that I had intended to be my first destination to travel to in India. Because of the abundance of amazing invitations I received from friends and colleagues to tour other destinations, it’s taken me three months to actually get here. The famous Golden Triangle of India is the route that connects Delhi, Agra and Jaipur, so that should tell you something about how important of a place this is. The Amber Fort...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jaipur</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jaipur</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>rajasthan</category>
        
        <category>jaipur</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ajmer and a 1000 Year Old Manmade Lake in Rajasthan</title>
        <description>Arriving to Ajmer My first train ride in India led me to Ajmer, a small town in the heart of Rajasthan. A German friend of mine, Tobi, who is also staying at my hotel in Hyderabad, joined on this weekend adventure which also covered Jaipur and Pushkar. Ajmer is a small town of only 500,000 people (which is a small town in these parts). The town was easily walkable, which is what we opted to do for the mile journey to Daulat Bagh, a park on Ana Sagar Lake. In the park, we came across an interesting temple to Lord Shiva. I would later learn that king cobra snakes are present in all of Lord Shiva’s temples, but...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ajmer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ajmer</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>rajasthan</category>
        
        <category>ajmer</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Annual Hyderabad 10k Around The Hussain Sagar Lake</title>
        <description>Mutual Mobile participates every year in the Hyderabad 10k. I happened to be in town for this event, so naturally, I ran with the team! The running path is along the Necklace Road, which surrounds the Hussain Sagar Lake in the city center. The event was reminiscent of the Mardi Gras Marathon in New Orleans because they had a stage with live music at every kilometer marker. The music ranged from traditional to rock to school choirs. I ran the whole 10k, but only 1km at a time, then I would listen to the music for a while and run to the next stage. I couldn’t help myself! The VIP at the starting line was renowned Indian track Olympian, &lt;a...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/hyderabad-10k</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/hyderabad-10k</guid>
        
        <category>fitness</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>hyderabad</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>running</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dubai Is The Billionaire's Oasis In the Middle East</title>
        <description>Dubai - The Grandest Oasis Dubai: the playground of billionaires, royalty and me (for a day)! Thank you to my dear friend Laura and her family for hosting me while I was in Dubai. Laura and I worked together on my cornerstone project while in the Peace Corps. She was a key player at UNESCO, who funded the project, so, she is one of my favorite people on Earth. Laura drove all the way out to Abu Dhabi to pick me up after I did my sightseeing there. In Dubai, she spent a whole day making sure I got to make the best of my few hours. We went to the Burj Khalifa, the tallest man-made structure...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dubai</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dubai</guid>
        
        <category>mena</category>
        
        <category>united arab emirates</category>
        
        <category>dubai</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Abu Dhabi - Making the Best of a 36-Hour Layover in the UAE</title>
        <description>A 36-Hour Layover in Abu Dhabi What an unexpected treat! I’ve dreamed of visiting the United Arab Emirates for such a long time but even with all of my travel experience, this has always felt like a place too distant, too exotic and so far out of reach that I might not ever get here. However, thanks to a 36-hour layover in Abu Dhabi on my way back to India from Colombia, I got to experience a few of the key landmarks which I’ve always hoped to see. Uber is truly my favorite service in the world. I landed in Abu Dhabi, connected to free wifi while waiting in the customs line, requested an Uber, and when I walked out...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/abu-dhabi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/abu-dhabi</guid>
        
        <category>mena</category>
        
        <category>united arab emirates</category>
        
        <category>abu dhabi</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Colombia Is The New Germany - A Rotary Youth Exchange Reunion</title>
        <description>A Reunion In Colombia I recently made a 12-day trip to Colombia to reunite with a few friends from my year as a Rotary Youth Exchange Student in Germany. We visited several fantastic places around the country and had the best local insight available thanks to Alejandro Borda who organized our time in his country and made sure we were well-entertained. Bogotá: The Capital of Colombia Our first days were spent in the capital city, Bogotá. On the first day we explored the Monastery, Cerro de Monserrate, which has breathtaking panoramic views of Bogotá. After some photo ops with local school children, we went down into the city center and spent several hours at The Gold Museum. This museum is the...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/colombia-new-germany</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/colombia-new-germany</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>colombia</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>rye</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Andrés Carne de Res - The Tackiest Steakhouse In The World</title>
        <description>Andrés Carne de Res We celebrated our final evening in Colombia in grand fashion with incredible food, drinks and dancing. The most famous place to eat in all of Colombia is Andrés Carne de Res. There are 2 locations in Bogotá. One is in the city center (fashion district) and is new and corporate feeling. The original location is just outside of town. If you get a chance, go to the out-of-town location. It’s like Hard Rock Cafe, Cracker Barrel, Tex Mex, BBQ and a hoarder-artist estate sale had a freak baby who turned out to be a culinary prodigy. Andrés Carne de Res is the best place to eat, drink, and party on the weekends. Closes at 3am. Prepare for...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/andres-carne-de-res</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/andres-carne-de-res</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>colombia</category>
        
        <category>bogota</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>rye</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Salt Cathedral of Zipaquirá - A Subterranean Monument of Faith</title>
        <description>The Salt Cathedral of Zipaquirá Near Bogotá is the Salt Cathedral of Zipaquirá. If you go to Colombia and don’t go here, you should truly feel like you’ve missed out on something grand. Dubbed, “a wonder of the world, the first wonder of Colombia,” photos can’t do this place justice. Just get there.      &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_3607.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_3607.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_3607.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_3607.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_3607.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_3607.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;figure-img rounded img-fluid mb-2 mt-3 w-100&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;Rotary public art on the plaza of the Salt Cathedral of Zipaquirá. Very suitable!&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;853&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/salt-cathedral-zipaquira</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/salt-cathedral-zipaquira</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>colombia</category>
        
        <category>zipaquira</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>rye</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Villa de Leyva - A Historical Mountain Retreat In Colombia</title>
        <description>Villa de Leyva - A Historical Mountain Retreat Our next destination is the preserved town of Villa de Leyva. Located a 4-hour drive north from Bogotá nestled in rolling hills and a landscape that was, to me, what I expected Colombia to look and feel like. The architecture is uniform: white stucco with red tile roofs. The streets are paved in stones, and I must admit, the ladies here wearing high heels are even braver and graceful than the Kyrgyz women who wear heels in winter. The first day was spent wandering the town’s historic streets and enjoying a sunset behind the mountains and dark rainclouds which only impacted us long enough to make us seek refuge in a Brazilian cafe;...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/villa-de-leyva</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/villa-de-leyva</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>colombia</category>
        
        <category>villa de leyva</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>rye</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Isla Palma - Private Island Paradise of Pablo Escobar</title>
        <description>Getting To Isla Palma The destination that we considered to be, at lest during the planning phase, the main event, was the 3-day all-inclusive visit to Isla Palma, an island resort which used to be the summer home of famed drug cartel boss, Pablo Escobar. The island is located a 3-hour bus ride south of Cartagena, followed by a 30-minute boat ride out into the Caribbean. The island is beautiful and has a great mixture of refined resort, island charm and overgrown development which makes for some great exploration. Though most people would go gaga over the beaches and crystal clear water, I care little for the white sands of the beach and am much more thrilled by the...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/isla-palma</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/isla-palma</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>colombia</category>
        
        <category>isla palma</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>rye</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cartagena - A Historical Tour Through Colombia's Magnificent Port</title>
        <description>I am so excited to tell you about the stunning and fun city of Cartagena! If you have some tips to add, please do so in the comments below or by messaging me directly at @judsonlmoore. Arriving to Cartagena After having a chance to recover from jet lag, we headed to the coastal city of Cartagena. This is one of the most visited destinations in Colombia for the rich and the famous; we had just missed Prince Charles by a few days.  The Old City is where you want to spend all of your time in Cartagena. The beaches there are dirty so you will need to leave the city or go out to the islands to find the clear water...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/cartagena</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/cartagena</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>colombia</category>
        
        <category>cartagena</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>rye</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bogotá - A Capital of More Romantic Times and a Beautiful Nation</title>
        <description>Our first days were spent in the capital city, Bogotá. On the first day we explored the Monastery, Cerro de Monserrate, which has breathtaking panoramic views of Bogotá. After some photo ops with local school children, we went down into the city center and spent several hours at The Gold Museum. This museum is the most extensive collection of gold artifacts in the world. Located in a region of town called La Candelaria (the old town), the museum is next to the national capital and some very interesting architecture.      &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_2109.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_2109.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_2109.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_2109.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/11/IMG_2109.jpg...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bogota</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bogota</guid>
        
        <category>south america</category>
        
        <category>colombia</category>
        
        <category>bogota</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        <category>rye</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Agra Is Home of The World's Oldest Fairy Tail Tragedy</title>
        <description>An Epic Journey to Agra Bucket list: check! After an 18-hour drive direct from visiting the Dalai Lama in Dharamshala, I’ve made it to Agra to see the Taj Mahal! There is a Trident Hotel here in Agra, and I was able to arrange a room so that I could freshen up. It was an awesome perk they offered me, and I very much appreciated the opportunity to shower, change and have some breakfast before heading over to the Taj Mahal. The hotel also arranged a guide for me today. Sarfaraz is a university professor with a Ph.D. in Indian History. He is the perfect guide for a day in Agra. We set out to the Taj Mahal and...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/agra</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/agra</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>uttar pradesh</category>
        
        <category>agra</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dharamshala is Home To The Dalai Lama and This Wonderful Shopkeeper</title>
        <description>Dharamshala The Dalai Lama represents peace and tranquility to millions throughout the world, and Dharamshala is his home in exile from Tibet. Tibetan buddhists believe he is the incarnation of the Buddha of compassion, who has long been considered to be the patron deity of Tibet. Dharamshala sits within view of the Himalayan mountains and covers the side of a very large foothill. The upper area of the town is called McLeod Ganj and is where the Dalai lama lives. Our hotel was in the town proper at the foot of the mountain. The drive from bottom to top is about half an hour up a well-paved switchback road which, ironically, mostly weaves in and out of an active military installation. At...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dharamshala</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dharamshala</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>himachal pradesh</category>
        
        <category>dharamshala</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Manali - India's Doorway to the Himalayan Mountains</title>
        <description>On The Road To Manali Manali is 350 miles north of Delhi and sits right on the edge of the Himalayan Mountains. The temperate summer climate and the snowy winters make this a very popular destination for seasonal tourism. We visited Manali in the off-season between summer and winter, so we had the place relatively to ourselves. The greatest attraction near Manali is Rohtang Pass, with an altitude of 3979m (13,050 ft). We drove up a fairly treacherous road to the pass. Once there, we rode horseback to get closer to the peak. This route is easily one of the more scenic places I have been in all of India, and it was a bucket-list check to see the...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/manali</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/manali</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>himachal pradesh</category>
        
        <category>manali</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bangalore Is Known For More Than Being India's Silicon Valley</title>
        <description>Spontaneously Bangalore My trip to Bangalore was rather spontaneous. I’ve made some expat friends in Hyderabad who work with Deloitte, and they travel a lot as a group. Since I am traveling solo in India, they are kind enough to invite me on a few of their weekend excursions. But due to some last minute changes in their ability to come to Bangalore, I spent most of the time touring the city on my own. As it turned out, Mutual Mobile had representatives here conducting some recruitment efforts, so I spent my first day with them interviewing candidates. After the interviews, I met up with the Deloitte crew for dinner at the City Center, followed by dancing on the City...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bangalore</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bangalore</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>karnataka</category>
        
        <category>bangalore</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dandiya Is The Festival Drummers and Dancers Were Born For</title>
        <description>Dandiya: Festival of Sounds As it so happened, the months I spent in India spanned the peak festival season. I love festivals, so this was very convenient. Of all the cultural events I attended, Dandiya was my favorite. The music seemed to be unique to this festival. I never heard music elsewhere in India with so much percussion, and, to be honest, I rarely ever heard live music of any nature, but this night made up for that. I like to describe the band as having the “correct number of drummers,” because everyone on stage was a percussionist! (keep in mind that piano is a percussion instrument; therefore a synthesizer is too!) Dandiya has a fascinating history (Wikipedia) and the...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dandiya-festival-2014</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/dandiya-festival-2014</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>telangana</category>
        
        <category>hyderabad</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mutual Mobile Receives High Blessings In Hyderabad</title>
        <description>Blessings for Mutual Mobile Hyderabad In celebration of construction beginning at the new Mutual Mobile office in Hyderabad, the builders organized a puja to be performed. A puja is a widely-used term for a Hindu prayer ritual to honor and worship one of the deities. In this case, the puja is seeking the blessings for successful construction and profitable business to always come to Mutual Mobile in this space. Our CEO’s parents live in Hyderabad, so they attended the event as honor guests. PhotosfFrom the puja      &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/10/IMG_1311.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/10/IMG_1311.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/10/IMG_1311.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/10/IMG_1311.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/10/IMG_1311.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/10/IMG_1311.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;figure-img...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/mutual-mobile-puja</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/mutual-mobile-puja</guid>
        
        <category>hinduism</category>
        
        <category>hyderabad</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>mutual mobile</category>
        
        <category>puja</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Three reasons Tranquebar is worth the long drive to get to</title>
        <description>Resting In Tranquebar Anyone who has ‘vacationed’ with me knows that I’m not very good at the whole rest and relaxation thing, but in Tranquebar on a holiday weekend, that was all we could do.. and it was awesome! I’ve never enjoyed doing nothing so much in my life. Stacey and I stayed in an amazing oceanside plantation-era house converted into a “non-hotel-hotel” called The Bungalow on the Beach.  The space kept true with the colonial furnishings and decor. This house was the only place to eat in this tiny seaside town and the menu changed with the day’s catch. The local economy seems to be mostly from fishing and tourism. Everyday we sat on the porch of the hotel and...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/tranquebar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/tranquebar</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>tamil nadu</category>
        
        <category>tranquebar</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Pondicherry Sunrise Is Better Than A Tequila Sunrise</title>
        <description>A Sunrise In Pondicherry I had originally planned for my first trip in India to be to the northwest region of Rajasthan, but I made a last-minute change in schedule because I found an awesome travel partner: Stacey. She suggested that we go south instead to discover the southeastern coast of India. We start in Pondicherry. We arrived in Pondicherry on the southeast coast of India after flying to Chennai and then taking a taxi several hours through the night, weaving between commercial trucks. It was a long and horn-honking experience. We arrived just in time to watch the sun rise over the Bay of Bengal, which made the tiresome journey very much worthwhile. National Holiday For Gandhi...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/pondicherry</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/pondicherry</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>tamil nadu</category>
        
        <category>pondicherry</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hampi the Fallen Capital of the Vijayanagara Empire in India</title>
        <description>Hampi: Fallen Seat of an Empire In south central India, in the heart of a jungle less-traveled, lies the now sleepy town of Hampi. This village was once home to over 500,000 people and in it’s time it was one of the largest cities in the world. Now recognized as a UNESCO World Heritage Site, this former capital of the Vijayanagara Empire is a mere shadow of it’s former glory, but what remains is truly breathtaking. In A Nutshell Highlights - Hampi boasts some of the oldest, most beautiful, and well-preserved architecture in all of India. The tourism-friendly market offers a few familiar comforts to guests, without distracting from Hampi’s uniqueness.. Lowlights - The sites are too far...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/hampi</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/hampi</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>karnataka</category>
        
        <category>hampi</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Golconda Fort</title>
        <description>I was a child when I first visited the National Natural History Museum in Washington D.C. I’ve never been one for jewels, especially diamonds, but ever since my childhood, I’ve been captivated by the Hope Diamond, which is notorious for supposedly being cursed. The history and mystery of that stone is very interesting, and it’s origins are rather unknown, except that it was mined and originally housed just west of Hyderabad, India, at the once formidable Golconda Fort. The fort’s original buildings are over a thousand years old and have been extensively expanded over the centuries. The center of the fort rests atop a 100m-high granite hill, which is the source for many of the buildings’ stones. The outer wall is seven miles...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/golconda-fort</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/golconda-fort</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>telangana</category>
        
        <category>hyderabad</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Charminar</title>
        <description>I had the most wonderful experience exploring Hyderabad today! I went to visit one of India’s most recognizable monuments, a mosque called Charminar. The name comes from combining the Urdu words Chār and Minar’, which translates to “Four Towers,” referencing the monument’s four ornate minarets. This structure is the icon of Hyderabad and is visited by thousands of people every day. Charminar is the first tourist destination I’ve visited in India and I’ve learned something: tourists and locals do not pay the same rate, not by a long shot. The local rate is 25INR, while I paid 500INR! This is less than $8USD, which is a fine amount of money to pay, but wow, what a surcharge! The one benefit to paying...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/charminar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/charminar</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>telangana</category>
        
        <category>hyderabad</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Trident Hotel and Poverty</title>
        <description>Living high above the poverty line I’ve now been living in Hyderabad, India, for about 3 weeks and am starting to get accustomed to my daily schedule and the opportunities presented to me here. The main purpose of my being here is for an extended stay business trip with Mutual Mobile as the project manager for developing a new office in the city for around 100 team members. More on that in a separate post as things develop. Generally speaking, I have seen three things in this city: The Trident Hotel, Charminar, and the Golkonda Fort. For the sake of brevity, I will just write about the hotel in this post. You can find my...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-trident-hotel-and-poverty</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-trident-hotel-and-poverty</guid>
        
        <category>asia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>telangana</category>
        
        <category>hyderabad</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Global Travel Announcement</title>
        <description>One year, three months, and seven days ago, I moved to Austin, Texas. Since that time, I have only spent ten days traveling. It’s time to get a move on! I write to you today to announce some exciting travel plans I have for the remainder of 2014. If you will be in my vicinity, let me know, and let me try to meet up!  September 8 - October 29: Hyderabad, India October 30 - November 10: Bogotá, Colombia November 12 - November 13: Abu Dhabi, UAE November 14 - December 15: Hyderabad, India December 15 - January 4: South Germany / Central Europe January 5 - ???: Austin, Texas, USA  Well, there you have it. My adventure...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/global-travel-announcement</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/global-travel-announcement</guid>
        
        <category>abu dhabi</category>
        
        <category>colombia</category>
        
        <category>india</category>
        
        <category>interests</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel announcement</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Achieve Silicon Valley Anywhere</title>
        <description>If you are in the tech world, Silicon Valley is your mecca. Or at least that’s what we’re led to believe, thanks to its high concentration of technophiles and constant attention as “America’s technology capital.” But why? Flourishing tech hubs like New York’s Silicon Alley, Austin’s Silicon Hills, and other emerging hotspots prove that Silicon Valley isn’t the only tech-friendly area. What truly makes Silicon Valley unique among its like-minded city counterparts is the close-knit community of entrepreneurs, investors, and tech up-and-comers. Nothing is stopping other cities from cultivating that Silicon Valley community feel. Places like Austin are ripe with potential — we have a high concentration of technology companies, emerging and established technophiles, and entrepreneurs in our downtown corridor,...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/how-to-achieve-silicon-valley-anywhere</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/how-to-achieve-silicon-valley-anywhere</guid>
        
        <category>austin</category>
        
        <category>brazos tech district</category>
        
        <category>community</category>
        
        <category>mutual mobile</category>
        
        <category>publications</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UT Peace and Conflict Resolution Symposium</title>
        <description>Today I gave an hour-long presentation at the University of Texas to a Peace, Conflict Resolution and Global Ethics Symposium where I spoke in large part about my Peace Corps projects and how I continue to serve the Central Asian journalism community from Austin. The students were very engaged, asked great questions, and flooded me with excellent feedback and discussion after the talk concluded. Here is the presentation I shared with them.          &lt;a class=&quot;example-image-link&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ut-peace-conflict-resolution-symposium</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ut-peace-conflict-resolution-symposium</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LSU Alumni Association Magazine Article – Fall 2013</title>
        <description>Well, this chapter of my life has now officially concluded. With my final article in the LSU Alumni Magazine, Peace Corps is officially in my past. Enjoy the read and thank you all for the support. On to the next adventure! View original source here: https://issuu.com/lsualumni/docs/lsuaa_fall2013 LSU Alumni Magazine, Fall 2013, Volume 89, Number 3, P. 68-69 ### Greetings Tiger Nation, Serving in the United States Peace Corps these last two years has been a tremendous experience. During my two years in Kyrgyzstan I accomplished many things; too many to attempt listing here. So let me just describe the cornerstone achievement: Mobile Community Media Centers. Rural and underserved populations of Kyrgyzstan, especially women and children, have a very weak voice...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-association-magazine-article-fall-2013</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-association-magazine-article-fall-2013</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>lsu</category>
        
        <category>lsu alumni</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>published</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Custom Carbon Road Bike 56CM SRAM Red</title>
        <description>This beautiful custom road bike was handcrafted, painted, and assembled in Austin, TX, by Giano Fabricata. I bought it in June 2013 as my first road bike, and it has defied (my understanding of) the laws of bike-physics ever since. This machine is inspirational on the road. Since every part was hand-selected and assembled, I can’t simply say what the bike is. Therefor, I have put a list of parts here. The value of just the parts is over $6500. That doesn’t even include the cost of paint, labor, and tuning.  Carbon Frame 56CM Carbon fork SRAM RED GROUP SRAM RED 22 DoubleTap Shifters SRAM RED Rear Derailleur - SRAM RED Front Derailleur - SRAM RED Crankset - SRAM RED BB - SRAM RED...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/custom-carbon-road-bike-56cm-sram-red</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/custom-carbon-road-bike-56cm-sram-red</guid>
        
        <category>austin</category>
        
        <category>bikes</category>
        
        <category>biking</category>
        
        <category>carbon fiber</category>
        
        <category>custom</category>
        
        <category>sram</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>National Corvette Museum Hosts the C4 Gathering</title>
        <description>The C4 Gathering: An American Tradition After spending over two years outside of the United States, what’s the most American thing I can do to kickstart my reintegration? How about a week long road trip where we just eat fast food and stay at cheap motels, all while looking at driving fast cars? How about if every single one of those fast cars was a Corvette? Yes, this would be pretty American, indeed! So that is what my friend Daniel and I set out todo! The National Corvette Museum and Manufacturing plant in Bowling Green, Kentucky, has an annual event called The C4 Gathering, which is an opportunity for 4th Generation Corvette owners, enthusiasts and other gear-heads to get together and geek out about...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/corvette-c4-gathering</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/corvette-c4-gathering</guid>
        
        <category>north america</category>
        
        <category>united states of america</category>
        
        <category>kentucky</category>
        
        <category>bowling green</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What to do for A Weekend in Istanbul</title>
        <description>Before we get too far down the Istanbul rabbit hole of awesomeness, let me remind you that I just had a major abdominal surgery a few weeks ago and am still very much in the midst of recovering. I give a lot of thumbs ups and smiles for the camera, but I had to move really carefully and slowly through all of this. That said, please forgive me if I tended to not do my hair. I would also love to hear from you about your past or future time spent in Istanbul. Please share your story in the comments below or by messaging me directly at @judsonlmoore! Naziia accompanied me on this trip and it was an amazing honeymoon of...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/weekend-in-istanbul</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/weekend-in-istanbul</guid>
        
        <category>europe</category>
        
        <category>turkey</category>
        
        <category>istanbul</category>
        
        
        <category>travel guide</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Peace Corps Mission is Accomplished</title>
        <description>Serving with the United States Peace Corps in Kyrgyzstan these last two years has been a tremendous experience. During my two years in Kyrgyzstan I accomplished many things; too many to attempt listing here. So let me just describe the cornerstone achievement: Mobile Community Media Centers. Rural and underserved populations of Kyrgyzstan, especially women and children, have a very weak voice in the country and in society. Enabling a wider voice to this population but with a lack of social mobility and weak technological resources posed a great challenge. While working with the Kloop School of Journalism I realized that harnessing mobile technology could provide a sustainable solution. The country has well-developed cellular and data networks, and smartphones are a...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/peace-corps-mission-accomplished</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/peace-corps-mission-accomplished</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>life goal</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>rpcv</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Appendectomy In Bishkek</title>
        <description>A Fair Warning The following is an account of my appendectomy which was performed in Kyrgyzstan. Due to the medical and at times gruesome nature of this story, I have chosen to omit a few details and spare the public of some photography. That said, there may still be a few details here not suitable for queazy stomachs. You’ve been warned. Read on at your own risk. Day 1 Today I woke up around 5am with some mild abdominal pain. I didn’t think too much of it but by 7am the pain was a bit more alarming. I contacted the Peace Corps Medical Officer (PCMO), who told me he would come immediately. I, like most people, enjoy hot showers. Though as...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/appendectomy-in-bishkek</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/appendectomy-in-bishkek</guid>
        
        <category>appendectomy</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>health</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>travel safety</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nooryz 2013</title>
        <description>Nooryz is the Islamic new year and is celebrated in the spring time as new life is emerging from the icy grip of winter. In Kyrgyzstan, celebrations typically include cultural performances of music and dance. This video is from the Turkish-Manas Kyrgyz University in Djal, outside of Bishkek. What is really great about this video is its showcasing of a wide variety of performances from throughout Central Asia. Though many performances here are not native to the Kyrgyz people, they are all very popular in this country and are widely practiced and performed amongst youth. Thus, in this single event, I was able to capture a wide range of performances which will demonstrates nearly all of the music and dances...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/nooryz-2013</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/nooryz-2013</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>holiday</category>
        
        <category>islam</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>new year</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>K-19 COS Conference</title>
        <description>This is it. This is the end. I made it. Yet somehow, I don’t feel any sense of accomplishment. As I participate in the commencement sessions of my Peace Corps group for three days at this resort, all I can think about is how I need to be back at my site. There is still so much work to be done and precious few hours left to accomplish it all. I still have two months until I will leave Kyrgyzstan, so this also just doesn’t feel like goodbye, even though the topic of the conference is exactly that. We share stories with each other and with staff about our experiences as Peace Corps volunteers. In particular, we provide feedback about how future...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/k-19-cos-conference</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/k-19-cos-conference</guid>
        
        <category>cos</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>rpcv</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bike Race</title>
        <description>I recently participated in my first bike race! It was a really great experience but because I entered into the “professional” category and we were the last of 3 categories to race, I lost a lot of energy just standing around and the weather turned from a beautiful sunny morning to a bitter cold and windy stand storm by the time we hit the track. Combining that the really painful blister I got on my right foot from hiking in the canyons the day before, and a wreck that occurred on the starting line slightly spraining my ankle, I wasn’t able to finish the race. That was a major bummer but the day was great just the same. Yeah Bike! &lt;!-- Gallery...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bike-race</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bike-race</guid>
        
        <category>biking</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>disaster</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>sport</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hiking Konorchek Canyon in Kyrgyzstan</title>
        <description>I joined a group from the Trekking Union of Kyrgyzstan today to explore Konorchek Canyon. The landscape in this canyon is very different from anything else I’ve seen in Kyrgyzstan. It reminds me of the canyons in New Mexico and Arizona. Much of Kyrgyzstan’s landscape is made of sharp, hard black rock, but this place is red and soft. We hiked about 12 miles today, here are the photos.         ...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/hiking-konorchek-canyon</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/hiking-konorchek-canyon</guid>
        
        <category>central asia</category>
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
        <category>nature</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LSU Alumni Association Magazine Article - Spring 2013</title>
        <description>Here is my contribution to the LSU Alumni Association Magazine for Spring 2013. View original source here: https://issuu.com/lsualumni/docs/lsuaa_spring2013 Greetings Tiger Nation, I hope the start of 2013 is fulfilling all of your hopes and dreams! The holiday season in Kyrgyzstan was, strangely, both very familiar and very new. Bringing in the new year was quite a spectacular series of events. Unlike in America, New Year’s Eve is a formal family affair. Imagine combining Thanksgiving, Christmas and New Year all together: Santa Clause (Father Frost) and his grand daughter deliver presents to children on New Years Eve, every house has a New Year’s Tree decorated almost exactly as westerners would expect to find a Christmas tree and at midnight there are...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-association-magazine-article-spring-2013</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-association-magazine-article-spring-2013</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>lsu</category>
        
        <category>lsu alumni</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>published</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I Am The Quiz Master</title>
        <description>Last night I was the quiz master at my favorite local quiz night in Bishkek. We had a great turnout of 30 people consisting of locals, foreigners and all ages and professions. This weekly quiz night is a relaxed place to have fun and learning something new. This was my first time to be the quiz master and I am pretty happy with the questions I came up with so I thought I would share them with you. Pay attention to number 11-20; those are about Kyrgyzstan. Come next time and join us. Every Wednesday evening at 8pm at The Dragon’s Den, 557 Frunze (across from the Grand Hotel, next to Beirut cafe) Current world events  In a recent...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/i-am-the-quiz-master</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/i-am-the-quiz-master</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>fun</category>
        
        <category>interests</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>trivia</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Community Media in Kyrgyzstan Key to Achieving Social Justice [cross-post]</title>
        <description>The culmination of months of work, preparation and an international team overcoming very difficult situations get’s summed up nicely in this article posted on the UNESCO-Kazakhstan website. Though I am not mentioned here, my work site, Kloop Media, and my director, Rinat Tykhvanshin, are. I will let it speak for it’s self. The text below was originally posted here: https://www.unesco.kz/new/en/unesco/news/2725/ The power of community media was clearly evident in Bishkek on 20 February, as 100 participants from throughout the country gathered to mark the International Day of Social Justice in Kyrgyzstan. The conference was organized within the EU-UN joint programme “Operationalizing Good Governance for Social Justice in Kyrgyzstan.“ The three-year, USD five million project, brings together the work of UNDP, UNICEF, UN Women and UNESCO...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/community-media-in-kyrgyzstan-key-to-achieving-social-justice</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/community-media-in-kyrgyzstan-key-to-achieving-social-justice</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>central asia</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
        <category>service</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        <category>un</category>
        
        <category>unesco</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bishkek Attack</title>
        <description>Just considering that I would begin this post with something like, “I don’t know how important it is to tell you that…” should be a pretty clear indicator, but for the sake of documentation, and most importantly, to let you all know that I am OK, let me tell you a little about my Saturday evening. Saturday was the birthday celebration of a close colleague and friend of mine from Kloop Media, Ilya. Starting with dinner and drinks at his house, we quickly moved on to a nice dance club in Bishkek called Promzona. After what seems like an unreasonably short period of time we decided to change venues to a downtown dance club where I decided not...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-attack</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-attack</guid>
        
        <category>atack</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>interests</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>travel safety</category>
        
        <category>violence</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Merry Christmas (Russian Orthodox)</title>
        <description>January 7th is the date of Orthodox Christmas. For a long and detailed explanation of why this differs from the western-celebrated December 25th Christmas you can refer to this article on Wikipedia. My friend Dimity instructed me to the time and place where the Orthodox observance of Christmas could be witnessed in Bishkek and I wrangled up about 15 other foreign friends and we went to the Bishkek Orthodox Cathedral together at 8pm to take it all in. We were instructed that the ceremony would begin when the first stars appeared in the sky. Locally that was a little before 8pm. However, the rule actually applies to when the first starts appear of Israel, not where the local church stands. So...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/merry-christmas-russian-orthodox</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/merry-christmas-russian-orthodox</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>christmas</category>
        
        <category>holiday</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>orthodox</category>
        
        <category>religion</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Happy New Year / С новым годом / Жаны жылыныздар менен</title>
        <description>                 ...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/new-years-2013</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/new-years-2013</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>holiday</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>new year</category>
        
        <category>party</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ski Trip to Zil 2</title>
        <description>I made my third trip skiing this season today and it was a real blast. The weather was the best I have had all season. It was warm and sunny for most of the day. I also got in quite a few runs, 15 or so! There is a new upper-lift on the right side of the mountain and this was really the best skiing. It is challenging and fast. But the best part is the lift has literally no wait because most people are afraid to go to this summit (my theory). We went to a resort not far from Bishkek called Зил (Zil) which is my favorite place to ski. They say the best skiing in Kyrgyzstan is...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ski-trip-to-zil-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ski-trip-to-zil-2</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>fun</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>ski kg</category>
        
        <category>skiing</category>
        
        <category>sports</category>
        
        <category>zil</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LSU Alumni Magazine Article – Winter 2012</title>
        <description> Photo Caption: Judson and his Kyrgyz friends having fun at a cross-cultural dinner party. One of many such events he hosts in his home to share American culture and Louisiana cuisine.” %}  Greetings Tiger Nation, As beautiful summer days become a distant memory from this dark and cold Kyrgyzstani winter, I wrap myself in the warm knowledge that though my time here is quickly coming to a close, I have indeed made a difference. My accomplishments here have been diverse: development of rural community radio stations throughout the country, summer camps developing students’ decision-making skills regarding healthy lifestyle choices, English clubs and now the development of the first original news internet radio broadcast from Central Asia. What else...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-winter-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-winter-2012</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>lsu</category>
        
        <category>lsu alumni</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>published</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ski Trip To Zil</title>
        <description>Ski Season is here! My desire for years has been to live within a 3-hours drive of skiing. And now I am less than an hour away from skiing. And what makes it even better is that an entire day’s cost (transport, food, ski rental and lift pass) costs less than $30.00! My friend, Artiom, has his own tourism company called Travel In KG. He works non-stop in the summer months but in winter he takes his time to relax. However, he still has his van and he is still happy to drive folks around who need to get somewhere. So Artiom gives us a great price for driving us and joins us skiing. It is a great win-win situation! Plus,...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ski-trip-to-zil-1</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ski-trip-to-zil-1</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>fun</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>ski kg</category>
        
        <category>skiing</category>
        
        <category>sports</category>
        
        <category>zil</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Biking to Panorama</title>
        <description>I bought a mountainbike so that I could go to the mountains. And so I did! My lovely new Giant ATX770 held up to the test. We road about 10 miles into the low-lying hills on the south-side of Bishkek to a well-known spot called “Panorama.” This is like Make Out Point for Bishkek by night, but by day it is just a windy road to the top of a pretty big hill. We took the road up but came down directly off the side of the mountain. If I don’t ride this bike another day in Kyrgyzstan, then it was worth having it just for today!    ...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/biking-to-panorama</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/biking-to-panorama</guid>
        
        <category>biking</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>fun</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>sports</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kurban Ait</title>
        <description>This morning Bishkek Muslims began the Kurban Ait celebration by gathering in the center square of the city. 70,000 people were projected to be in attendance and I made my way to observe the events. If you have ever seen Muslims pray, then there is nothing new to report here. The entire affair lasted only about half an hour and was a calming way to being this beautiful autumn day.          &lt;a class=&quot;example-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/2013/01/AitBishkek_002.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;example-set&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/kurban-ait</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/kurban-ait</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>holiday</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>FLEX Exam 2012 Bishkek</title>
        <description>I was asked to help proctor the FLEX exam this year in Bishkek. Here is a snippet about the program from the FLEX Website: The Future Leaders Exchange (FLEX) Program is a US government-sponsored program for secondary school students from the 11 republics of the former Soviet Union (Eurasia). The program provides scholarship funding for students to travel to the United States, attend a US high school for a full academic year, and live with a US host family. FLEX was established in 1992 as the centerpiece of the Eurasian Secondary School Initiative under the FREEDOM Support Act. Funding is provided by the US Department of State. The goal of the program is to provide the students with experience living in a...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/flex-exam-2012-bishkek</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/flex-exam-2012-bishkek</guid>
        
        <category>accels</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>flex</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>testing</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bishkek Photo Tour - A Morning in Kyrgyzstan's Capital City</title>
        <description>Waking up to a perfect October morning, I decided to make a Bishkek photo tour before the streets filled up.  I grabbed one of the Cannon 600D cameras from Kloop Media and hit the street of Bishkek to see if I could find anything interesting. I was lucky to have perfect weather and find some interesting subjects. A Collection From the Bishkek Photo Tour      &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/10/Bishkek_001.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/10/Bishkek_001.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/10/Bishkek_001.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/10/Bishkek_001.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/10/Bishkek_001.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/10/Bishkek_001.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;figure-img rounded img-fluid mb-2 mt-3 w-100&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;The view of my apartment building...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-photo-tour</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-photo-tour</guid>
        
        <category>architecture</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>photos</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My New Contact Information</title>
        <description>

Please update your records to reflect my new contact information:

Skype:
Old: judson.moore
New: JudsonLMoore

Snail Mail:
Kloop Media
Judson Moore
Ogonbaeva 222
Bishkek
270011
Kyrgyzstan

Клооп Медиа
Джадсон Моор
Огонбаева 222
Бишкек 720011
Кыргызская
Республика

Download Mailing Label Here (click)

Telephone:
+996 770 76 00 45 Kyrgyzstan
+01 310 571 5210 (powered by Google Voice VoIP Service, you can call me here 24/7 and reach me on my laptop! If I don’t answer, I will see your call and call you back, or you can leave me a voicemail. Let’s talk soon!)

Unchanged:
@JudsonLMoore (Twitter)
JudsonLMoore (Google Talk)
jaymooreusa (Windows Live Messenger)
sweetdrumr (AIM)
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/my-new-contact-information</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/my-new-contact-information</guid>
        
        <category>about me</category>
        
        <category>contact info</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bishkek Graffiti</title>
        <description>I took a long bike ride and found this great stretch of graffiti art on a long concrete wall. I haven’t seen anything else like this in Kyrgyzstan so I though it was worth sharing with the world. Please leave a comment below with your thoughts about these pieces.           &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/BishkekGraffiti_002.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/BishkekGraffiti_002.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/BishkekGraffiti_002.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/BishkekGraffiti_002.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/BishkekGraffiti_002.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/BishkekGraffiti_002.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;figure-img rounded img-fluid mb-2 mt-3 w-100&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-graffiti</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-graffiti</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>graffiti</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>photos</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bike Trek Around Bishkek</title>
        <description>I took a little trek around Bishkek and was smart enough to carry my camera with me. It was such a beautiful day! I tried to focus mostly on architecture in the beginning but then I discovered a great canal through the city with more natural area. I took this way outside of this city so I got away from the architecture but I think these photos will give you a nice idea of what are some typical visual elements to my time in Kyrgyzstan.

You can see more photos of Bishkek architecture in my other blog post, More Bishkek Photos. And even more biking photos in my post, Biking to Panorama.





  

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bike-trek-around-bishkek</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bike-trek-around-bishkek</guid>
        
        <category>architecture</category>
        
        <category>biking</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>photos</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LSU Alumni Magazine Article - Fall 2012</title>
        <description>Here is a screenshot of my most recent article in the LSU Alumni Association Magazine. The text from the article is posted below the screen shot. Enjoy!  Greetings Tiger Nation, Hot weather, sports, seemingly endless food, group activities and an element of learning by fun. Yes, it has all the symptoms of summer camp season and even half a world away few things feel different other than the language and towering mountains engulfing a summer of inspirational camps and fun. A Peace Corps Volunteer’s role often turns into that of a camp director in summer time. This summer I had many rewarding service opportunities conducting camps and special trainings for kids from all around Kyrgyzstan. Themes have...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-fall-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-fall-2012</guid>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>lsu</category>
        
        <category>lsu alumni</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>published</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>National Opera House</title>
        <description>This is the national Opera House which I pass every day to and from my office. I often hear the singers practicing through the windows so everyday I get a little bit of a free concert.
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/national-opera-house</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/national-opera-house</guid>
        
        <category>architecture</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bishkek Apartment</title>
        <description>Keeping with tradition and always being on the move, I have now moved into a new apartment after only being in Bishkek for two months. This makes the 5th place I have lived in Kyrgyzstan and my short 17 months here. This place is a real find. Right in the center of Bishkek, newly renovated and the right price (about $250). The kitchen is still being finished and a wardrobe is being installed in the bedroom, but this should give you a good idea of how I am living these days.      &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/09/P1050283-e1357552536235.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/09/P1050283-e1357552536235.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/09/P1050283-e1357552536235.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/09/P1050283-e1357552536235.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/09/P1050283-e1357552536235.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/09/P1050283-e1357552536235.jpg 1024w&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-apartment-2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-apartment-2</guid>
        
        <category>apartment</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>living conditions</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Almanbet's Brother's Wedding</title>
        <description>My good Kyrgyz friend, Almambet, invited me to attend his brother’s wedding. His brother is the general manager of the 5-star Hotel Jennat on the southern edge of Bishkek where the wedding was held. The hotel was the Monte Carlo Casino until January 2012 when casinos were outlawed in Kyrgyzstan. Now it stands as a beacon of luxury backdropped by snow-capped mountains and surrounded by Soviet-era block housing. The wedding was grand and though things were “nicer” than any of the other Kyrgyz weddings I have been to, the order of operations was pretty much the same. Ljuba came as my date. She has only been in Kyrgyzstan for a few weeks and this was his first Kyrgyz party. We...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/almanbets-brothers-wedding</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/almanbets-brothers-wedding</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>holiday</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>party</category>
        
        <category>wedding</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving To Bishkek - New City. New Work. New Address.</title>
        <description>I Am Moving To Bishkek I’ve have had a very busy and productive summer full of summer camps, exploration and moving to the capital city. I moved to Bishkek in August to expand my work developing the independent broadcast media of Kyrgyzstan. (Please update your records with my new address available on this PDF Mailing Label). Previously, while working in Talas, I was working at RadioMost 100.5 FM, the premier community radio station of Kyrgyzstan, where I was assisting them to develop new radio stations across all regions of the country. Now I have moved to Bishkek to work with the Kloop Media Foundation to develop the first ever internet radio broadcast originating from Kyrgyzstan. This station’s format will...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/new-city-new-work-new-address</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/new-city-new-work-new-address</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kloop</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>site change</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>KG Street Festival</title>
        <description>                   &lt;a class=&quot;example-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/2012/09/KGStreetFest_004.jpg&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/kg-street-festival</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/kg-street-festival</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>festivals</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>street festival</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Martin Abschieds Party</title>
        <description>                   &lt;a class=&quot;example-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/2013/01/MartinAbschiedsparty_004.jpg&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/martin-abschieds-party</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/martin-abschieds-party</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>martin</category>
        
        <category>party</category>
        
        <category>sie germans</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Giant ATX 770 Mountain Bike Technical Specifications</title>
        <description>After a 3-year hiatus beginning when I moved off to London and had a massive sell-off of all my possessions, I am back on wheels with this great bike I found in Bishkek. This used Giant ATX 770 has a few upgraded components and rides great. The price? Well, let’s call it an even trade for my 1st Gen iPad That I sold last week. The iPad wasn’t getting much use and certainly was not promoting my health. I think the trade is a good one. The real challenge will come in a few weeks when the temperatures start to drop. Will I have the strength to ride during winter? We will see… Giant ATX 770 Mountain Bike Technical...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/giant-atx-770</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/giant-atx-770</guid>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>biking</category>
        
        <category>toys</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2012 Kyrgyz Republic Independence Day</title>
        <description>               &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/08/2012KGIndeDay_015.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/08/2012KGIndeDay_015.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/08/2012KGIndeDay_015.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/08/2012KGIndeDay_015.jpg 640w,...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/2012-kyrgyz-republic-independence-day</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/2012-kyrgyz-republic-independence-day</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>freedom</category>
        
        <category>holiday</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Almanbet's Birthday Cookout</title>
        <description>My friend Linda has a friend named Almanbet who invited her to the mountains for a cook out. I got invited as a tagalong and we had a blast. We went in two cars but one broke down so we had to pile, very unsafely, into the other. The mountains were beautiful and the food was amazing. Almanbet didn’t bother to tell anyone it was his birthday but one of the girls with us revealed the secrete to us at the end of the day. It’s a pretty standup guy who just wants to enjoy time with his old friends and new on his birthday and not even bring attention to the fact. Almanbet, Happy Birthday! ...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/almanbets-birthday-cookout</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/almanbets-birthday-cookout</guid>
        
        <category>bbq</category>
        
        <category>birthday</category>
        
        <category>culture exchange</category>
        
        <category>day trips</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>mountains</category>
        
        <category>nature</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ICT Camp Dinner Night</title>
        <description>Last night I had a group of new friends in Bishkek over for dinner at my new apartment. We played Jinga, ate red beans and rice, and had a really fun time. Everyone here was involved in the 2-day camp I did in July for students from Jalalabad Oblast. They are the magic makers!           &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/ICTCampDinnerNight_003.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/ICTCampDinnerNight_003.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/ICTCampDinnerNight_003.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/ICTCampDinnerNight_003.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/ICTCampDinnerNight_003.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2013/01/ICTCampDinnerNight_003.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;figure-img...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ict-camp-dinner-night</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/ict-camp-dinner-night</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>dinner party</category>
        
        <category>friends</category>
        
        <category>ict</category>
        
        <category>jinga</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lake Issyk Kul Summer 2012</title>
        <description>Scuba Diving My friend Alina (the Kyrgyz girl in these photos) invited me a long to go on a scuba diving trip to Lake Issyk-Kul. This is a very large lake which dominates the map of Kyrgyzstan in the east. It is 118x37 miles in size and it’s deepest point is nearly 2,000 feet (668m)! It is the second largest mountain lake in the world behind Lake Titicaca in South America. There is hardly anything alive in the lake due to over fishing during Soviet times. We were diving to a depth of 10m around a dead coral reef and the largest sign of life I saw was a shrimp-like crustacean about the length of my thumbnail. Regardless, the water was very clear and the...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lake-issyk-kul-summer-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lake-issyk-kul-summer-2012</guid>
        
        <category>issyk-kul</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>lake issyk-kul</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Besh Tash with Family</title>
        <description>My second host family in Talas, Kyrgyzstan, took me to the nearby Besh Tash (Five Stones) National Park. They have a “cowboy” who watches over their flock of sheep and various other animals. We plucked one from the heard and cooked it up river-side. It was delicious! By “it” I am referring  of course, to the single national dish of the Kyrgyz people: BeshBarmak (Five Fingers). I have eaten it many times. Only twice can I consider it to have been “good.” This was one of these times and it was in fact, amazing. Check out how cute my little sister is!     &lt;a class=&quot;example-image-link&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/2012/07/P1040303.jpg&quot; data-lightbox=&quot;example-set&quot; data-title=&quot;A hotel, in the...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/besh-tash-with-family</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/besh-tash-with-family</guid>
        
        <category>besh tash</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bishkek ICT Training</title>
        <description>If there is a reason why I joined the Peace Corps it was the experience of the last few days. I conducted an ICT training for students from the southern oblast of Jalalabad where I am not allowed to travel due to Peace Corps regulations. Since I could not go to them, they came to me! Many of these students had never touched a computer before and their only interaction with the internet was what they could access through their cell phones and using text-based messaging service. While covering the basics of the internet, search, social media, research and MC Office, these students all picked up the taught basic skills right away. They were truly incredible. We also organized a tour for...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-ict-training</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-ict-training</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>ict</category>
        
        <category>irex</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>training</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2012 4th of July Bishkek Embassy Party</title>
        <description>Happy Birthday America! Here are a few photos of the festivities at the American Embassy in Bishkek. They really know how to throw a party and make us ExPats feel at home for a day! Thank you!               &lt;a...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/2012-4th-of-july-bishkek-embassy-party</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/2012-4th-of-july-bishkek-embassy-party</guid>
        
        <category>4th of july</category>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>embassy</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>party</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Golden Birthday and Sie Germans</title>
        <description>Golden Birthday Party 29 on the 29th is apparently all the reason needed to bring people from all over Kyrgyzstan to Talas. It was also the site visit weekend for the new group of volunteers (K-20). Dinner and then a house party. It was an epic evening full of friends, food, beer pong and many things which shall never ever be mentioned.           &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/GoldenBirthday_002.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/GoldenBirthday_002.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/GoldenBirthday_002.jpg 448w,...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/golden-birthday-and-sie-germans</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/golden-birthday-and-sie-germans</guid>
        
        <category>birthday</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>germans</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>party</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Radiomost Office</title>
        <description>Here is the office and colleagues from my first site in Talas City, RadioMost.                &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/RadioMostOffie_003.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/RadioMostOffie_003.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/RadioMostOffie_003.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/RadioMostOffie_003.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/RadioMostOffie_003.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/RadioMostOffie_003.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;figure-img rounded img-fluid mb-2 mt-3...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/radiomost-office</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/radiomost-office</guid>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>radiomost</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sushi Nights</title>
        <description>In the year that I have lived in Talas I have made many visits to the Kyrgyz capital city, Bishkek. During this time I have been the beneficiary of great kindness and hospitality by those who live in the capital and have housed me and made me feel at home. These last few weeks I have been house-sitting for my friend, colleague and mentor, Bettina Ruigies, and she allowed me to have some guests over. I recently learned from a Japaneese friend how to make sushi and so I hosted two sushi nights where I taught others how to do this as well. Thank you all who have supported me! I will appreciate your kindness forever! Sushi Night #1 &lt;!-- Gallery...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/sushi-night</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/sushi-night</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>cooking</category>
        
        <category>culture exchange</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>sushi</category>
        
        <category>thanks</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mars Family</title>
        <description>Mars is a dear friend of mine from Bishkek and was my main host when I visited Bishkek before I moved here. Here I am with his family having a great time enjoying a beautiful day.               &lt;a class=&quot;example-image-link&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/mars-family</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/mars-family</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>friends</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyz culture</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>K20 Site Placement Ceremony</title>
        <description>               &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/K20SitePlacement_001.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/K20SitePlacement_001.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/K20SitePlacement_001.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/K20SitePlacement_001.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/K20SitePlacement_001.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/06/K20SitePlacement_001.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/k20-site-placement-ceremony</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/k20-site-placement-ceremony</guid>
        
        <category>k20</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>pst</category>
        
        <category>site placement</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Osh Bazaar</title>
        <description>The Osh Bazaar in Bishkek is one of the most important shopping places in Kyrgyzstan. I live about a 10-15 minute walk from here and it is a pretty important place for me too.





  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/osh-bazaar</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/osh-bazaar</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>central asia</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>osh bazaar</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>shopping</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LSU Alumni Magazine Article - Summer 2012</title>
        <description> Greetings Tiger Nation, I am proud to report that I am now celebrating the 1-year anniversary of my arrival to my site in Talas, Kyrgyzstan. Over the last year I have engaged in many activities, learned a lot about myself and worked hard to help others learn skills useful to their own endeavors. Among my activities have been: coat and blanket distributions, English clubs, computer and internet trainings, community beautification projects, grant writing seminars, event management trainings and numerous cross-cultural exchanges. As rewarding as all this has been, I am now gearing up for what will likely be the most impact full activity I will carry out: summer camp. In July I will be directing a summer camp...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-summer-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-summer-2012</guid>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>lsu</category>
        
        <category>lsu alumni</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>published</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Besh Tash National Park</title>
        <description>In preparation for the 2012 Talas GLOW/TOBE Camp I needed to make a site visit to the camp site in the Besh Tash National Park. The camp had been here last year but I was not in attendance. I had a few friends come a long with me. The scenery is beautiful despite spring having not yet arrived. Entering the mouth of the mountains feels like something out of the Lord of the Rings. The photos spek for themselves!      ...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/besh-tash-national-park/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/besh-tash-national-park/</guid>
        
        <category>besh tash</category>
        
        <category>hiking</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peace Corps Hardship</title>
        <description>Life in the Peace Corps is not as luxurious as some might think it could be. Here is a quick shot of my daily hardship:  From left to right: Epiphone 6-string (steel) guitar; Mr. Coffee French press with fresh-ground columbian coffee, iPad 32GB+wifi (being used as second monitor for…), 11” Macbook Air hooked up to the internet via the USB 3G Modem, dual-sim card cell phone, Apple Mighty Mouse bluetooth mouse, iPhone 3GS pumping out the jams, Dell 15” laptop with Windows 7, Apple Time Capsule wireless base station hosting my iTunes, computer backup and charging the iPhone, 100watt 2.1 sound system hooked up to iPhone and disturbing the neighbors. I know. It’s rough, but hey, someone has to do...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/peace-corps-hardship</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/peace-corps-hardship</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Disaster Ski Trip</title>
        <description>I don’t like to be negative about too many things, but man oh man this day was pretty much a disaster (and I have seen some disasters.. Katrina, Rita, Gustav… I know what I am talking about!) The car was late picking us up, the ski rental shop was closed, finally found another one, then drove to the resort, our car couldn’t make it up the mountain so about a mile short of the skibase we strapped on our ski boots and hiked up while lugging our skis. Reaching the skibase totally exhausted and freezing I went into the cafe and ordered lagman and chai which cost about 500com (5 times what you would expect to pay anywhere else). Then...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/disaster-ski-trip</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/disaster-ski-trip</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>disaster</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>ski kg</category>
        
        <category>ski trip</category>
        
        <category>skiing</category>
        
        <category>tik</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Bishkek / Talas Winter Road Conditions</title>
        <description>Think you have a tough commute? This is just another day in the life of a Talas Peace Corps Volunteer. I came to a point where every time I got in a car to make this drive I full accepted the idea that this may be the very last time I use my legs. It is no way to live accepting something like that, but it is a real risk we take out there. Good luck to everyone who still has to make the journey!      &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/03/P1020144.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_256/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/03/P1020144.jpg 256w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_448/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/03/P1020144.jpg 448w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_640/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/03/P1020144.jpg 640w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_832/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/03/P1020144.jpg 832w, https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1024/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2012/03/P1020144.jpg 1024w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;figure-img rounded img-fluid mb-2 mt-3...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-talas-winter-road-conditions</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/bishkek-talas-winter-road-conditions</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>danger</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>road to bishkek</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>winter</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LSU Alumni Magazine Article - Spring 2012</title>
        <description>Greetings Tiger Nation, As the New Year gets it’s start in this winter wonderland of Central Asia, I find myself drowning in opportunity for service in 2012. Starting off on the right foot in a partnership with United States Air Force soldiers from the Manas Transit Center in Bishkek (the gateway for American soldiers entering and leaving Afghanistan), I worked to distribute 1500 coats and blankets to needy children in western Kyrgyzstan.  “Operation Warm &amp;amp; Dry” was a military humanitarian mission that partnered with Peace Corps Volunteers and PCV-counterparts to bring warmth to those who most need it.  It was an honor to work with US servicemen but most importantly the project made a great impact. With only 18 more...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-spring-2012</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-spring-2012</guid>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>lsu</category>
        
        <category>lsu alumni</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>published</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peace Corps Volunteers on Kyrgyz National Television OTPK</title>
        <description>How and why were Peace Corps Volunteers on Kyrgyz National Television?

Kyrgyz national television ОТРК-1 recently came to my house to interview some Peace Corps Volunteers about how we celebrate the New Year in American and how we will celebrate the holiday in the Kyrgyz Republic.



Peace Corps Volunteers and Counterparts Appearing In this video:


  
    Aika Kanaeva: Peace Corps Counterpart
  
  
    Judson L Moore : K-19
  
  
    Lindsay Hull: K-18
  
  
    Andrew Hull: K-18
  

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/pcvs-on-kyrgyz-national-television</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/pcvs-on-kyrgyz-national-television</guid>
        
        <category>journalism</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>video</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thanksgiving, New Government and New Year</title>
        <description>Being as far away from America as I am did not put even the slightest dent in my celebrating the Thanksgiving holiday last week. Thanks to the US Embassy in Bishkek and the Peace Corps staff we had 3 x 20lbs Butterball turkeys and all the dishes you would expect to see at any American celebration of thanks. The PC Medical Officer (who plays excellent blues guitar) and I provided the entertainment. He played blues/jazz guitar while I accompanied on drums and occasionally I also played guitar. This was my first public guitar performance and I feel pretty good about it. I even led a few sing-alongs of American Pie and Stand By Me. While in Bishkek for the week...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/thanksgiving-new-government-and-new-year</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/thanksgiving-new-government-and-new-year</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>holiday</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>thanksgiving</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Program Travel Report Nov 13-27, 2011</title>
        <description>Sunday Nov 13 - Monday Nov 14 These were travel days to the HIV Training in Cholpon Ata. The first day was travel by taxi from Talas to Bishkek.  The second day was travel by PC-supplied charter bus from PC Office - Cholpon Ata.  One thing to note was that for Talas volunteers it was impossible to travel to Bishkek on the same day as traveling to Cholpon Ata due to the winter road conditions being too unstable to guarantee our arrival on time. On the PC Charter Bus I took advantage of my Russian tutor being present.  We sat together and did a 3-hour lesson consisting of vocabulary drills and verb conjugations. Tuesday Nov 15 - Thursday...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/program-travel-report-nov-13-27-2011</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/program-travel-report-nov-13-27-2011</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LSU Alumni Magazine Article – Winter 2011</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-winter-2011</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/lsu-alumni-magazine-article-winter-2011</guid>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>lsu</category>
        
        <category>lsu alumni</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>published</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Thanksgiving in Kyrgyzstan</title>
        <description>Happy Thanksgiving! Things here were very eventful on Thursday but not a a holiday. However,this week has been quite amazing. On Tuesday I returned to Bishkek fromKarakol (ski town in the far east of Kyrgyzstan) and went to Rotary for the1st time where I met (among others) some exchange students from the USA,who I then joined for Mexican food (1st time!) the next day for lunch.After the meeting I went to a cafe and sat in with a band for a while. Iknocked their socks off! Apparently, though Kyrgyzstan has no shortage oftalented musicians, there are not many drummers, and even as out ofpractice as I am, I was among the best they had ever heard. As a result, Iwas...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/thanksgiving-in-kyrgyzstan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/thanksgiving-in-kyrgyzstan</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>holidays</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>May Freedom Ring</title>
        <description>Yesterday was the 20th anniversary of the Kyrgyz Republic’s independence from the USSR. To mark the occasion there was a parade downtown in front of the White House (The State of Talas’s government building) in the morning followed by widely-held house parties, demonstrations of the national horse games and fireworks in the evening. The horse games were by far the most interesting thing I have seen in country. Essentially it is a game of Polo but instead of sticks, players used their hands, and instead of a ball, the object of attention is a headless sheep carcass. The manner in which the game is performed resembles more closely demolition derby than any other sport Westerners might be familiar with. I...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/may-freedom-ring</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/may-freedom-ring</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Peela Chai Each</title>
        <description>Last week was RadioMost’s 4th Anniversary as the pioneer community radio station in Kyrgyzstan.  To mark the occasion we had a music festival at which a few of my fellow Peace Corps Volunteers performed a song.

This song, a translated cover of The Kink’s, “Have A Cup of Tea,” was such an anticipated success that these volunteers were requested to perform it on-air during an interview.  Here is the recording of that interview and the new hit single, “Peela Chai Each.”

Enjoy!


</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/peela-chai-each</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/peela-chai-each</guid>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>k10</category>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>pcvs</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>pixies</category>
        
        <category>radiomost</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Nature of My Work</title>
        <description>I have been at my site now for 1 month. Though I have only scratched the surface of my work’s potential and am still in the “honeymoon” phase, I feel like I have accomplished a lot. I will write more on the programs I have created later once they are funded. For now, allow me just to introduce you to my office. The MediaMost Foundation is a non-governmental organization located in Talas City in the western part of the Kyrgyz Republic. The mission of MediaMost is to bring about social reform and development by bridging the information gap and thus helping people in Talas prosper by giving them access to information. MediaMost’s primary operation is RadioMost FM 100.5. This radio...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-nature-of-my-work</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-nature-of-my-work</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Жатсон доско тамаша!</title>
        <description>For my birthday, the Press Secretary to the Governor of Talas State wrote me a song. Here it is in the original Kyrgyz, and a (bad) translation of the text from Google Translate. Жатсон доско тамаша! (Kyrgyz) Океандын ар жагы, болсо да Жатсон турагы, Алыстан аттын арытып Таласка келген убагы. Билими жетик жаш бала келгени бизди кубаннты, Долбоорду бизге жазышып коп акча тартат сыягы. Канткен менен досубуз алп мучолуу балбандай, Тилди дагы коп билет, суйлой билет ар кандай. Баарынан да тан калдым, октом жигит окшойсун, Манас деп атын коюпсун Айколдон дагы тайманбай! Туулган кунун кут болсун, жалпылап куттук айтабыз! Омурундо коп болсун тамаша менен тайпаныз, Журо бербей колоктоп кыздарды дагы жанданыз, Алыска барбай эле сиз радио мосттон танданыз! Калынын...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/kyrgyz-poem-for-my-birthday/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/kyrgyz-poem-for-my-birthday/</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rotary Is Ubiquitous</title>
        <description>For many of you this post is going to sound like a broken record. But hey, it’s a big deal to me, so keep reading. :) My parent’s aside, I more or less give credit to Rotary International for me being who I am today. I won’t run down the whole history, but to understand what I want to say I need to go back (nearly) to the beginning. When I was in high school I had the opportunity to serve as a Rotary Youth Exchange Student in Germany for 1 year. The was my first time out of the country and certainly the longest that I was away from home. This opened my eyes to the world and and...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/rotary-is-ubiquitous</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/rotary-is-ubiquitous</guid>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Working Hard For The (no) Money</title>
        <description>Thus far in the Peace Corps, I have been elected or appointed into every available leadership roll. They are: Airport Captain: I was responsible for the movement of volunteers and information sharing of all logistics to all volunteers from JFK&amp;gt;Istanbul&amp;gt;Bishkek. There were 4 captains, for different stages of the journey. My responsibility seemed to be the most constantly active.. always having to count heads and mark off names every time we got onto or off of an airplane. I was always the last one onboard and the first one off. Trainee Action Committee: I was the representative of my language group during our 10-week training that had the “official” line of communication to the PC Staff in regards to things...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/working-hard-for-the-no-money</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/working-hard-for-the-no-money</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A quick update on the last week of my life…</title>
        <description>A quick update on the last week of my life… The swearing-in ceremony was eventful, as expected. It was held in the national theater and the building had a perimeter of police that would make you believe the president was there. In fact, we did have the Ambassadors of both the USA and Japan present, along with many high-ministers and cabinet members of the Kyrgyz Government. About 500 people in total. The ceremony WAS broadcast on the internet, but we were provided with the wrong link. The correct link, where clips and be viewed on-demand, is here (I am in the front row sitting on stage, green shirt, purple tie): After the ceremony the Volunteers were bussed away to the...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/a-quick-update-on-the-last-week-of-my-life</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/a-quick-update-on-the-last-week-of-my-life</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Day On Site in Talas City</title>
        <description>I haven’t seen as many horses as I have seen today since I lived in Kentucky! I arrived in Talas City about 3 hours ago and had dinner (and tea, of course).  Dinner was amazing.. fresh veggies and fruits (both of which have been lacking in my diet) as well as an assortment of baked and meat-based foods.  It was all very delicious.  I have a host- mom and dad, 3 sisters age ranging from 7-20, 1 brother age 5+- and maybe another brother slightly older… family dynamics here are really hard to figure out! The younger sister played a violin concert for me.  She is quite good for her age!  Reminds me very much of my cousin Matthew...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/first-day-on-site-in-talas-city</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/first-day-on-site-in-talas-city</guid>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Site Placement - Radiomost 100.5FM</title>
        <description>The NGO I will be working for is call Radiomost. I have not been given very much information from the PC about this organization but after some Google searches I found the articles below.

https://www.unesco.kz/ci/projects/2004/talas/report_cmc_talas_2004.pdf

This seems to be a rewritten version of the first article but has some extra detail
https://www.unesco.kz/?lang=&amp;amp;newsid=2049&amp;amp;menu=&amp;amp;keyword=

Twitter!
https://twitter.com/radiomost
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/site-placement-radiomost-100-5fm</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/site-placement-radiomost-100-5fm</guid>
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        <category>talas</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Arrived Safely to Bishkek!</title>
        <description>I have arrived safely to Kyrgyzstan! The country is breathtakingly beautiful, the people are amazing and the food is even pretty awesome! This is my first time to access the internet and I probably won’t have another chance for about a week. I will be receiving a cell phone on or around April 9, at which time my outbound communication will improve. Training so far is a lot of fun but does not allow for very much sleep. Language is coming along pretty quickly. I will meet my host family later this afternoon for the first time and will be staying with them for the next 3 months in the city of Kant. Please keep in touch, I love and...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/arrived-safely-to-bishkek</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/arrived-safely-to-bishkek</guid>
        
        <category>bishkek</category>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In Route to the Kyrgyz Republic</title>
        <description>We are in route to Istanbul, Delta Flight 75 from JFK.  The in flight film was The Kings Speech.  Brilliant!  I am so glad to have seen it  It was on the top of my list of movies to see before I left the country and I never had the time for it.  Just goes to show that things tend to work out if you just trust the system. People have been asking me for weeks if I am excited about my service and thus far I have mostly said that I am not.  Reason being is that I was excited weeks ago and that recently I have just been READY.  Well, here I am, on the place, the USA...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/in-route-to-the-kyrgyz-republic</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/in-route-to-the-kyrgyz-republic</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I have Arrived at Staging</title>
        <description>I have safely arrived to the Staging hotel in Philadelphia (room 542 if you are nearby!) I don’t have anything scheduled until tomorrow at noon. From there, the schedule is head spinning! The staging event will last for 7 hours tomorrow afternoon. Presumably there will be free time in the evening to get to know my new colleagues and friends. At 8am on Saturday we all board a bus that will take us to NYC where we will fly out of JFK in the late afternoon. After a 7 hour layover in Istanbul, we will arrive to Bishkek Kyrgyzstan at 2am on Monday morning. Again, busses will pick us up and take up about 10 miles outside of town to...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/i-have-arrived-at-staging</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/i-have-arrived-at-staging</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kyrgyzstan + Anthropology</title>
        <description>My parent’s live near Texas A&amp;amp;M University and they discovered a Anthropologist who teaches there and specializes in the Kyrgyz culture and the surrounding region.  I emailed with her and got an interesting list readings that I thought I should share. Here is what she suggested: To get a better undertanding of local culture, I recommend articles by the following cultural anthropologists:  Judith Beyer Madeleiene Reeves Morgan Liu Kathleen Kuehnast Julie McBrien  I also highly recommend a book edited by Jeff Sahadeo and Russell Zanca on Everyday Life in Central Asia. This book contains essays about all of the Central Asian republics. Many of daily life customs and values are quite similar across the region, so it is...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/kyrgyzstan-anthropology</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/kyrgyzstan-anthropology</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Selected: Kyrgyz Republic</title>
        <description>I was right! Kyrgyz Republic here I come! So where is that you ask?  Well I will tell you: Also known as Kyrgyzstan, it is a landlocked country bordered by Kazakhstan to the north, Uzbekistan to the west, Tajikistan to the southwest and People’s Republic of China to the east. Some facts:   The official languages are Kyrgyz and Russian   The population is less than 6 million   The whole country is the size of Nebraska   The Kyrgyz ethnic makeup is a mix of Asian influence in the east and the Kyrgyz’s in the north identified by their red hair and pale skin (I found my people!)   80% of the population identify...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/selected-kyrgyz-republic</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/selected-kyrgyz-republic</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Selected! But Not Much More...</title>
        <description>Woooo!  My status has been updated to SELECTED FOR SERVICE!  Most unfortunately there is nothing else to report at this time.  They only state    “Congratulations, you have been selected for service with the Peace Corps. More information is on it’s way to you in the mail.”  So more sit and wait.  Though I have deduced a location.  I have no reason to believe that this is it but by applying the scientific method and process of elimination, I have found that the only country in Asia/Central Asia that has a Community Development Program that departs in late March is to the Kyrgyz Republic. This is only based on the information available to me and some guess work.  I have no way...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/selected-but-not-much-more</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/selected-but-not-much-more</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>All Thats Left</title>
        <description>All that stands between me and getting on the airplane is the actual invitation.  The Selection Committee in Washington DC couldn’t even open my file until I was medically cleared.  Now that I am cleared, hopefully they can come to a decision quickly and I can find out what path my life will take.

If the selection committee has half of the enthusiasm for me that my recruiter had, then this should be a no-brainer for them.

Now I really am holding my breath.

JM
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/all-thats-left</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/all-thats-left</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medically Cleared</title>
        <description>Two days ago my status was updated to reflect that “a decision has been made regarding your medical eligibility.”  Well that is sure a little bit unsettling.  I have seen all of my results and everyone assures me that I am 100% healthy and that all tests came back with the desired results.  Plus I was on the phone with my PC medical office a few days ago and she told me that she expected to clear me the next day (when in fact my status was updated). Today I was visiting with Marguerite Constantine, the single most influential woman in my life aside from my mom.  Marguerite is the reason why any of this is happening.  She was the one that...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medically-cleared</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medically-cleared</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medical Review - The Poilo Catch 22</title>
        <description>The VA does not give Polio Boosters.  I don’t have a record that I have had one before.  All the local hospitals, clinics and doctor’s offices that give polio booster shots do so with shots provided by the federal government.  The feds regulate that the shots are to be given at no cost but only to people 10 years of age and younger. So the Feds are requiring that I get this shot, and are also the reason why I can not get the shot.  What a conundrum! Jason to the rescue again!  Turns out that Jason’s Czechian dance instructor is also the director of the public health clinic here.  The clinic already told me no-go on the shot, but Louisiana politics...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medical-review-the-poilo-catch-22</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medical-review-the-poilo-catch-22</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medical Review - Blood and Teeth</title>
        <description>17 vials of blood!!  They took more blood out of me than I knew I even had in me!  It was more or less painless but still it was a shock to the system.  I had breakfast right after and then I was feeling fine. After breakfast I checked in with Charlie and he sent me to Dental.  I was in and out of there pretty quickly.  Seems I still have pretty healthy teeth.  My dentist was really awesome.  He has just started at the VA after retiring from a dental career in the Navy where he spent the past 20 years stationed at the Pentagon.  I imagine he must be good at what he does since he has worked...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medical-review-blood-and-teeth</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medical-review-blood-and-teeth</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medical Review - The VA</title>
        <description>Turns out that the Peace Corps has an agreement with the Department of Veterans Affairs allowing for Peace Corps applicants to ge their medical exams done at a VA Facility.  Luckily, my other housemate, Jason, is active duty Army (currently on leave) and has some great contacts at the VA in Pineville.  We went over there today and jumped through all sorts of hoops but finally I got through to the eligibility officer who got me setup with the nurse that oversees Employment Health.  His name is Charlie S. Charlie is a super cool dude and I am glad he is my point of contact.  Very laid back and eager to help out.  As you can imagine, the VA doesn’t get a lot...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medical-review-the-va</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medical-review-the-va</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Medical Review - Eyes</title>
        <description>My housemate, Jenny, works at the Alexandria Eye and Laser Center and got me hooked up with an eye exam.  That was easy enough.  Turns out, I still have perfect vision!

I got my medical packet in the mail a few days ago.  The eye part is clearly the easiest.  The rest of this looks like it is going to be pretty difficult to get done in time.

Here’s lookin’ at you!

JM
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medical-review-eyes</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/medical-review-eyes</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interview Done and Nomination In Hand</title>
        <description>I’m just going to jump in and tell you the end of the story up front: I had my interview and apparently it went well because I was nominated on the spot! Curt (my recruiter) told me that he was scheduling interviews for 6 weeks from now but when he read my resume he thought that I would be very well suited for a program that closes nominations this Friday.  He bumped up my interview to ASAP and upon concluding everything told me that he was very impressed with me and asked if I would be interested in a program of this description:   Departs late March 2011   Would be located in Asia/Central Asia   I...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-done-and-nomination-in-hand</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-done-and-nomination-in-hand</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interview Scheduled (for TOMORROW!)</title>
        <description>WOAH!  This is crazy!  My regional Peace Corps office (Dallas) received the additional follow up paperwork for my application yesterday and they called me today to setup an interview for TOMORROW!

My recruiter’s name is Curt Baker.  Sounds like he is on my side with things.  I am excited to know him and I look forward to the interview… TOMORROW!

JM

PS: Please excuse the all-CAPS words.. I think it’s tacky and I usually don’t do that, but I am pretty excited right now and want you to freak out (at least a little) with me!  THANKS!
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 26 Oct 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-scheduled-for-tomorrow</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/interview-scheduled-for-tomorrow</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Application Submitted!</title>
        <description>Ok so not much of an update here.  It took me weeks to do what I could have really done in a few hours or days at most.  Darn those essays!

I received an email from the Peace Corps a week ago stating that application were due by October 1 if an applicant hopes to depart in summer/fall of 2011.  I made the deadline, now it is just a matter of hearing back from them.

Holding my breath but trying not to think about it.

JM
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/application-submitted</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/application-submitted</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Application Followup Paperwork</title>
        <description>Well they got the application but that (of course) just lead to more paperwork!  They sent me forms for fingerprints and are asking about financial (read: debt) standings.  Luckily I am pretty much debt free and getting the finger prints was easy enough thanks to the fine folks at the Pineville Police Department.

Follow up work done and submitted.

Still holding my breath.

JM
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/application-followup-paperwork</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/application-followup-paperwork</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why The Peace Corps?</title>
        <description>Having grown up in a politically-charged family I always took politics and matters of great concern with a grain of salt. It was not until my return from a year in Germany as a Rotary Youth Exchange Student that I started to have a greater appreciation for the world around me. Exactly one year later I returned from a 6-month trip to Brazil. As my mother says, “Germany opened my eyes to the world and Brazil opened my eyes to myself.” I have long since believed in a life of “Service Above Self,” the mantra of Rotary International, an organization that has done more for me than is deserved.  I have been an active Rotaractor on the local and international...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/why-the-peace-corps</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/why-the-peace-corps</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reflections and the Future</title>
        <description>The past year has been quite busy for me!  In the past 12 months I have lived in Chattanooga TN, London UK, Bryan TX, New Orleans LA, Los Angeles CA and now I hang my hat in Atlanta GA.  It’s hard to say that in this period of time one can truly live in this many locations, but somehow I have done it. Now I am faced with trying to figure out the future.  Where will my path lead next?  I am miffed to admit that I do not know.  Through all the change in the last year, I had a plan and a backup plan.  Now I don’t even have plan A. While I sort through job postings and...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/reflections-and-the-future</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/reflections-and-the-future</guid>
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Everything I Own, Right Here.</title>
        <description> Thats right.  I finally did it.  I am down to a backpack and a suitcase!  (well, a backpack, and 2 suitcases…) The boxes in the middle are to be shipped to my parent’s house for long-term storage.  The suitcases and backpack are all I am living out of now.  My goal is to get down to the small suitcase and my backpack, and nothing else. This has been a long-term goal for me and I am damn near completion.  Thank you to Aeslya for buying my car and helping me get down to this.  The car was the major prohibitor.  So long as...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/everything-i-own-right-here</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/everything-i-own-right-here</guid>
        
        
        <category>peace corps</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What I would have said - home is where the heart is</title>
        <description>Had I the opportunity to address tonight’s audience at the celebration of the 10th Anniversary of the Rotaract Club of Southbay, I would have said this: In 2006 I made my first journey to Los Angeles.  I was 1 of 6 delegates representing the Rotaract Club of LSU to the 2006 USCC Conference hosted at UCLA by Rotaract District 5280. During this trip, I became acquainted with the Rotaract Club of Southbay and a few of their illustrious members: Cheryl, Claudia, Megan, Tori, Jonathan, and Roderick (to name a few). Ever since this trip, Los Angeles has been on the horizon for me. It has always just been a matter of time.  From this brief conference, I knew there was...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/home-is-where-the-heart-is</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/home-is-where-the-heart-is</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>rotary</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Celebrity Encounters List</title>
        <description>* indicates the number of times I have encountered this group/person **.38 Special* 12 Stones* 4 Lyn* Afroman* Alabama* Alice In Chains* Al Kapone* Alter Bridge* American Bang* Another Animal* Ben Kweller Blackfoot* Black Stone Cherry* Blind Melon Boys Like Girls* Breaking Benjamin****** Brian Howe of Bad Company* Buckcherry* Carrie Underwood* Chamillionaire** Charlie Daniel’s Band* Cherry Moore ∞ Chevelle** Chris Cagle* Chris Young* Collective Soul* Corey Smith* Cross Canadian Ragweed** Darius Rucker* Daughtry** Dave Matthews* Dezmond Meeks ∞ Dierks Bently* Dinosaur Jr.* Dr. John*...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/celebrity-encounters-list</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/celebrity-encounters-list</guid>
        
        <category>celebrity encounter</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Did it while I was young</title>
        <description>“Do it while you’re young.” I can’t tell you how many times I heard those words growing up. I heard them from family, friends, T.V., people I aspired to be like, and everywhere in between. I don’t know how many times it took hearing before it sank in, but eventually, it did. I have lived on three continents, in four countries, and in 12 cities in the past ten years. I am not a military brat. I am not a gypsy (though I might like to be one day). I am not sketchy. I am certainly not running from anything or anyone. If anything, I am running toward something, though I don’t know who, where or what that is. What...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/did-it-while-i-was-young</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/did-it-while-i-was-young</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>sticky</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Blogging Failure</title>
        <description>When I was eight years old, my mom sat me down at the dining room table, placed a composition journal in front of me, and told me there would be no T.V. or playing until I wrote an ENTIRE half page of my thoughts.  She knew the importance of journaling. While my parents vary rarely made the dumb mistakes that plague most child-rearing experiments, mom did this time: she thought that equating writing with the lack of fun activities would be the best way for me to fall in love with the task. Of course, she was wrong. I pouted and complained and came with all sorts of witty reasons why I was unable to write and why running off...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/my-blogging-failure</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/my-blogging-failure</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Concert Posters</title>
        <description>My first job after university was as a concert promoter at TCB Concerts (now Green Machine Concerts). I worked with some of the biggest names in American music during that time, including Taylor Swift, the White Stripes, ZZ Top, and Eric Church. Below are a collection of concert posters from the shows that I was a part of producing. Update: Jim Green, my friend, mentor, and legendary independent music promoter, the founder of Green Machine Concerts, passed away in June 2020. His obituary can be read here.      &lt;img src=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_1200/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/06/2008.11.10_OAR_in_F230083.jpg&quot; srcset=&quot;https://res.cloudinary.com/judsonlmoore-com/image/fetch/c_fill,g_auto,f_auto,q_auto,w_159/https://www.judsonlmoore.com/assets/images/2014/06/2008.11.10_OAR_in_F230083.jpg 159w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot; class=&quot;figure-img rounded img-fluid mb-2 mt-3 w-100&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;&quot; loading=&quot;lazy&quot;...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/concert-posters</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/concert-posters</guid>
        
        <category>concerts</category>
        
        <category>career</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to identify and accomplish your life goals</title>
        <description>People tend to speak about goal-setting in cliches, which is too bad because spending time reflecting on what you want out of life and writing down your life goals is an important thing to do and review often. In the example below, I share my personal life goals, which I wrote as finishing college. The exercise is quite simple to do and consists of just two parts. Your life goals The first part is to identify the one overarching theme you want your life to represent. What one thing do you most want to be able to say you did with your life (not just in your life). Perhaps it is easier to think about this point in terms of...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/life-goals-exercise</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/life-goals-exercise</guid>
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
        <category>accomplishments</category>
        
        <category>goals</category>
        
        <category>impact</category>
        
        <category>interests</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Elgin Marbles - Should they be returned to Greece?</title>
        <description>The prestige of the world’s finest museums is primarily rooted in collections of stolen art.  There is a fair share of ‘home-grown’ art in national museums, but there are also vast collections of artifacts that have been obtained by nations by forcefully removing them from their places of origin.  These acts are frequently done during times of conquest when one country has fallen to a greater power, and the taking from the weak is generally accepted as normal behavior under these circumstances.  However, there has rarely been an act of thievery so damaging to the history of culture and carried out in such an unforgiving way than removing the Parthenon sculptures known as the Elgin Marbles. The Parthenon, built in...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-elgin-marbles-should-they-be-returned-to-greece</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-elgin-marbles-should-they-be-returned-to-greece</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Does Oil Hender Democracy?</title>
        <description>The article, Does Oil Hender Democracy, by Michael Ross, examines why the generally excepted theory that economic growth fosters democratic rule fails in countries where the main economic stimulator is from oil production.  The Middle East, Central Asia, and Venezuela share two things in common: they are all major oil-producing countries, and they all have non-democratic regimes.  Ross structures his paper by studying three aspects of the “oil-impedes-democracy” claim. The first of these aspects is testing whether or not a claim is valid.  For instance, it is difficult to test the validity of a claim when there are no variations upon which to test it.  The example Ross gives us is that of countries in the Middle East that...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/does-oil-hender-democracy</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/does-oil-hender-democracy</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Decision that Saved the World -  An Analysis of the Decision-Making Process during the Cuban Missile Crisis</title>
        <description>During the thirteen days from October 18-29, 1962, the world stood and watched as the United States and U.S.S.R. nearly entered into a war that could have resulted in a worldwide nuclear holocaust.  The showdown resulted from the extraction of Soviet nuclear presence in Cuba in exchange for the removal of American atomic weapons in Turkey and a continued quarantine against Cuba, which is still in place to this day.  There were many events during this thirteen-day period that nearly set off a war. Yet, thanks to the diligent decisions made by both President John F. Kennedy and Russian Premier Khrushchev, nuclear war was avoided. The Kennedy administration played a key roll in avoiding catastrophe by adhering to a process...</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-decision-that-saved-the-world-an-analysis-of-the</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-decision-that-saved-the-world-an-analysis-of-the</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The American Red Cross - An International Organization</title>
        <description>The American Red Cross was chartered in 1905 by the American Congress to “carry on a system of national and international relief in time of peace and apply the same in mitigating the sufferings caused by pestilence, famine, fire, floods, and other great national calamities, and to devise and carry on measures for preventing the same.”  The American Red Cross plays a substantial role in the United States and the world in assisting victims of disaster (clients), and other agencies involved in disaster situations (firefighters, FEMA, police, etc.) Here in Louisiana, the Red Cross most recently played a huge role in the relief efforts from Hurricanes Katrina and Rita through financial assistance, providing shelter, medical supplies, and handing out hygiene...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-american-red-cross-an-international-organization</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-american-red-cross-an-international-organization</guid>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Comparison of Emergency Warning Systems</title>
        <description>A November 2000 report published by the executive Subcommittee on Natural Disaster Reduction about Natural Disaster Information Systems, three different major disaster warning systems and their relative application and effectiveness were discussed.  These three were the NOAA Weather Radio, the Emergency Alert System, and GPS technology. The NOAA Weather Radio is one of the few broad-range warning systems which is exclusively government-controlled and owned.  This system works by broadcasting a four to six-minute-long warning about weather hazards in a particular area and then looping it so that anyone can tune in and get the alert at any time.  This radio network is currently available in 90% of the United States but is hindered by the fact that one must own...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/a-comparison-of-emergency-warning-systems</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/a-comparison-of-emergency-warning-systems</guid>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Review of The Tin Drum by Günter Grass</title>
        <description>The main character and narrator is Oskar Matzerath. Oskar is a man who never grew up, literally. He stunted his growth when he was three years old, at three feet. In the book, he does grow an additional 13 inches. Oskar is known for never parting with his red and white lacquered tin drum, which he is continuously beating on. Oskar’s other unique characteristic is that he has an extremely high-pitched singing voice, shatter glass. As Oskar grows taller, he also loses this glass-breaking voice. Oskar does not attend school but tries to educate himself instead of studying Goethe and Rasputin’s writings. Jan Bronski isVincent Bronski’s son and Oskar’s mother. Oskar believes that Jan is his birth father. Jan is...</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/book-review-tin-drum</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/book-review-tin-drum</guid>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Four Technologies of Disaster Management</title>
        <description>When working in a disaster, there are many resources and available technologies to help managers coordinate relief efforts.  Some of the critical technologies include mapping, aerial photography, information management, and logistics.  The following is a brief review of these four areas and how their proper implication in the disaster management field can make a difference in saving lives. Knowing the geographic features of the affected area are extremely important.  Having reliable maps is key to planning the distribution of resources and people and determining what obstacles are likely to be in the way of getting to those locations.  Many different types of maps can assess the area: topographic maps, geologic maps, hazard maps, demographic maps, and hurricane tracking maps.  It...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/four-technologies-of-disaster-management</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/four-technologies-of-disaster-management</guid>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Play Review - The Weavers</title>
        <description>The Weavers, by Gerhart Hauptman, is a play about the suppressed weavers of Peterswaldu, Langenbielau, and Kaschbach, Germany.  This story tells about their efforts to liberalize themselves from the trappings of poverty and the social structure, which keeps them there.  This struggle leads to a violent revolt, which ends with innocent death.  Before the play’s events can be outlined in any detail, I will introduce a few of the main characters. Dreissiger is a local merchant and owner of a textile production company.  The weavers come to him once a week to sell him the cloth they have made and obtain new yarn to make more for the next month.  Dreissiger pays the weavers too little because he says that...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/play-review-the-weavers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/play-review-the-weavers</guid>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The History of Events Surrounding the Camp David Accords</title>
        <description>Turmoil and unrest have been embedded as a day-to-day presence in the Middle East for much of history. This can be explicitly seen in the region being fought over between Jews and Arabs, now known as Israel. The Israeli-Palestinian conflict erupted in 1967 and has been the source of multiple wars, economic and cultural chaos, and the loss of countless lives. Throughout this conflict, there have been many actors and many battlefields, but not much progress. The most significant progress was made at the United States intervention under the Jimmy Carter administration in 1978, which produced the Camp David Accords. These documents would spearhead negotiations for the following decades. Still, they would continue to prove that no foundation is truly...</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-history-of-events-surrounding-the-camp-david</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-history-of-events-surrounding-the-camp-david</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sponsored Identity - Cultural Policy in Puerto Rico (book review)</title>
        <description>Sponsored Identity: Cultural Policy in Puerto Rico, by Arlene Davilla, explores the current and historical context of Puerto Rico’s cultural identity, mostly as expressed through events and festivals.  The author explores the government’s concern about the expanding presence of corporate sponsors and how they affect the traditional aspects of the nation, and what problems this poses for some people.  The author lays out a compelling combination of facts that revolve around how this influence is being regulated to stay within reasonable guidelines and how it affects the nation’s festive scene. Much of the political culture of Puerto Rico has changed over the last half-century.  In 1952 there was considerable support for independence from the United States.  In the 1993...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/sponsored-identity-cultural-policy-in-puerto-rico</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/sponsored-identity-cultural-policy-in-puerto-rico</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Development of the Modern State</title>
        <description>In this chapter, two points are made: first, discuss the different forms of ‘state’ which have existed and how they transformed into the modern state; second, why it is that the nation-state became the dominant form of the modern state. The author shares that the modern state has its birth in European history, stretching back to the Holy Roman Empire 1600 years ago. The author continuously refers to the idea that the history of the modern state is the history of Europe. Early in Europe, Feudalism was the major form of government. This form of government is structured by loose agreements and obligations which flow down to an autonomous level. Feudalism was the most popular form of government from the...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-development-of-the-modern-state</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-development-of-the-modern-state</guid>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Otto von Bismarck and His Path to Unification</title>
        <description>During the 19th Century, Europe underwent many dynamic changes such as many wars, governmental upheavals, and cultural refinements; therefore, no one thing could stand alone as the European 19th Century’s main event. However, if one were to take the largest geographic area in central Europe in a single empire, one would find Prussia and Austria. Therefore, Germany’s unification could reasonably be considered the most dynamic change in central Europe during the 19th Century, with the possible exception of the 1848 revolutions. With little doubt, Otto von Bismarck was the most influential leader of Prussia during this time frame. His authoritative leadership aided in the creation of a unified Germany. Bismarck’s legacy was to see the German people united, and he...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/otto-von-bismarck-and-his-path-to-unification</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/otto-von-bismarck-and-his-path-to-unification</guid>
        
        <category>austro-prussian war</category>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>otto von bismarck</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        <category>prussia</category>
        
        <category>research paper</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Raven in Native American Mythology</title>
        <description>Native American culture is embedded with extensive tales and legends.  Every aspect of life, death, and existence has its own story to explain why things are the way they are.  Often, different Native American tribes had very similar beliefs, but most tribes have their own unique variations in the details of these legends. The raven is a significant figure in most Native American cultures.  It is seen as the creator of light and as a trickster figure.  As the maker of light, the raven symbolizes the ultimate creator of all things that existed before the beginning.  As a trickster figure, the raven is seen as a catalyst of mischief and mayhem. Although credited as the “creator” of life, one story of...</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-raven-in-native-american-mythology</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/the-raven-in-native-american-mythology</guid>
        
        <category>culture</category>
        
        <category>mythology</category>
        
        <category>native american</category>
        
        <category>raven</category>
        
        <category>symbols</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Book Review - The Unification of Germany</title>
        <description>The Unification of Germany, by Michael Gorman, is a short yet precise and detailed book that outlines the events surrounding and influencing the German Unification of 1870-71.  This book tells the history of Germany during the 19th century, focusing on details that help the reader understand the causes for revolution in 1848, the conflict between central European states, and Germany’s eventual unification as a nation-state. This book is packed full of translated primary sources that powerfully illustrate the changes and the preventions during this time, political cartoons, charts and graphs, and commentary from the author. To help the reader understand the book’s purpose, the author includes a chapter by chapter synopsis of the book in the introduction.  Covering all of...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2004 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/book-review-the-unification-of-germany</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/book-review-the-unification-of-germany</guid>
        
        <category>germany</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
        <category>college</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meeting Papa Roach on tour in Hamburg Germany</title>
        <description>Today I get to see one of my favorite bands of all time: Papa Roach. The day started at 11:45 am when I had to meet Katharina and Thomas at the train station. Our train left Oldenburg at 11:33 and arrived in Hamburg at 1:09 pm. We didn’t have our tickets yet, and we couldn’t go to the club to pick them up until 8:00 pm, so we had about 7 hours to walk the city like zombies. So that’s what we did! While walking, we stopped in many stores, including a cool second-hand clothing store where I found an LSUMC (my dad’s work) security uniform shirt! I didn’t buy it though because it was too small. But that was...</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.judsonlmoore.com/meeting-papa-roach</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.judsonlmoore.com/meeting-papa-roach</guid>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
        <category>rye</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
