<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Judson L Moore</title>
    <description>Author and travel addict</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 18:57:04 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2019 18:57:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tips for how to successfully find work abroad as an American</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The whole reason I started this blog&lt;/strong&gt; was as a way to publicly answer the question I have been asked for many years, “Judson, &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; do you get to travel so much?” The answer to that is varied and complex if you want it to be. On one side, it is as simple as saying that I just packed my bag and went for it, but of course, there is a large degree of planning that goes into making the plans which lead to a successful experience abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t regret any of my moves abroad, but not all of them have worked out as hoped. For many years, Europe seemed to be a black box as an American trying to work there. I tried many things and even made a failed attempt to move to England in 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving abroad as a student is relatively easy. Perhaps even getting an internship or very entry-level job under the right conditions could be managed without too much difficulty. But what about those of us who have long-sense graduated and are not willing to take a massive pay cut as an intern? It is said that beggars can’t be choosers, and I will confess that some sacrifice might be necessary, but with a good strategy and a lot of motivation, &lt;strong&gt;I believe that anyone can find a way to make a successful move abroad&lt;/strong&gt; and land a satisfying and rewarding job in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended reading: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/showing-up-secret-to-success/&quot;&gt;The Secret to all my Success&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am thrilled to now say that I have lived and worked for more than two years in Germany and have been having a great time while I am at it. A lot of people have started to now ask “Judson, what tips do you have for now to find work in Germany as an immigrant?” So I thought it was about time that I write down my observations and thoughts about how you too can make a successful move to Europe. Moreover, I think that this advice is relevant regardless of where you are from and to what country you would like to move to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While reading this, keep in mind that there are many avenues which can lead to a successful move abroad. Maybe you have a heritage claim, are very skilled in your discipline, you’re married to a person from that country, so on and so forth. The following insights are limited to my recent observations but I think you will see the logic behind my claims. If you spot a flaw in my thinking or would like to offer additional ideas, &lt;strong&gt;please leave a comment below&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; The opportunity that brought me to Germany was in-part thanks to a friend giving me an inside recommendation at trivago. That friend was a classmate back in my 2000-01 Rotary Youth Exchange year in Oldenburg, Germany, and so yes, my successful move to Germany is yet another “who you know” situation. That said, what I offer below is more generic tips and insights which I believe will be useful to anyone looking for a job abroad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Another disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;: As I mention my employer several times in this post, I would like to point out that my statements do not necessarily reflect the views of trivago, nor are they necessarily endorsed by trivago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;your-greatest-asset-native-language-and-market-knowledge&quot;&gt;Your greatest asset: Native Language and Market Knowledge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are smart and talented people with relevant job experience all over the world. So why would a company hire you and take on the headache of immigration visa sponsorship when they could just hire someone down the street? After all, the root of many immigration laws is designed to protect citizens’ ability to work and to have preference over anyone else. A company with a job opening has to prove first that &lt;em&gt;no available&lt;/em&gt; applicant in the country can do the job to which you are applying, &lt;em&gt;and therefore&lt;/em&gt; they are considering a foreign applicant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping that in mind, there are &lt;strong&gt;three reasons why a company might be allowed to hire an immigrant&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You work in a field which is in &lt;strong&gt;high demand&lt;/strong&gt; and there is a shortage of qualified local applicants (many STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) jobs are in this category);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) You are truly an &lt;strong&gt;expert in your field&lt;/strong&gt; and bring a level of thought leadership in the industry to the company which can not be found in the country (maybe you wrote a book or gave a TED Talk with millions of views on the topic of the role to which you are applying);&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You have &lt;strong&gt;native-level fluency in your native language&lt;/strong&gt; and, as a native of your country, &lt;strong&gt;you understand the culture&lt;/strong&gt;, business, and people to a degree which a non-native person simply can not.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may very well qualify under point 1 or 2 of this list, but that will apply to a smaller number of people. If 1 and 2 apply to you, then you probably also don’t need to be reading this article (not that it hurts!) because you already have a fast and direct path into your dream job abroad. Point 3 was how I made my current move to Germany, thusly, I argue that &lt;strong&gt;your greatest asset is native language and market knowledge&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-companies-desire-your-skills&quot;&gt;What companies desire your skills?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the key part. Actually, this insight, which I only recently became conscious of, is probably the single most important part of finding a job abroad, and it is very simple. You should be looking for &lt;strong&gt;companies which meet these two criteria:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Are based in the country where you want to move; and&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do business in the country where you are native.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s that simple! But let me explain the logic here. Let’s say you are American and you want to work in Germany (trying to be consistent with my examples here…). American companies with offices in Germany (think: Facebook, Google, Amazon, IBM, Nike, Ford) built those offices because they needed local market knowledge in Germany. &lt;strong&gt;They already have plenty of American-based resources.&lt;/strong&gt; So working for one of these companies in Germany might be quite difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now consider the large German-based companies which do business in America (think: trivago, Bayer, BMW, Adidas, Puma) they are headquartered in Germany and they seek experts in the markets where they operate. Sure, many of those companies will have offices around the world to service this need, but HQ also needs some people to be present and to offer insight about the various markets around the world in which they operate. &lt;strong&gt;This is where you come in.&lt;/strong&gt; Look for these companies, check out their open roles, and see what might be a good fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/jobs/search/?f_JT=F&amp;amp;f_TP=1%2C2%2C3%2C4&amp;amp;keywords=english&amp;amp;location=Germany&amp;amp;locationId=de%3A0&quot;&gt;do a job search on LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt; for the keyword “English” and then add filters for “location = Germany” and “job type = full-time.” The results will be available jobs that require English in Germany! Note that some of them will say, “requires excellent English &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; German,” but a lot will just mention English. This is your target list of companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-kind-of-roles-should-you-go-for&quot;&gt;What kind of roles should you go for?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may or may not find that the career path you are currently on or would like to be on, falls inside of the permitters of what you are likely to get a visa for. Just the same, there are ways to leverage your experience, whatever it is, to land you a &lt;em&gt;first&lt;/em&gt; job abroad. Since we are talking about companies with international reach, they are going to have a number of departments which require the market knowledge and language skills which &lt;strong&gt;only a native can deliver on&lt;/strong&gt;. Here are a few examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sales&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Marketing&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Media Buying&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Content Marketing&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Business Development&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;UX and other Copywriting&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SOX Compliance (for publicly traded companies)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Legal and paralegal work, including proofreading of legal documents&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If none of that sounds like a longterm passion for you, ask yourself, “would an international experience in one of these fields serve me well later in my career for what I really want to do?” If so, then why not give it a try? Not only might you find your way into that coveted visa, but you also will gain valuable experience while getting your foot in the door. &lt;strong&gt;This is just the beginning.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended Reading: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/high-tech-resume-tips/&quot;&gt;High-tech Tips for any Resume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-i-dont-want-to-be-in-sales-or-marketing&quot;&gt;But I don’t want to be in Sales or Marketing!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me either! But the fact is, &lt;strong&gt;getting a visa is really hard&lt;/strong&gt;. Once you have a visa, are in the country, are at the company, then life gets a lot easier. In a lot of circumstances, you can change roles internally at the company (which is what I did at trivago). My first job was as a North American spokesperson for trivago’s B2B products. I had native English and despite having no industry knowledge, I had market expertise because I know how to speak with and present to Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After one year, I shifted into the role I &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; wanted, software product management, a role which I would have never gotten a visa for, but NOW (and only now) there was an additional argument to say to the visa authorities which was, “Judson understands the American user, hotelier, and has an intimate knowledge of how our business operates, thus making him an ideal product manager which we could not find in another applicant.” See how that worked? It is &lt;strong&gt;the ole’ bait and switch!&lt;/strong&gt; But seriously, it was a good strategy for my long-term goals and yes, I learned a lot and had a lot of fun in that one year as a spokesperson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-additional-suggestions&quot;&gt;Some additional suggestions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who you know&lt;/strong&gt; can still play a big role here. Reach out to your network and figure out who works for a company based abroad, knows someone who does, or who might get you an introduction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set up informational interviews&lt;/strong&gt; just to ask the question, “&lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt; I were to apply to a role in your country or at your company, what skills, experience, and knowledge, would you find most attractive?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google phrases similar to&lt;/strong&gt; “English speaking jobs in &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;” and “English speaking companies in &lt;strong&gt;__&lt;/strong&gt;” to find articles which cover this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join networks such as&lt;/strong&gt; InterNations, CouchSurfing, LinkedIn Premium, XING (German LinkedIn), Rotary, and anything else with a focus on international networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If moving to Germany is your goal&lt;/strong&gt; then sites like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.howtogermany.com/&quot;&gt;HowToGermany.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://lifeinduesseldorf.com/&quot;&gt;LifeInDuesseldorf.com&lt;/a&gt; are really great resources. I am pretty sure every country and major city has similar sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Facebook Groups&lt;/strong&gt; exist for every topic you can imagine. Look around for ones with titles like “Expats in Germany,” or “Expats in Duesseldorf,” and even “English speakers of &lt;strong&gt;_&lt;/strong&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-it-go&quot;&gt;How did it go?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go give this a try, look around LinkedIn, and let me know what you discover and how it went &lt;strong&gt;by leaving a comment below&lt;/strong&gt;. Do you have other advice to offer? Please share that here as well, and good luck, you can do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;table class=&quot;rouge-table&quot;&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-gutter gl&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class=&quot;rouge-code&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 21:07:05 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/working-abroad-tips/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/working-abroad-tips/</guid>
        
        <category>germany,</category>
        
        <category>inspiration,</category>
        
        <category>interview,</category>
        
        <category>whileyoung,</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
        <category>words</category>
        
        
        <category>lifestyle</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Lost City of Petra is More Amazing Than I Ever Imagined</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The lost city of Petra, of Indiana Jones fame, sits in the southern territories of Jordan, between Amman and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/wadi-rum-jordan-destination-guide/&quot;&gt;Wadi Rum&lt;/a&gt;. This UNESCO World Heritage Site has been on my bucket list for a long time and I am glad to report that it does not disappoint. All I really knew about Petra was The Treasury building, which is famous for being the resting place of the Holy Grail in the 1989 film &lt;em&gt;Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade&lt;/em&gt;. I was thrilled to descend the long and winding &lt;em&gt;Siq&lt;/em&gt;, or path, into Petra, where The Treasury is not the first thing you see along the path, and as it turns out, it is not nearly the last thing either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;petra-in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;Petra In a Nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights -&lt;/strong&gt; Unbelievable mysteries to explore, open-range hiking and exploration, more sites than you could find in a week of trying, high-speed and open WiFi almost everywhere, clean and modern bathrooms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowlights&lt;/strong&gt; - Not very accessible if you have limited mobility.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom Line&lt;/strong&gt; - No trip to Israel or Jordan is complete without a day in Petra. Hands down, this is a top-5 site in the world.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-get-to-petra&quot;&gt;How to get to Petra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined a tour group out of Tel-Aviv to make this journey into Jordan. Along with visiting Wadi Rum and Jerash, we also got a day in Petra. The tour was operated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://abrahamtours.com/tours/petra-and-wadi-rum-tour-tlv/&quot;&gt;Abraham Tours&lt;/a&gt; and cost about $500USD inclusive of transportation, food, and accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip:&lt;/strong&gt; if you book a night at the Abraham hostel, you get 10% off any tour they offer. In this case, a $20 room saved me $50. Nice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The drive to Petra is its own experience. The roads are very new and well-maintained, so no fear there! Along the way, you get treated to incredible views of the desert vistas and a sneak-peak into the lifestyles of modern-day Bedouin tribes. Upon arrival at the entrance to Petra, there are a few hotels and ample parking, so if you were to come here on your own, there are some really nice places to stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The welcome center to Petra is much more than a gift shop and a ticket booth. There are a series of cafes and restaurants, a museum, an official hotel, and also a bar claiming to be the world’s oldest because it is inside of a cave which has been actively used for trade and rest for thousands of years. Just the same, it is a really awesome place to relax at the end of the day. But let’s leave that for later. Time to descend the &lt;em&gt;Siq&lt;/em&gt; and discover Petra!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-one-day-ticket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A 1-day ticket to Petra, taken at the entrance of the Siiq&quot; title=&quot;A 1-day ticket to Petra.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A 1-day ticket to Petra.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-siq-into-petra&quot;&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Siq&lt;/em&gt; into Petra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sloping path into Petra is called the &lt;em&gt;Siq&lt;/em&gt;. It is a gently-sloping dirt and stone path on the main Petra trail which is 8km long. Along the way, there are various tombs and petroglyphs to admire before the path is taken over by towering walls formed by a massive earthquake eons ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of structures which you will discover in Petra are tombs and are the only remaining symbols of the Nabataean Kingdom which ruled the area from 400BC until the Roman’s conquered them in the 1st Century AD. Not much is known about the Nabataean people except for what has been found in trade Greek and Roman trade records from the era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-obelisk-tomb-and-the-triclinium.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Obelisk Tomb and the Triclinium along the Siiq to Petra&quot; title=&quot;Obelisk Tomb and the Triclinium along the Siq to Petra&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Obelisk Tomb and the Triclinium along the Siq to Petra&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tombs of Petra do not have names or years indicated on them, however, some of the architecture in Petra offers clues about the period in which they were built. One of the first structures you come to along the Siq is called the Obelisk Tomb. It is called this because it features obelisks, which is very uncommon in Petra. Probably this tomb was built for a wealthy Egyptian merchant or someone who had a strong connection with Egypt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to note about these structures is that they are not built. Rather, they are &lt;em&gt;carved&lt;/em&gt;. What you see here in all these photos are structures carved into the side of mountains. Occasionally, where the curvature of the rock-face wasn’t large enough to accommodate the builder’s vision, some stone might be added on top, but for the most part, these structures have all been carved out of the side of the mountains with great precision and little error. Impressive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the Obelisk Tomb and a few others, the rock walls start to climb up on either side and the Petra experience turns into something truly unique. The predominant material in Petra is sandstone. The sandstone is iron-rich, giving it a brilliant rose color (similarly to why &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/wadi-rum-jordan-destination-guide/&quot;&gt;the sand in Wadi Rum is red&lt;/a&gt;). Millenia of water flow has carved the walls and floor of the Siq smooth, adding to the alien-like environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip: &lt;/strong&gt;check the weather for any rain before you go. Petra is known to flash-flood and it is very dangerous to be in the Siq when it is raining anywhere in the region. The local police and guides take every precaution to give advance warnings and to evacuate visitors. I arrived on a dry day, but our guide showed a video from 1-week before when the whole place was full of rapids!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One really interesting thing to note in the Siq (as pictured below) is the waist-high channels carved into the sides of the walls. These are actually aqueducts which carried fresh water to the buildings below! In a few places you can still see the clay pipes which were set into these carvings, but in most places, it is just an open trough today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-the-siiq-path.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I take a selfie halfway down the Siiq on the way to The Treasury at Petra&quot; title=&quot;Halfway down the Siq on the way to The Treasury at Petra&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Halfway down the Siq on the way to The Treasury at Petra&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-treasury-at-petra&quot;&gt;The Treasury at Petra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you approach the bottom of the Siq, a view of The Treasury starts to thinly reveal itself before suddenly the whole thing comes in to view and you find yourself in a deep cavern surrounded by magnificent walls on all sides and The Treasury looming over you. It is a site to behold and it is no wonder that The Treasury was voted as one of the New7Wonders of the World in 2007!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is the building that India Jones made famous as being the resting place of the Holy Grail. Great movie, and a perfect location for that scene, but certainly not what this building ever did. Inside, rather than a labyrinth of obstacles which can only be passed by the devout and the hyper-intelligent (Indi..), there is a single large chamber with no markings, carvings, or anything else which would suggest much of anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to years of vandalization and graffiti, the inside of The Treasury is not accessible to visitors, but that’s ok, the outside is where the show is. Of all the structures in Petra, The Treasury is the most well-preserved due to the closeness of the surrounding cliffs. The Treasury only receives a maximum of 4-hours of daylight per day and is protected from wind, rain, and other elements which could cause it harm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip:&lt;/strong&gt; The photo below is taken upon a ledge high above the place where the Siq ends in front of the Treasury. There are two ways to get there: the 3.5km (2.2 miles) Al-Khubtha trail (AKA green trail), which takes about 3 hours or pay one of the local kids at The Treasury to take you up a secret (and guarded) path which takes about 5 minutes. Trust me, you don’t want to do this by yourself and the $5 will help a local family. The best part: you get an awesome photo like this, and now you freed up 3 hours of your day to explore other trails instead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-al-khazneh-treasury-above.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson stands on a ledge above The Treasury at Petra.&quot; title=&quot;The Treasury at Petra.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The Treasury at Petra.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-around-inside-petra&quot;&gt;Getting around inside Petra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to eons of water flow and millions of visitors, the paths around Petra are pretty smooth and free of obstacles, so I argue that the best method of transportation is your own two feet. Keeping that in mind, Petra is 264 sq km (102 sq miles) and the whole site is on a slope, not to mention that each of the impressive sites resides atop of a different hill. So if by the end of the day you find yourself a bit exhausted, I wouldn’t judge you for hopping on a camel or donkey back to the visitor’s entrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional Reading: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/wadi-rum-jordan-destination-guide/&quot;&gt;Mars on Earth: The Wadi Rum Desert in Jordan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several camel stations around Petra, so you can hop on one from and to just about anywhere. If you were to take one at all, I recommend that you wait until the end of the day and take one from next to the Treasury back up to the visitor’s entrance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-camels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Camels and donkeys relaxing at The Treasury in Petra&quot; title=&quot;Camels and donkeys await tourists to give rides to.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Camels and donkeys await tourists to give rides to.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-monastery-at-petra&quot;&gt;The Monastery at Petra&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I most enjoyed about Petra is that &lt;em&gt;it is so much more&lt;/em&gt; than The Treasury. I had no idea that Petra was a whole ancient city and not just that one building. There are many tombs and other buildings carved into the sandstone at Petra, The Treasury is just the most well-preserved. The Monastery is the biggest monument and was built around 100BC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This magnificent structure appears to be built rather than carved, but actually, it is a mix. You can see the rock wall to the right is part of the original hillside from which The Monastery is indeed carved. But you can also see a sloping seam-line on the column left of center which slopes in the direction of the original hillside, thus indicating that the top of the Monastery was indeed built, at least in part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-ad-deir-monastery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Monastery at Petra with a Jordanian flag&quot; title=&quot;The Monastery at Petra&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The Monastery at Petra&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-high-place-of-sacrifice-and-trail&quot;&gt;The High Place of Sacrifice and Trail&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The name “Petra” comes from the Greek word “petros” which means “stone, rock.” Greek merchants observed the city’s inhabitants offering sacrifice to their deity on a large stone, and thus the city became known as Petra. Considering this, a stroll to the High Place of Sacrifice is highly recommended. The trail has two entrance points: one next to the Amphitheater behind The Treasury, and one closer to the trailhead which goes up to the Monastery. I recommend seeing the Monastery first and then take the trail to the High Place of Sacrifice because then you’ll be pointed in the right direction to head out to the visitor’s entrance. Many people only do the short in/out part of the trail from the Amphitheater, but that is a mistake! The longer part of the trail is much easier going up and there are incredible sites along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the trail being very beautiful and mostly void of other visitors, there are a number of other tombs along the way which you can enter and fully explore. When you do arrive at the High Place of Sacrifice, you will be confronted with the best panoramic view of Petra, which you can enjoy over a cup of Bedouin tea, prepared fresh for you in a small tent with comfortable seating right on the edge of the cliff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link href=&quot;/assets/css/gallery-fluid.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;tz-gallery&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-high-place-of-sacrifice-trail.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-high-place-of-sacrifice-trail.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bushes with pink flowers in a desert landscape along the route of the High Place of Sacrifice Trail in Petra&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Along the route of the High Place of Sacrifice Trail, A.K.A. &quot;the yellow trail.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-petra-jordan-high-place-of-sacrifice-trail-rock-formations.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-petra-jordan-high-place-of-sacrifice-trail-rock-formations.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stacked stones on the route of the High Place of Sacrifice Trail in Petra&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Stacked stones on the route of the High Place of Sacrifice Trail&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-tomb-of-a-roman-soldier.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-tomb-of-a-roman-soldier.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Facade of The Roman Soldier's Tomb on the High Place of Sacrifice Trail in Petra&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;The Roman Soldier's Tomb on the High Place of Sacrifice Trail&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/baguettebox.js/1.8.1/baguetteBox.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    baguetteBox.run('.tz-gallery');
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/petra-jordan-royal-tombs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A selfie with The Royal Tombs of Petra, taken from atop the High Place of Sacrifice&quot; title=&quot;The Royal Tombs of Petra, taken from atop the High Place of Sacrifice&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The Royal Tombs of Petra, taken from atop the High Place of Sacrifice&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-are-you-going-to-petra&quot;&gt;When are you going to Petra?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tag! You’re it! I hope that I have encouraged you to make a trip to Petra in your near-future. I can’t recommend it enough! Have you been before? Do you have questions I can answer for you? Do you have additional information which should be shared with readers? &lt;strong&gt;Please leave a comment below&lt;/strong&gt; and let me know your thoughts. Safe travels!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 11:00:54 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/petra-jordan-destination-guide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/petra-jordan-destination-guide/</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>guide</category>
        
        
        <category>jordan</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mars on Earth - The Wadi Rum Desert in Jordan</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;wadi-rums-hollywood-fame-and-tourism&quot;&gt;Wadi Rum’s Hollywood Fame and Tourism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wadi Rum is an iron-rich desert in the south of Jordan which is famous for its &lt;strong&gt;Mars-like landscapes&lt;/strong&gt;. The iron and mineral content of the sand here gives the desert a red coloring which is unlike anything you can see elsewhere on the planet. Because of this, Wadi Rum has become a popular destination for Hollywood to film. Films such as Lawrence of Arabia, which kickstarted the tourism industry in this area of Jordan, and more recently, The Martian, have brought fame and tourism to the desert for decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to Wadi Rum is actually a lot easier than you might suspect. If you are already in the area, visiting other parts of Jordan, or Israel, &lt;strong&gt;don’t miss the opportunity to visit this fascinating place&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wadi-rum-in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;Wadi Rum In a Nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights -&lt;/strong&gt; Breathtaking views unlike anything else you can see. Even though it is a desert, there are some historical markers and interesting stories to walk in the footsteps of. Great hospitality from the locals.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowlights&lt;/strong&gt; - Without a jeep, camel, or guide, I couldn’t imagine spending more than a day here.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottomline&lt;/strong&gt; - Though some consider Wadi Rum to be the best Middle Eastern destination for hikers, climbers, campers, and nature lovers, I wouldn’t recommend spending more than 24-hours in Wadi Rum. But don’t dare come within 100km and not come here for at least half a day. It is amazing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;human-history-in-the-desert&quot;&gt;Human History in the Desert&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tens of thousands of petroglyphs and inscriptions have been found on the rocks of Wadi Rum, which date roughly &lt;strong&gt;12,000 years of human presence in the area&lt;/strong&gt;. The Bedouin people and culture have the longest steady claim in the area, but the origins of human civilization and migration are rooted in Wadi Rum and the surrounding areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the &lt;strong&gt;nearby site of the City of Petra&lt;/strong&gt;, which was the capital of the mysterious Nabataeans, only dates back a fraction as long as that of early humans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But enough with the human history: &lt;strong&gt;what can people do here today?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, people still live here and carry on a desert and nomadic culture. Though trade was once the core of the local economy, like that of the Silk Road, Wadi Rum now flourishes on tourism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/wadi-rum-jordan-jeep-tour-group.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My new friends from the Wadi Rum tour, including Tiffany Tchouboukjian (opposite from me), pilled up in the back of a truck for our desert jeep tour&quot; title=&quot;My new friends from the Wadi Rum tour, including Tiffany Tchouboukjian (opposite from me), pilled up in the back of a truck for our desert jeep tour&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My new friends from the Wadi Rum tour, including Tiffany Tchouboukjian (opposite from me), pilled up in the back of a truck for our desert jeep tour&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tours-of-wadi-rum&quot;&gt;Tours of Wadi Rum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I booked a multi-day group tour from &lt;a href=&quot;https://abrahamtours.com/&quot;&gt;Abraham Tours&lt;/a&gt; in Israel, so I didn’t have to organize anything on my own. To be honest, you could come here on your own that that would be just fine, but I found the service of a tour company and guide to be well worth the relatively low cost just so that I wouldn’t have to worry about the border crossings or transportation and lodging logistics. &lt;strong&gt;Abraham Tours did a great job and I recommend them&lt;/strong&gt; to you, but you can also do a Google search to see if you find something better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Abraham Tours is owned by Abraham Hostels, which has locations in Tel-Aviv and Jerusalem. If you book a room at the hostel, you get a 10% discount on any tour. In this case, a $20 room saved me $50 on the tour. So it was like getting $30 cash-back and a free room for a night!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour included stops in Jerash, Amman, Petra, and lastly (but most certainly not lastly), Wadi Rum. The tour group included 30 people from all walks of life, but &lt;strong&gt;everyone was pretty much awesome&lt;/strong&gt;. By the time we arrived at Wadi Rum, we were all buddies for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Wadi Rum tour consisted of three parts: jeep tour, camel tour (optional), lunch. Jeep is the best way to get around the desert, I believe. &lt;strong&gt;We only ever got stuck in the sand once!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/wadi-rum-jordan-jeep-tour-parked.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson poses with Wadi Rum tour jeeps in the Lawrence Memorial Bedouin Camp&quot; title=&quot; The jeeps line up at the Lawrence Memorial Bedouin Camp.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The jeeps line up at the Lawrence Memorial Bedouin Camp.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;camels-of-wadi-rum&quot;&gt;Camels of Wadi Rum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who have read my articles for some time now, you might have noticed &lt;strong&gt;I sometimes obsess on camels a bit&lt;/strong&gt;. I don’t know where this comes from. I think they just photograph nicely and are somehow exotic animals in exotic landscapes. But just the same, when I see a camel, I jump at the opportunity to learn about them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Wadi Rum, you will see &lt;strong&gt;two types of camels&lt;/strong&gt; when you visit: those which are saddled and prepped for safari and those which are just walking free. However, none of these camels are wild. They are all domesticated and all belong to someone. Camels are left to free-range grazing and wandering off to their favorite watering hole because they pretty much always return home to their owner. They are quite loyal like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Camels do go missing&lt;/strong&gt; from time to time, but according to the guides I spoke with, they didn’t seem too worried about it because the camels always turn up somewhere soon enough. It is sort of like what we say in the USA, “it all comes out in the laundry,” meaning that whatever balance needs to be found, it will be eventually. So no stress!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is something new I learned: when you see camels freely walking in a straight line, it means they intend to walk a really long distance! &lt;strong&gt;I wonder if that has to do with aerodynamics?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/wadi-rum-jordan-camels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Camels laying on the red sand of Wadi Rum in Jordan&quot; title=&quot; Camels of the Wadi Rum Desert in Jordan&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Camels of the Wadi Rum Desert in Jordan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;desert-camel-safari&quot;&gt;Desert Camel Safari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite my weird love for camels, when offered the optional opportunity to take a camel safari in Wadi Rum: I declined. It was going to be an extra $20 and I already had enough &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/pushkar/&quot;&gt;desert camel safari when I was in Pushkar, India&lt;/a&gt;. But if you have never ridden a camel: do it here! The camels were &lt;strong&gt;more well-behaved than the ones in India&lt;/strong&gt;, and though both the Rajasthan and Wadi Rum deserts are majestic, this one is pretty unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This camel safari only lasted 20-30 minutes and ended at the Lawrence Memorial Bedouin Camp where I was already waiting for everyone, as I came in a jeep. This also meant &lt;strong&gt;I had more time for drinking&lt;/strong&gt; the incredible (and incredibly sweet) Bedouin tea!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/wadi-rum-jordan-camel-ride.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A tour group takes a camel safari in the Wadi Rum Desert in southern Jordan&quot; title=&quot; The camel safari of the Wadi Rum Desert&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The camel safari of the Wadi Rum Desert&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;petroglyphs-and-inscriptions&quot;&gt;Petroglyphs and Inscriptions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, so I mentioned the 12,000-year-old origins of humans in the area. Wadi Rum is scattered with &lt;strong&gt;more than 40,000 known petroglyphs and inscriptions&lt;/strong&gt; on the rocks. The point of our tour where the camel safari began is one such point of interest where these markings are clearly visible. Luckily, the markings are very much out of reach without a ladder, which is probably one of the reasons they have lasted for so long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/wadi-rum-jordan-nomads-petroglyphs-inscriptions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson points out the 12,000 year-old Petroglyphs and inscriptions in Wadi Rum.&quot; title=&quot; Petroglyphs and inscriptions in Wadi Rum date as far back as 10,000 B.C.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Petroglyphs and inscriptions in Wadi Rum date as far back as 10,000 B.C.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-filter-needed&quot;&gt;No Filter Needed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am occasionally guilty of applying some filter or editing touches to photos. But I wanted to highlight that the next landscape photo is totally untouched. &lt;strong&gt;This is just how the place looks.&lt;/strong&gt; And this was taken with an iPhone, not a professional camera, which means the color depth of the photo is not nearly as rich as the real-life view of Wadi Rum. This place is just truly spectacular, and at every turn, you better be prepared to lose your breath!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/05/wadi-rum-jordan-daytime-landscape.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Seven Pillars of Wisdom rock formation in Wadi Rum, Jordan&quot; title=&quot; The Seven Pillars of Wisdom rock formation in Wadi Rum, Jordan&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Seven Pillars of Wisdom rock formation in Wadi Rum, Jordan&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this article! Have you been to Wadi Rum before? What did I miss? What questions do you have? &lt;strong&gt;Please contribute your thoughts below in the comments.&lt;/strong&gt; Safe travels!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 12:00:17 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/wadi-rum-jordan-destination-guide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/wadi-rum-jordan-destination-guide/</guid>
        
        <category>camel,</category>
        
        <category>desert,</category>
        
        <category>safari,</category>
        
        <category>tours,</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>guide</category>
        
        
        <category>jordan</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DRUMSON performs live at the trivagoVibe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I love working at trivago!&lt;/strong&gt; The company embodies many of my core passions: technology and innovation, travel, multiculturalism, and on occasion, music! The trivagoVibe is a bi-annual concert of trivago’s musically-talented employees and is the activity where I have the most fun at work (and yes, that includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/trivago-tour-2017/&quot;&gt;the famed trivago on Tour annual trip&lt;/a&gt;. Nothing beats live music in my book!) And at trivago, live music means &lt;strong&gt;trivagoVibe!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;trivago recently moved into &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/LQikZZIia2k&quot;&gt;a new spaceship-like campus&lt;/a&gt; in Düsseldorf, which is an incredible facility in every way, including lots of open-air spaces which are perfect for music. During the past trivagoVibes, I didn’t have the opportunity to perform and so this time I was as proactive as possible to make sure that I would be included in the lineup. &lt;strong&gt;I couldn’t be more satisfied with the outcomes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lineup of musicians was incredibly impressive. With a range of genres from singer-songwriter, blues, country, rock, and dance music, &lt;strong&gt;there was something for everyone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-e-drums-changed-everything&quot;&gt;How e-Drums Changed Everything&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years back while I was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/india/&quot;&gt;traveling across India&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;I had an identity crisis&lt;/strong&gt;. I came to understand that if I wanted to continue saying, “I am a drummer,” instead of, “I &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; a drummer,” then I better start drumming more regularly. My nomadic and apartment-dwelling lifestyle was not conducive to such loud and bulky habits. One night, while laying in bed, I was watching drumming YouTube videos when I came across a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JqReO5NPN_g&quot;&gt;Drumeo video featuring Michael Schack&lt;/a&gt;, Roland’s endorsed artist for their flagship e-drums. I was hooked, and 10-minutes later, I was typing my credit card into eBay where I found a great deal on a Roland TD-30KV drum set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past years, I have enjoyed coming home to my 1-bedroom apartment and jamming under the headphones late into the night without disturbing my neighbors. I even did a few studio recordings with the drums (they sound even better than ‘real’ drums on recordings) &lt;strong&gt;but never dared to dream of using them for a live performance&lt;/strong&gt;; I am too much of an acoustic-purist to play e-drums live!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But here I am in Germany, no gigs played in the two years since I moved here, no bands to play with, and yet there is an opportunity at work where I could perform. But perform with who?? Sure, I talked to some other musicians, but I think they shared my view on acoustic drums being the only proper drums for a band. And so I was left without buddies to jam with. One day I decided, “Judson, you can do this alone. After all, Michael Schack can do it, so why can’t you?” &lt;strong&gt;And so that is what I set out to do: a one-man band drumming extravaganza.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now things are about to get interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;soundcheck-is-for-sharing&quot;&gt;Soundcheck is for Sharing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the week of the show, I show up to my spaceship-esque office with my spaceship-esque drums, and not even I really know what to make of it. I have never hooked this Roland kit up to external speakers before, and though I have no doubts of its capabilities, I also wasn’t sure what sort of &lt;strong&gt;unforeseeable technical difficulties&lt;/strong&gt; I could run in to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the time for soundcheck came, another drummer got to the stage first with her acoustic drums, so we got those setup. But that is when things got interesting. The acoustics of the venue were really terrible. There was an echo that went on for minutes. We had a big fear of how to control the sound of live drums. After a brief attempt at a soundcheck, &lt;strong&gt;it already seemed like a bad idea&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then came the question:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Them:&lt;/strong&gt; Judson, can we use your drums for all the bands tonight?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; hmmmmmm… well, yes, of course, but are you sure that is a good idea?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Them:&lt;/strong&gt; Well let’s just give it a try&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me:&lt;/strong&gt; Ok!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so we set up the Roland drums for soundcheck. When all was set, I got behind the drums, and with one beat into the kick drum &amp;gt;BOOM&amp;lt; we all knew we struck gold. &lt;strong&gt;This. Drumset. Sounds. AMAZING. Live!&lt;/strong&gt; Thusly, the rest of the night had amazing sounding rhythm which was super easy to mix into the volume of everyone else on stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-001.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image full&quot; loading=&quot;auto&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; description=&quot; Janine (Avocadogate) sound checks on the Roland TD-30KV&quot; alt=&quot;Janine (Avocadogate) sound checks on the Roland TD-30KV&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;musical-talent-of-trivago-the-lineup&quot;&gt;Musical Talent of trivago: The Lineup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am just blown away at the level of musical talent that exists in this company.&lt;/strong&gt; Not to mention the courage it takes to play music in front of all your colleagues. The concert featured 8 acts: 6 bands, a DJ, and me. Here are some highlight photos from the evening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;link href=&quot;/assets/css/gallery-fluid.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;tz-gallery&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-013.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-013.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tintin performs at the trivagoVibe in Düsseldorf&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Tintin&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-002.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-002.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Champion du Monde performs at the trivagoVibe in Düsseldorf&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Champion du Monde&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-003.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-003.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Diana Bailey Band performs at the trivagoVibe in Düsseldorf&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Diana Bailey Band&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-004.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-004.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Avocadogate performs at the trivagoVibe in Düsseldorf&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Avocadogate&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-012.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-012.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Josito &amp;amp; the Kids performs at the trivagoVibe in Düsseldorf&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Josito &amp;amp; the Kids&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-005.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-005.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Carmencitas performs at the trivagoVibe in Düsseldorf&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Carmencitas&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-008.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-008.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drumson performs at the trivagoVibe in Düsseldorf&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Drumson&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-009.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &amp;lt;img
              src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-009.jpg&quot;
              alt=&quot;Hakan, AKA &quot;Minimus&quot; produced the trivagoVibe and closed out the night with an incredible DJ set.&quot;
            /&amp;gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Minimus&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/baguettebox.js/1.8.1/baguetteBox.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    baguetteBox.run('.tz-gallery');
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t get much video of the other bands, but be sure to check out this awesome video of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/Bmu6MBIFzS_/&quot;&gt;Josito &amp;amp; the Kids performing Daft Punk’s &lt;em&gt;Get Lucky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;These guys are amazing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-first-stage-performance-in-years&quot;&gt;My first stage performance in years&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, late in the evening, after everyone was good and loosened up, having just listened to hours of amazing live music, my moment of truth came. &lt;strong&gt;It was time for me to hit the stage&lt;/strong&gt; for the first time in Germany, and if I am being completely honest, this was my first true live performance since… I honestly can’t remember! (Seriously, I am sitting here trying to remember, and &lt;em&gt;I just don’t remember..&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drummers typically sit in the back of the stage, behind the rest of the band. That is not an excuse to lack showmanship, but now my drums were pushed to the front edge of the stage and I was up here all alone. It was time for me to shine or sink. The crowd was full of energy, and it was my responsibility to keep them entertained. &lt;em&gt;Did I rehearse enough? Did I program the right drum sounds? Does the backing track work? Will the video backdrop work? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These are all the questions which were in my head.&lt;/strong&gt; But I was focused. I was prepared. I rehearsed, and now it was time to see if I still have what it takes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I walked onto the stage, I slipped into character. For the next 32 minutes, I would be: &lt;strong&gt;DRUMSON&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Checkout the official website for Drumson at &lt;a href=&quot;https://drumson.de&quot;&gt;https://drumson.de&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-006.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image full&quot; loading=&quot;auto&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; alt=&quot;Drumson performs a solo show at the 2018 trivagoVibe!&quot; width=&quot;2048&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;watchvideo-footage-from-my-first-drumson-performance&quot;&gt;Watch Video Footage from my First DRUMSON Performance&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all the years that I have played drums, I have no videos from a live performance, and I hardly have any photos. I certainly have no quality photos. Therefore, I asked a few friends to take some videos of my performance. &lt;strong&gt;The results were really amazing!&lt;/strong&gt; Many people sent me videos and I was able to splice together this video recap of the show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please excuse the unstable audio level, I think the phones had a difficult time keeping up with how loud the show was!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/strong&gt; (and please leave me your feedback in the comments section of this post!) :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=U8XFiPi4TO4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-you-to-everyone-who-came-out-to-support-the-music&quot;&gt;Thank you to everyone who came out to support the music!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you&lt;/strong&gt; to all the other musicians, my friends, my colleagues, and especially to trivago for making this special night a reality, not just for me, but for everyone involved. The trivagoVibe happens twice a year and I hope that I will be able to perform at the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until then, please leave me your thoughts in the comments below, and you can always reach me directly on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/JudsonLMooreBlog/&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/judsonlmoore&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/08/trivagoVibe-Summer-2018-011.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image full&quot; loading=&quot;auto&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1440&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 22:35:07 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/trivagovibe-summer-2018/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/trivagovibe-summer-2018/</guid>
        
        
        <category>trivago</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Without a Path Podcast asked me to share travel advice in Kyrgyzstan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://withoutapath.com/&quot;&gt;The Without a Path Podcast&lt;/a&gt; with the American writer, traveler, and meddler Joe Baur is chock full of intriguing chats with creative types, adventurers, and the occasional story of hope for humanity. Guests share stories about the travels which has helped define their lives in this weekly travel podcast. &lt;strong&gt;I highly encourage you to subscribe to&lt;/strong&gt; the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/without-a-path/id1037475413?l=es&amp;amp;mt=2&quot;&gt;Without A Path Podcast on iTunes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My interview on the podcast&lt;/strong&gt; focuses on stories from Kyrgyzstan, how I got there, what I was doing there, and what has happened in the country since I left in 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To learn more about Joe Baur&lt;/strong&gt;, the Without a Path Podcast, or even to suggest yourself or someone else as a guest of the show, check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://withoutapath.com&quot;&gt;WithoutAPath.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please listen, share, and comment below with your thoughts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;166&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/395218398&amp;amp;auto_play=true&amp;amp;color=255b87&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources-i-mentioned-during-the-interview&quot;&gt;Resources I mentioned during the interview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked about a lot in this episode of the Without a Path Podcast. Here are some notes and links to things I discussed in my conversation with Joe Baur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rotary.org/en/our-programs/youth-exchanges&quot;&gt;Rotary Youth Exchange Program&lt;/a&gt; - I lived in Germany for 1 year when I was 17 years old with this free program which facilitates youth exchange between local Rotary Clubs all over the world. If you would like to be introduced to a Rotary Club near you, let me know and I will be happy to help you get in touch.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.peacecorps.gov/volunteer/is-peace-corps-right-for-me/&quot;&gt;United States Peace Corps&lt;/a&gt; - In its 50th year since being established by President John F. Kennedy, I had the honor of serving as a Peace Corps Volunteer in Kyrgyzstan, where I launched a journalism project which has touched hundreds of thousands of people since.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kyrgyzstan&quot;&gt;Where is Kyrgyzstan?&lt;/a&gt; - “The Switzerland of Central Asia” is a landlocked country on the northwestern side of China. Its remoteness is only surpassed by its beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kloop.kg/&quot;&gt;Kloop School of Journalism&lt;/a&gt; - This nontraditional school in Kyrgyzstan teaches Western-style journalism practices to youth. Their stories are published on one of Central Asia’s most-read news sites.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://kyrgyzmedia.com/&quot;&gt;Kyrgyz Media&lt;/a&gt; - This is the project that I launched while in the Peace Corps. Even if you don’t read Russian or Kyrgyz, just looking through the photos in the posts will tell you a lot about the Kyrgyz People.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.friendsofkyrgyzstan.com/cookbook/&quot;&gt;Friends of Kyrgyzstan Cookbook&lt;/a&gt; - This is a cookbook written by Peace Corps Volunteers in Kyrgyzstan. Many of the recipes are of traditional foods from the area and are easy to prepare.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://worldnomadgames.com/en/&quot;&gt;World Nomad Games&lt;/a&gt; - It is like the Olympics for nomadic cultures. Teams from all over the world compete in a series of games which have been played for thousands of years. The 2018 World Nomad Games will be hosted in Issyk-Kul Kyrgyzstan from September 2-8, 2018. I will be there for sure, will you?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-sheep-slaughter-video&quot;&gt;The Sheep-Slaughter Video&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the interview, I mentioned a sacrificial sheep slaughter which temporarily converted me into a vegetarian. Joe thought it wise to include some of the audio in the Podcast episode, &lt;strong&gt;which has stirred a lot of questions&lt;/strong&gt; about what the event looked like. Look no further, here is the full event for those of you whose curiosity is stronger than your stomachs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4f3QsvHVv20&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-favorite-without-a-path-podcast-episodes&quot;&gt;My favorite Without a Path Podcast Episodes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Without a Path Podcast has dozens of episodes to choose from, so I promise &lt;strong&gt;there is something of interest to everyone&lt;/strong&gt;. Here are a few of my very favorite episodes which you should also give a listen to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://withoutapath.com/expats-immigrants-live-abroad/&quot;&gt;Expats vs Immigrants and Why Americans Should Live Abroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://withoutapath.com/archaeologist-jens-notroff/&quot;&gt;Archaeologist Jens Notroff is Living in His Golden Age of Travel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://withoutapath.com/johnny-jet-podcast/&quot;&gt;Johnny Jet Turns a Fear of Flying into a Travel Career&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://withoutapath.com/trump-travel-ban-sher-she-goes-cuba/&quot;&gt;Trump’s Travel Ban and Sher She Goes to Cuba&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-did-you-like-my-interview-on-the-without-a-path-podcast&quot;&gt;How did you like my interview on the Without a Path Podcast?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that you enjoyed the episode! Please leave me a comment below to &lt;strong&gt;let me know your thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;, feedback, or to ask me followup questions. Alternatively, you can also reach out to me directly on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/judsonlmoore&quot;&gt;@JudsonLMoore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 17:41:33 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/without-a-path-podcast/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/without-a-path-podcast/</guid>
        
        <category>interview,</category>
        
        <category>podcast,</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>kyrgyzstan</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Edinburgh Castle Walking Tour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After having spent my morning taking &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/edinburgh-free-walking-tour/&quot;&gt;a free walking tour&lt;/a&gt;, I decided it was worth buying a ticket to one of the afternoon paid tours. The tour organizer, SANDEMANs, had several to chose from but I was most interested in getting to know the Edinburgh Castle. So after a quick lunch on my own, I rejoined my trusty (and awesome) guide, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neweuropetours.eu/Edinburgh/en/Guides/Details/Yb9onL/dave&quot;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;, and off we went together on &lt;strong&gt;the Edinburgh Castle walking tour&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This tour runs daily&lt;/strong&gt; in the afternoon. Check &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neweuropetours.eu/edinburgh/en/home?&amp;amp;Tour=8276&quot;&gt;the SANDEMANs website&lt;/a&gt; for schedules and ticket information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping things simple, our meeting point was at the same location as the free walking tour, on The Royal Mile. Our group was small, just 7 of us. After going through a quick round of introductions, we started our &lt;strong&gt;5-minute walk up the hill to the Edinburgh Castle&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional reading: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/edinburgh-free-walking-tour/&quot;&gt;Edinburgh FREE Walking Tour - All You Need to Know Before You Go&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;In A Nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights -&lt;/strong&gt; Enthusiastic and knowledgeable guides tell educational stories with flair and efficiency. The Edinburgh Castle is perhaps the most historically significant building in Scotland. The views from on top of the castle are incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowlights -&lt;/strong&gt; If you were to have bad weather, there is almost no protection from the elements. If you have seen the British Crown Jewels in London, don’t get too excited about the Scottish Crown Jewels in Edinburgh Castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line -&lt;/strong&gt; The Edinburgh Castle walking tour is a great way to see the castle and ensure that you don’t miss any detail of the architecture or significant history. On a day with good weather, this is a perfect post-lunch activity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;edinburgh-castle-walking-tour&quot;&gt;Edinburgh Castle Walking Tour&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.edinburghcastle.gov.uk&quot;&gt;The official website of the Edinburgh Castle&lt;/a&gt; offers a lot of great information about the castle’s history and the independent tours you can take on your own. &lt;strong&gt;I recommend&lt;/strong&gt; that you [download the official Edinburgh Castle Map” file=”../assets/images/2018/01/edinburgh-castle-orientation-map.pdf) now so that you can better orient yourself as you read this article and follow along on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour was nearly &lt;strong&gt;two hours from start to finish&lt;/strong&gt;. When the tour concludes, you are free to explore the castle on your own and see some of the special exhibits, such as Scotland’s Crown Jewels which are on display in the castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the winter months, like when I was there, the tour concludes just before sunset, which can make for &lt;strong&gt;a spectacular view&lt;/strong&gt;. Just plan accordingly because though the sunset is worth sticking around for, the temperature will drop very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-gatehouse-at-edinburgh-castle&quot;&gt;The Gatehouse at Edinburgh Castle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Edinburgh Castle was built as an impenetrable and menacing fortress with deterrence kept in mind as the main message which the architecture should portray to any who cast a gaze upon it. Standing atop of vertical cliffs on three sides, the castle looks unapproachable. Despite that, it has been through 26 sieges, which makes it &lt;strong&gt;one of the most besieged places in Britain&lt;/strong&gt; and among the most besieged places in the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new gatehouse is the first thing you see when you approach the Edinburgh Castle. You can see that the stone color and the architecture is rather different from the castle which lay behind. The reason for this was triggered by a visit of Queen Victoria who upon arrival was &lt;strong&gt;a bit disappointed at how unwelcoming the castle felt&lt;/strong&gt;. She desired that there be a more royal castle aesthetic and so this new gatehouse was built in 1888, along with one tower on the main building which, though a small detail, does go a long way to making the Edinburgh Castle feel a bit more like the royal castles of England, such as Windsor Castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/castle-walking-tour-edinburgh-new-gatehouse-coffee-truck.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A red coffee truck stands in front of The Gatehouse at Edinburgh Castle&quot; title=&quot; A coffee truck stands in front of the Gatehouse at Edinburgh Castle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; A coffee truck stands in front of the Gatehouse at Edinburgh Castle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;prisoners-of-war&quot;&gt;Prisoners of War&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; makes a castle? A dungeon! The Prisoners of War is a reenactment and multimedia experience in the Edinburgh Castle’s dungeon. Here, you get to explore the castle’s prison as it would have looked for centuries as the home to prisoners of war from all over the world. Alongside furnishings and personal items which were typical of prisoners who live here, there also audio clips playing throughout the room. As you listen, you get to learn about some of the lives and experiences of real prisoners, who were kept in the Edinburgh Castle dungeon. Prisoners came from all over the world, because of all sorts of conflicts, including &lt;strong&gt;the American Revolution&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/castle-walking-tour-edinburgh-military-prison.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of the sleeping conditions which prisoners of war held at Edinburgh Castle would have endured&quot; title=&quot; Prisoners of War Exhibit at Edinburgh Castle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Prisoners of War Exhibit at Edinburgh Castle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scotlands-crown-jewels&quot;&gt;Scotland’s Crown Jewels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the highest point of Edinburgh Castle&lt;/strong&gt; are the Scottish Crown Jewels, known as “The Honors of the Kingdom.” You are not allowed to take photos inside, so a quick Google search can show you what it is you can expect here. I will just let you know now that if you have seen the crown jewels in London, this exhibit is not to be compared. In a lot of ways, Scotland’s crown jewels are more significant because they have a longer history. But they are not as refined and glamorous as the crown jewels that you will find at the Tower of London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading up to seeing the crown jewels is an exhibit chronicling the history of the monarchy and other various royal families and dynasties of Scotland. &lt;strong&gt;The whole exhibit is done very well.&lt;/strong&gt; Unfortunately, I didn’t have very much time left to spend in the castle so I had to rush through all of that fairly quickly. You should give yourself at least 20 to 30 minutes to enjoy The Honors of the Kingdom exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/castle-walking-tour-edinburgh-crown-jewles-sign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of the sign leading to The Honours of The Kingdom Exhibit at Edinburgh Castle&quot; title=&quot; Sign leading to The Honours of The Kingdom Exhibit at Edinburgh Castle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Sign leading to The Honours of The Kingdom Exhibit at Edinburgh Castle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;mons-meg--510mm-caliber-cannon&quot;&gt;Mons Meg - 510mm Caliber Cannon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mons Meg is a 500-year-old siege cannon. Its 20-inch (510mm) barrel size makes it &lt;strong&gt;one of the largest-caliber cannons in the world&lt;/strong&gt;. Though only fired a few times, and usually for ceremonial reasons, the 175 kilograms (386 lb) stone cannon balls are proven to have a consistent range of around 2 miles (3 km).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time Mons Meg was fired with ammunition was in 1680 to celebrate the arrival of James, Duke of Albany and York, who would later become King James VII. On this occasion, &lt;strong&gt;the barrel burst open&lt;/strong&gt; and it has not been capable of munitions firing ever since. However, it is fired still today once a year on Hogmanay (new year) to mark the beginning of the fireworks display. Of course, now it just fires blanks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/castle-walking-tour-edinburgh-mons-meg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mons Meg pointed out to the harbor below Edinburgh Castle&quot; title=&quot; Mons Meg at Edinburgh Castle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Mons Meg at Edinburgh Castle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scottish-national-war-memorial&quot;&gt;Scottish National War Memorial&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another recent addition to the Edinburgh Castle is the Scottish National War Memorial. The memorial was opened in 1927 and &lt;strong&gt;pays tribute to all fallen soldiers of Scotland&lt;/strong&gt; in both World Wars and conflicts since. Presumably, it was first built with the intention of memorializing soldiers of the first World War only, since the second war had not yet been fought. After World War II, 50,000 Scottish names were added to the building’s roster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exterior of the memorial has been designed with the Edinburgh Castle aesthetic kept in mind. As this rests atop one of the highest points of the castle’s grounds, it is very visible from afar and so the architecture is intended to blend in. The interior, on the other hand, is almost art deco in style and feel much more like a modern memorial of sorts. &lt;strong&gt;The flags of Scottish regiments hang throughout.&lt;/strong&gt; Under each flag are thick books on display with the names of all those who have served in each regiment and who have died in service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/castle-walking-tour-edinburgh-scottish-national-war-memorial.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The outside of the Scottish National War Memorial&quot; title=&quot; Scottish National War Memorial at Edinburgh Castle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Scottish National War Memorial at Edinburgh Castle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;st-margarets-chapel&quot;&gt;St Margaret’s Chapel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The oldest building in all of Edinburgh&lt;/strong&gt;, St Margaret’s Chapel is a simple construction atop the Edinburgh Castle complex. The chapel was built in the 12th century and is thought to be a place of worship for St. Margaret herself. Though there is some debate about that due to the architecture giving hints of being built a bit later during the reign of her son, David I.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1314 the castle was captured by Robert the Bruce and all the buildings inside, except for the Chapel, were destroyed. Though the chapel did fall in to disuse after that, it would eventually be renovated and put back in to use in the 19th century. &lt;strong&gt;It has held services on a fairly regular basis ever since.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/castle-walking-tour-edinburgh-st-margarets-chapel-judson.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson taking a selfie in front of St Margaret's Chapel&quot; title=&quot; St Margaret's Chapel at Edinburgh Castle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; St Margaret’s Chapel at Edinburgh Castle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-day-well-spent-in-edinburgh&quot;&gt;A Day Well Spent in Edinburgh&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that concludes my day in Edinburgh! I started with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/edinburgh-free-walking-tour/&quot;&gt;a free walking tour&lt;/a&gt;, visited the Museum of Scotland, had haggis for lunch, and then spent the afternoon walking around Edinburgh Castle where I ended up catching the sunset. &lt;strong&gt;I recommend this schedule for anyone&lt;/strong&gt; who is visiting Edinburgh, either for your first day in town or if it is your only day in Edinburgh, as it was for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you been to Edinburgh? Have you visited the Edinburgh Castle? &lt;strong&gt;I would love to have your feedback and impressions of the castle.&lt;/strong&gt; Please feel free to leave a comment below or reach me directly on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/judsonlmoore&quot;&gt;@judsonlmoore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2018 12:00:30 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/edinburgh-castle-walking-tour/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/edinburgh-castle-walking-tour/</guid>
        
        <category>adventure,</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>guide,</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>tips,</category>
        
        <category>walking</category>
        
        <category>tour</category>
        
        
        <category>scotland</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Edinburgh Free Walking Tour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am believing more and more that &lt;strong&gt;the very best way to start any trip&lt;/strong&gt; is with a free walking tour. These tours are offered in many of the world’s top destinations and are a great way to quickly orient yourself to the highlights a city has to offer. Most walking tours do not go inside of the sites, churches, and castles, but rather offer stories and a local’s perspective on what makes the city unique. If you kick off a weekend trip with a free walking tour, then you will be well-equipped to spend the next days getting to know the city in greater detail on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many Edinburgh free walking tours to choose from but I was most impressed with the promises claimed by the tour company SANDEMANs, which is a known brand across Europe. As I only had one day to enjoy Edinburgh, I thought it was a good decision to start my morning with their free walking tour and see where that would take me. &lt;strong&gt;The experience did not disappoint.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;In A Nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights -&lt;/strong&gt; Very knowledgeable tour guides with a flair for theatrics and a passion for helping you understand Edinburgh and Scotland. Local knowledge quickly orientates you to the city and helps you plan the rest of your trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowlights -&lt;/strong&gt; Near the end of the tour there is a “coffee break” at their office where you are encouraged to buy tickets for paid tours. This would feel less scammy if after the coffee break there were another 1+ hours of walking, but there was only an additional 30 minutes or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line -&lt;/strong&gt; The value for money is undeniable and even the sales pitch to join a paid tour is perfectly appropriate. You can’t blame someone for using a free tour as bait to sell you something which also carries a value. All in all, free walking tours might cost you something, but what you get back in return far exceeds whatever you might pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sandemans-walking-tours&quot;&gt;SANDEMANs Walking Tours&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were several tour companies offering free walking tours in Edinburgh but I was drawn to the sleek website and tour descriptions of SANDEMANs. I can’t say that they are &lt;em&gt;the best&lt;/em&gt; since I haven’t compared them to other tour organizers in Edinburgh, but what I can say is that this was not my first free walking tour in Europe and in comparison to others I have taken it was &lt;strong&gt;at least equal to or better than any others that I have taken&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a wide variety of free and paid tours offered by SANDEMANs in Edinburgh. You can check out the tours and schedules on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neweuropetours.eu/edinburgh/en/home&quot;&gt;the SANDEMANs website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started my morning with the free walking tour and then I added the Edinburgh Castle tour to the afternoon. For both tours, I had the same guide; a really witty and very smart guy named &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neweuropetours.eu/Edinburgh/en/Guides/Details/Yb9onL/dave&quot;&gt;Dave&lt;/a&gt;. I overheard a few other guides introduce themselves and though their dry nature might be preferred by some, I really enjoyed spending the day with Dave. &lt;strong&gt;If you get a chance to choose, I vote that you request Dave.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really lucky with the weather the day I was in Edinburg but what is good to know is that all of SANDEMANs &lt;strong&gt;tours will go on as scheduled rain or shine&lt;/strong&gt;. The tours meet up on The Royal Mile which is the main street connecting the Edinburgh Castle at one end with the Royal Palace of Holyroodhouse on the other. The street in between is packed with shops and cafes, some of which even offer a discount to SANDEMANs ticket holders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;st-giles-cathedral&quot;&gt;St Giles’ Cathedral&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first stop on the free walking tour is St Giles’ Cathedral. This &lt;strong&gt;+900-year-old cathedral&lt;/strong&gt; is the seat of the Church of Scotland and is the most important cathedral in the country. As you can see in the photo below, there is a very interesting architectural feature in the steeple, which is shaped like a crown, rather than a point reaching to the heavens above, as is typical in church architecture around the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In nearly a millennium of history, you can imagine that St Giles’ Cathedral is tied to plenty of interesting and historically significant events. The one which Dave shared with us as his favorite story is about a street-seller named Jenny Geddes, who, during a religious service, became so upset at the archbishop that &lt;strong&gt;she threw her stool&lt;/strong&gt; (the kind you sit on) at his head. This instantly turned in to a full-blown riot which spread across Scotland. These riots grew to become the Wars of the Three Kingdoms, which included the English Civil War.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;St Giles’ Cathedral is also considered to be &lt;strong&gt;the mother church of Presbyterianism&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/free-walking-tour-edinburgh-st-giles-cathedral.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A Photo of the front of St Giles' Cathedral in Edinburgh&quot; title=&quot; St Giles' Cathedral in Edinburgh&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; St Giles’ Cathedral in Edinburgh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-elephant-house&quot;&gt;The Elephant House&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next few stops constitute a micro-tour inside of the tour. If I had to name it, it would be &lt;em&gt;the Origins of Harry Potter Tour&lt;/em&gt;. For Harry Potter fans, &lt;strong&gt;the next few sites will carry special significance&lt;/strong&gt;. Up first: The Elephant House.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pictured below, The Elephant House is a coffee shop inside of the Harvey’s Furniture Store building. If you look at the photo, the windows just above the building’s sign is the coffee shop. &lt;strong&gt;This is where J. K. Rowling wrote several of the early Harry Potter books.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where I am standing to take this photo is the Greyfriars Kirkyard, a graveyard &lt;strong&gt;where many recognizable names&lt;/strong&gt; from the novels can be found. But more on that later. First, we have to go to school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/free-walking-tour-edinburgh-harveys-furniture-store.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of the front of The Elephant House&quot; title=&quot; The Elephant House in Edinburgh where J.K. Rowling wrote Harry Potter&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Elephant House in Edinburgh where J.K. Rowling wrote Harry Potter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;george-heriots-school&quot;&gt;George Heriot’s School&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across the graveyard from The Elephant House stands George Heriot’s School. &lt;strong&gt;This private school is 400 years old&lt;/strong&gt; and was founded to offer a premier education to Scotland’s fatherless children. The castle-like architecture makes it stand out atop this hill which is across a valley from the Edinburgh Castle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see pictured below, the square building has a tall tower in each corner. &lt;strong&gt;These four towers are each the home, or “house,” to a group of pupils.&lt;/strong&gt; The house names are, Lauriston (green, after the school’s address, Lauriston Place), Greyfriars (white, named after the adjacent Greyfriars Kirk / Graveyard), Raeburn (red, after a famous former pupil, Henry Raeburn), Castle (blue, after Edinburgh Castle to the north).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The combination of this school with the four houses and the dramatic view of the Edinburgh Castle on a cliff across the way, form the basis of J. K. Rowling’s vision for &lt;strong&gt;Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/free-walking-tour-edinburgh-george-heriots-school.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;View of George Heriot's School from the side of the Greyfriars Kirkyard&quot; title=&quot; George Heriot's School in Edinburgh&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; George Heriot’s School in Edinburgh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;greyfriars-kirkyard&quot;&gt;Greyfriars Kirkyard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning back now to Greyfriars Kirkyard, this graveyard is home to many familiar names. Both names which hold real historical significance (James Douglas, Sir George McKenzie…) but also many names on &lt;strong&gt;these graves inspired characters in Harry Potter&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, lawyer Thomas Riddell is the inspiration for Voldemort, and poet William McGonagall inspired the character of Professor McGonagall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So why did these graves inspire these characters?&lt;/strong&gt; It is simple: graveyards offer authors all around the world with free and easy access to name inspiration for books. It is actually a common practice for authors to take names from graves, just as J. K. Rowling did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/free-walking-tour-edinburgh-greyfriars-kirkyard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo of our tour group in front of Sir George McKenzie's tomb in the Greyfriars Kirkyard&quot; title=&quot; Sir George McKenzie's tomb in the Greyfriars Kirkyard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Sir George McKenzie’s tomb in the Greyfriars Kirkyard&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;greyfriars-bobby-memorial-statue&quot;&gt;Greyfriars Bobby Memorial Statue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the tale of loyalty to the highest degree.&lt;/strong&gt; Greyfriars Bobby was a Skye Terrier which belonged to John Grey, the caretaker of the Greyfriars Kirkyard. John Grey passed away and his dog, Bobby, continued to stay by his human’s grave for the next 14 years, refusing to leave its side for any prolonged period of time. Bobby is now a well-known and well-documented figure in Scotland’s history. There are movies and books which retell the story of Bobby and this statue is a tribute to that loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the tour, we learned that &lt;strong&gt;the greatest honor a Scot can receive is to have a pub named after them&lt;/strong&gt;. We saw pubs named after cultural icons, royalty, and politicians. Here, you can see the even Bobby has had this honor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On another funny note: the graveyard actually has signs now saying that &lt;strong&gt;dogs are not allowed&lt;/strong&gt;. Oh how times change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/free-walking-tour-edinburgh-greyfriars-bobby-memorial-statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Greyfriars Bobby Memorial Statue with the Greyfriars Bobby Pub in the background&quot; title=&quot; Greyfriars Bobby Memorial Statue&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Greyfriars Bobby Memorial Statue&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;national-museum-of-scotland&quot;&gt;National Museum of Scotland&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our walking tour concluded at the National Museum of Scotland. This is a great destination because from here &lt;strong&gt;you can check out the museum, which is also free&lt;/strong&gt;. The museum is divided by era of Scottish history, starting with pre-historical origins, then lots of stuff about Vikings, Roman rule, the independence movement led by William Wallace, and then all the way up to modern-day Scotland with its engineering achievements and most notably, Dolly the Sheep!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/free-walking-tour-edinburgh-national-museum-scottland-atrium.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The atrium of the National Museum of Scotland in Edinburgh. &quot; title=&quot; National Museum of Scotland in Edinburgh&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; National Museum of Scotland in Edinburgh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dolly-the-sheep&quot;&gt;Dolly The Sheep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, the whole day has been pretty awesome up until now but &lt;strong&gt;this is for me the clear highlight&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dolly the Sheep is the first mammal to be cloned from an adult somatic cell. She was born in 1996 and is the creation of the University of Edinburgh. This leap in genetics paved the way for other animals to be cloned, including pigs, deer, horses, and bulls. Tonight as I wrote this post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/two-cloned-monkeys-scientists-break-new-ground-controversial-field-180967950/&quot;&gt;the news broke&lt;/a&gt; that two identical long-tailed macaques in China are the &lt;strong&gt;first ever primates to be cloned&lt;/strong&gt; using the technique that created Dolly the sheep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And who knows, maybe one day &lt;strong&gt;I can get a clone of myself&lt;/strong&gt; to help me write this blog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/free-walking-tour-edinburgh-national-museum-scottland-dolly-sheep.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A close-up photo of Dolly the Sheep, the first mammal to be cloned&quot; title=&quot; Dolly the Sheep in the National Museum of Scotland in Edinburgh&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Dolly the Sheep in the National Museum of Scotland in Edinburgh&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a final note, the guides of this (and all) free walking tours are not paid at all for the tour they provide. They earn money only on tips from tour participants. So if you think the job they did was good, &lt;strong&gt;be sure to recognize them for that&lt;/strong&gt;. Keeping in mind that a normal paid tour costs around 27£, offering a +10£ will go a long way for the guide and is really nothing at all for you as a participant. &lt;strong&gt;Be generous!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you think? Have you toured Edinburgh before? Have you been on a walking tour (paid or free) before? How do you think this one measures up? I would love to hear your thoughts. Feel free to leave a comment below or you can reach me directly on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/judsonlmoore&quot;&gt;@judsonlmoore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 12:00:44 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/edinburgh-free-walking-tour/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/edinburgh-free-walking-tour/</guid>
        
        <category>adventure,</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>guide,</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>tips,</category>
        
        <category>walking</category>
        
        <category>tour</category>
        
        
        <category>scotland</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Things to Do in Dublin - A 3-day Weekend Itinerary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are an incredible array of &lt;strong&gt;things to do in Dublin&lt;/strong&gt;, so if you are visiting for a short weekend, it can be a bit overwhelming to figure out how to best make use of your time. I recently had the good fortune of spending a week in Dublin. While there, I visited a lot of places, some were undeniably incredible, while others I could have lived without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I highlight the very best from my time in Dublin and schedule it out for you in an easy to follow guide which can serve as an outline for things to do in Dublin as you plan your trip there. Should you have feedback, additions, or questions, please leave a comment at the end of this article so that I and others can &lt;strong&gt;help you have the best trip to Dublin ever!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;outline-of-things-to-do-in-dublin&quot;&gt;Outline of Things to Do in Dublin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1 - Royalty and whiskey&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Dublin Castle &lt;em&gt;(1.5 hours)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Shopping in the old town &lt;em&gt;(open-ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Selfies with Statues &lt;em&gt;(open-ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Ha’penny Bridge &lt;em&gt;(10 minutes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Jameson Distillery on Bow St. &lt;em&gt;(2 hours)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The Church Bar &lt;em&gt;(open-ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2 - A historic walk and a brewery tour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The Samuel Beckett Bridge &lt;em&gt;(10 minutes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;St. Stephen’s Green &lt;em&gt;(30 minutes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Book of Kells + Trinity College &lt;em&gt;(1 hour)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;St. Patrick’s Cathedral &lt;em&gt;(1 hour)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Get your family crest &lt;em&gt;(5 minutes)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Guinness Storehouse &lt;em&gt;(3-4 hours)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Temple Bar &lt;em&gt;(open-ended)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Temple Bar whiskey tasting &lt;em&gt;(optional)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3 - A hike along the coast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;DART train to Greystones + Cliff Walk &lt;em&gt;(3-4 hours)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;DART train to Howth for Fish and Chips &lt;em&gt;(1-2 hours)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mix and match this schedule to suit your needs and weather conditions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-the-most-out-of-dublin&quot;&gt;Getting the Most out of Dublin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dublinbikes.ie/&quot;&gt;shared bikes all across Dublin&lt;/a&gt; and you can get a 3-day pass for just €5 and use the bikes an unlimited number of times for up to 30-minutes each ride. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dublinbus.ie/&quot;&gt;Public transportation in Dublin&lt;/a&gt; will cost you more and be less convenient in most cases, but if you anticipate bad weather just &lt;strong&gt;keep some coins in your pocket for the bus&lt;/strong&gt; as they don’t accept paper cash or cards, and they don’t give change. I also wouldn’t advise riding without a ticket, as the fine for getting caught can be as high as €1,000. Uber is also available throughout Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, in the week I spent in Dublin, I never took the bus and I only took an Uber to the airport. &lt;strong&gt;Dublin is very walkable.&lt;/strong&gt; Taking your own two feet is also the best way to explore the city. However, for a short weekend trip, you should probably take a bike, bus, or Uber to at least a few of the further out places, such as the Guinness Storehouse and the Jameson Distillery. I only say this as a timesaver and not because you couldn’t walk it if you wanted to. So consult Google Maps and make the decision that is best for your schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And last but not least, be aware that &lt;strong&gt;Ireland’s currency is the Euro&lt;/strong&gt; and you will need an adaptor for a &lt;strong&gt;type-G electrical plug at 230v&lt;/strong&gt; and 50Hz. I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B075VQDWZ7/ref=as_li_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B075VQDWZ7&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=judsonlmoor0a-20&amp;amp;linkId=f642c14792d29932c81b0b0796cb2fc1&quot;&gt;this adaptor on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;(affiliate link)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s get on with discussing all the things to do in Dublin for your awesome weekend trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-1---royalty-and-whiskey&quot;&gt;Day 1 - Royalty and Whiskey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take it a little bit easy on the first day. There are so many things to do in Dublin, but you just landed and you’ve not yet gotten acquainted with the city. &lt;strong&gt;There are a lot of things to stop and admire along the way&lt;/strong&gt; and so this first day balances a set to-do list and the flexibility to just explore as you go. Today you will get your bearings and walk through many of the central hotspots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend kicking off the day with breakfast wherever is near you. The “full Irish breakfast” is the go-to. Plus, you will get to try “black pudding,” a typical item on the Irish breakfast plate. &lt;strong&gt;You probably don’t want to know what it is.&lt;/strong&gt; Just eat it and smile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, head to the Dublin Castle around opening time. From there, enjoy Dublin’s shopping district. Then we will go learn some about the modern history of Dublin at the Jameson Distillery and taste some Irish whiskeys. To close the day out, grab a beer at one of &lt;strong&gt;the most interesting bars in the world&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-map-day-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
(https://goo.gl/maps/k7hetkFAABJ2) Click on image to open interactive map on Google.” %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dublin-castle&quot;&gt;Dublin Castle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dublin Castle is among the best things to do in Dublin, so what better place to start? The castle as you see it today is relatively new, built in the last 200 years, but there has been a government building here for &lt;strong&gt;around 900 years&lt;/strong&gt;. This was the seat of English, and later, British, government in Ireland until Ireland won independence in 1922. It is an active government building today, used mostly for formal state dinners and inauguration of the presidents of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are self-guided and guided tours available of Dublin Castle.&lt;/strong&gt; Much of the open exhibits allow for free-range exploration of the various rooms of state and apartments in the castle. There are rotating exhibit spaces as well which display some of Ireland’s finest artifacts. When I was visiting, the ceremonial Irish Sword of State was on display. This sword has been the symbol of Irish rule since 1681 and is officially part of the British Crown Jewels. It is on loan to the Dublin Castle from its normal display at the Tower of London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Early morning or after lunch&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 1.5 hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dublincastle.ie/&quot;&gt;dublincastle.ie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;link href=&quot;/assets/css/gallery-fluid.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;tz-gallery&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-dublin-castle-portrait-king-george-iv.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-dublin-castle-portrait-king-george-iv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A royal man in red uniform is painted against a brown background&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;Portrait of King George IV at the Dublin Castle&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;div class=&quot;col-sm-6 col-md-4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&quot;thumbnail&quot;&gt;
          &lt;a class=&quot;lightbox&quot; href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-dublin-castle-state-corridor.jpg&quot;&gt;

            

            &lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-dublin-castle-state-corridor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson stands in the State Corridor at the Dublin Castle&quot; /&gt;

            

          &lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;div class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;
              &lt;h3&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
              &lt;p&gt;The State Corridor at the Dublin Castle&lt;/p&gt;
          &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/baguettebox.js/1.8.1/baguetteBox.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script&gt;
    baguetteBox.run('.tz-gallery');
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-dublin-castle-irish-sword-of-state.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A detailed view of the gilded hilt of the Irish Sword of State&quot; title=&quot; The Irish Sword of State on Display at the Dublin Castle&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Irish Sword of State on Display at the Dublin Castle&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shopping-in-the-old-town&quot;&gt;Shopping in the old town&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The shopping in Dublin is very good.&lt;/strong&gt; Find Ha’penny Bridge on the map. The area south of the bridge is more historic old-town and higher-end shops. the area directly north of Ha’penny Bridge is a bit more bohemian and crafty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a lot of really cool shops in Dublin, but here are a few places I think everyone should check out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Secret Book and Record Store&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;15 Wicklow St, Dublin 2, D02 C924, Ireland&lt;/em&gt;
Cosy, independent bookshop offering a wide selection of new &amp;amp; secondhand titles, plus CDs &amp;amp; vinyl.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pg/The-Secret-Book-and-Record-Store-124706510933587&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aran Sweater Market&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;115 Grafton Street, Dublin 2, Ireland&lt;/em&gt;
The home of the famous Aran sweater, and original of Ireland! Sweaters, scarfs, and all sorts of other wool products.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aransweatermarket.com/&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George’s Street Arcade&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;S Great George’s St, Dublin 2, Dublin, Ireland&lt;/em&gt;
Ornate 1881 shopping plaza offering indie clothing boutiques &amp;amp; food vendors, plus books &amp;amp; jewelry.
&lt;a href=&quot;http://georgesstreetarcade.ie/&quot;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in &lt;strong&gt;secondhand and vintage shops&lt;/strong&gt;, then you must &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.siopaella.com&quot;&gt;check out Siopaella&lt;/a&gt;. There are four locations in Dublin, all very near each other. Each location has a different specialty, ranging from furnishings and luxury goods to more vintage items.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; 9:30 am - 7:00 pm 7-days a week (normal opening times)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; Open-ended&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-secret-book-record-store.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A long corridor with walls covered in posters and a bookshop at the end&quot; title=&quot; The Secret Book and Record Shop in Dublin Ireland&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Secret Book and Record Shop in Dublin Ireland&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;selfies-with-statues&quot;&gt;Selfies with Statues&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are statues and monuments everywhere in Dublin. Playing a history-based Pokémon-like game to &lt;strong&gt;try and find them all&lt;/strong&gt; will keep you quite busy and is a fun activity to play between all the other things to do in Dublin. Just keep your eyes open and snap a selfie every time you see a statue. If you do this, I promise you will have a really interesting compilation of photos across Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are too many statues for me to list or show&lt;/strong&gt;, but pictured here is perhaps the most famous statue. This is of Molly Malone, a legendary character of the 17th century. It is unknown if Molly was a real person or not, but still, her life is forever memorialized in a famous Irish folk song, and now in this statue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Daylight hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wikipedia:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_public_art_in_Dublin&quot;&gt;List of Public Art in Dublin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-molly-malone-statue.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson stands in front of a statue of Molly Malone&quot; title=&quot; Statue of Molly Malone in Dublin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Statue of Molly Malone in Dublin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hapenny-bridge&quot;&gt;Ha’penny Bridge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The River Liffey bisects Dublin into northern and southern halves. There are &lt;strong&gt;more than a dozen bridges&lt;/strong&gt; in just the central area of Dublin and so you shouldn’t ever feel too trapped on one side, without an easy route across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cast iron Ha’penny Bridge, dubbed as such because it was originally a toll bridge requiring pedestrians to pay in ha’pennies to cross it, is &lt;strong&gt;Dublin’s most historic bridge&lt;/strong&gt;. Over 200 years old, it was built in 1816 as Dublin’s first pedestrian bridge. It would remain the only pedestrian bridge until the nearby Millennium Bridge was opened in 1999.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Anytime&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; Minutes&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-hapenny-bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson stands in front of the Ha'penny Bridge&quot; title=&quot; The historic Ha'penny Bridge in Dublin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The historic Ha’penny Bridge in Dublin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jameson-distillery-on-bow-st&quot;&gt;Jameson Distillery on Bow St.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ireland is home to whiskey and no other whiskey in the world is as well-known as Jameson. The Bow St. Distillery in central Dublin is the historic home of Dublin, but it is no longer an active distillery. However, this does not make the experience any less exciting. The distillery “tour” is called &lt;em&gt;The Bow St. Experience&lt;/em&gt; because it is a multimedia 4-D immersion into the world of Jameson, whiskey, and Ireland (the 4th dimension is tasting whiskey!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jameson-distillery-tour-dublin/&quot;&gt;a comprehensive review of the Jameson Distillery&lt;/a&gt;  which you should read if you plan to visit the Bow St. Distillery. Regardless of how you feel about whiskey, I can’t stress enough that this is more or less mandatory on the list of things to do in Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Mid- or late-afternoon&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget: &lt;/strong&gt;2 hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamesonwhiskey.com/ie/visit-us/jameson-distillery-bow-st&quot;&gt;jamesonwhiskey.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional reading:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jameson-distillery-tour-dublin/&quot;&gt;Jameson distillery tour and whiskey tasting experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-jameson-distillery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson stands in front of the entrance sign for the Jameson Distillery&quot; title=&quot; The Jameson Distillery on Bow St. in Dublin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Jameson Distillery on Bow St. in Dublin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-church-bar&quot;&gt;The Church Bar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With so many cool things to do in Dublin and so many eclectic pubs, it is difficult to pin down “the best” place to grab a pint. But for sure, it is not every day that you can &lt;strong&gt;enjoy a drink inside of a church!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Church is a bar, restaurant, and event venue brought to life from the neglected ruins of St. Mary’s Church which had been left empty for over 30 years. The refurbished space has kept the stained-glass windows and organ pipes in-place and relishes in the grand church architecture as &lt;strong&gt;the perfect place to let go of your sins for a night!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, you can get married here, too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Evening&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://thechurch.ie/&quot;&gt;thechurch.ie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-the-church-bar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson sits waits for a drink at the Church Bar in Dublin Ireland. The Church's organ pipes are in the background.&quot; title=&quot; The Church Bar in Dublin Ireland&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Church Bar in Dublin Ireland&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-2--a-historic-walk-and-a-brewery-tour&quot;&gt;Day 2 – A historic walk and a brewery tour&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s get out and stretch out legs! There are so many things to do in Dublin and we don’t have any time to spare! &lt;strong&gt;Be ready for an intense day&lt;/strong&gt; of site-seeing, monument-gawking, and alcohol appreciation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will move in a westwardly direction for most of the day. Starting at another of Dublin’s iconic bridges, catching the sunset from atop the Guinness Storehouse, and then ending at &lt;strong&gt;the most iconic bar in all of Ireland&lt;/strong&gt; to sing our hearts out until sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-map-day-2-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
(https://goo.gl/maps/bKZP6fQF6ZU2) Click on image to open interactive map on Google.” %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-samuel-beckett-bridge&quot;&gt;The Samuel Beckett Bridge&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whereas the Ha’penny Bridge, which we saw yesterday, is one of the oldest bridges in Dublin, The Samuel Beckett Bridge is one of the newest bridges in Dublin. The architecture, however, is still what makes this a bridge worth checking out. The suspension cables and their mainstay form &lt;strong&gt;the shape of a harp&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the national symbol of Ireland since the thirteenth century. If you can catch the bridge on a calm day, the water of the Liffey River casts the neatest reflection. You can almost see that in the picture below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro tip: there is a Starbucks right around the corner from here, as well as the Admiral William Brown Memorial (another statue selfie!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Anytime&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; Minutes&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-samuel-beckett-bridge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson stands in front of the harp-shaped Samuel Backett Bridge&quot; title=&quot; The Samuel Beckett Bridge in Dublin is the shape of the Harp, Ireland's national symbol&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Samuel Beckett Bridge in Dublin is the shape of the Harp, Ireland’s national symbol&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;st-stephens-green&quot;&gt;St. Stephen’s Green&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This beautiful park in the heart of central Dublin is &lt;strong&gt;a great place to relax&lt;/strong&gt;. Complete with botanical gardens, fountains, meticulous landscaping, and even a waterfall, a visit to St. Stephen’s Green is among the more relaxing things to do in Dublin. As you can see, I visited in the dead of winter, yet despite that, the park was full of life and still a beautiful place to hang out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Daylight hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 30 minutes&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-st-stephens-green.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A winter view of a pond in St. Stephen's Green with blue skies&quot; title=&quot; St. Stephen's Green in central Dublin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; St. Stephen’s Green in central Dublin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;book-of-kells--trinity-college&quot;&gt;Book of Kells + Trinity College&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Book of Kells is actually four books containing the Gospels of the New Testament. They were created around 800 A.D. in either Britain or Ireland and are famous for their richly adorned pages with &lt;strong&gt;intricate drawings depicting the characters of the Gospels&lt;/strong&gt;. They have been on display at Trinity College since 1661. Only two volumes are on display at any given time and the page which the on-display books are open to changes fairly regularly as well so as not to cause damage to the books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you enter into the Old Library of Trinity College, you will have to pay for a ticket to see the Book of Kells. First, you are guided through a very well-organized exhibit detailing the history of the books. The larger-than-life prints from the book which are on display here, are honestly &lt;strong&gt;the best view you will get of the books&lt;/strong&gt;. After the exhibit, you go to a room where the books are and you can cast your gaze upon them for as long as you feel comfortable blocking someone else’s view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-long-room-of-the-old-library&quot;&gt;The Long Room of the Old Library&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Departing from the room with the Book of Kells, you go upstairs to The Long Room of the Old Library. &lt;strong&gt;This room is exciting for several reasons.&lt;/strong&gt; I will list some highlights here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Brian Boru Harp -  the oldest of the three surviving medieval Gaelic harps, and a national symbol of Ireland&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The rarest books - 200,000+ rare books, and in many cases very early volumes&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The smell - if you like the smell of old books and libraries, this will top all the senses&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Busts of Great Thinkers - the stacks are lined with amazing marble busts of great thinkers and philosophers&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Proclamation of the Irish Republic - one of the last remaining copies of the 1916 document proclaiming Irish independence&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cool factor - this is just a really cool room to be in&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The grounds of Trinity College are also very beautiful and historic. Take a walk around, check out the architecture, and if the weather permits, maybe &lt;strong&gt;have a picnic somewhere on the campus grounds.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Around lunchtime&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 hour&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tcd.ie/visitors/book-of-kells/&quot;&gt;tcd.ie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-book-of-kells.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson stands in the great hall of the Book of Kells&quot; title=&quot; The Book of Kells at Trinity College in Dublin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Book of Kells at Trinity College in Dublin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;st-patricks-cathedral&quot;&gt;St. Patrick’s Cathedral&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visiting a church might not be at the top of your list of things to do in Dublin. However, and quite simply, as one of the most iconic cathedrals in the world, the St. Patrick’s Cathedral holds special significance for Irish and non-Irish alike. There is a ticketed fee to enter the church, which is generally something I oppose, but they make it worth while with special exhibits and some other displays which are &lt;strong&gt;not common in other European churches&lt;/strong&gt; I have visited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the expected beautiful architecture and vast history of the church, there are also a number of exhibits detailing the impact the church has had on Irish culture. There are a number of artifacts on display around the church and quite a few multimedia stations playing short videos explaining the church’s impact on society. There are also some &lt;strong&gt;cool kid-friendly hands-on activities&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adjacent Saint Patrick’s Cathedral Choir School is &lt;strong&gt;the oldest such school in Ireland&lt;/strong&gt;, now nearing its 600th anniversary. The choir performs twice daily during the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pro tip: St. Patrick’s Cathedral is an Anglican church, which means some of their service terminologies differ from other traditional churches. For example, they do not celebrate “mass” but instead, refer to the ”Eucharist.” Knowing the difference between these words will go a long way in helping you blend in to the masses (pun intended!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Daylight hours (to see the stained glass windows better), or during any of these services held on weekdays:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;9:00 Sung Matins - &lt;em&gt;youth choir performance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;11:05 Eucharist&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;17:30 Choral Evensong - &lt;em&gt;youth choir performance &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 hour&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stpatrickscathedral.ie&quot;&gt;stpatrickscathedral.ie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-st-patricks-cathedral.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A view of the interior of St. Patrick's Cathedrial&quot; title=&quot; Inside St. Patrick's Cathedral in Dublin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Inside St. Patrick’s Cathedral in Dublin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-your-family-crest&quot;&gt;Get your family crest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a quick bonus at the St. Patrick’s Cathedral. The gift shop is actually quite nice and they have a section of all the family crests for the church’s members. People often ask me if I am Irish and I always say no, that I am more German and Danish. But here I found a crest for the Moore Family. &lt;strong&gt;This prompted me to fact-check my heritage&lt;/strong&gt; and learn that indeed, I am a bit Irish. Opps. Well, I guess we learn something new every day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-irish-family-crest-moore.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson holds the Irsh family crest for Moore. Two golden lions flank a green shield with three golden stars and a golden lion on it&quot; title=&quot; The Irish family crest for Moore&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The Irish family crest for Moore&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guinness-storehouse&quot;&gt;Guinness Storehouse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we started hard with whiskey so today lets take it a bit easier and go for a “bit of the black stuff!” Guinness is every bit as important to the history, prominence, and development of Ireland as Jameson is. Here, at the Guinness Storehouse, you will experience &lt;strong&gt;a deeply immersive educational experience&lt;/strong&gt; which is as much about the beer brewing process as it is about the history of Guinness and the impact this brewery had on Ireland’s industrial revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The storehouse is 1-part self-guided tour, 1-part museum, and 1-part hands-on experimentation. &lt;strong&gt;You even get to try your hand at making a perfect pour of a pint of Guinness.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are interested in visiting the Guinness Storehouse, be sure to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/guinness-storehouse-dublin/&quot;&gt;my comprehensive review of the Guinness Storehouse&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly to the Jameson Distillery, I argue that &lt;strong&gt;a visit to the Guinness Storehouse is a must-do&lt;/strong&gt; on this list of things to do in Dublin. If you can only do one or the other, then probably the Guinness Storehouse is the better experience, but both are very much worth visiting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Late afternoon&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 3-4 hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guinness-storehouse.com/en&quot;&gt;guinness-storehouse.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional reading:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/guinness-storehouse-dublin/&quot;&gt;Visiting the Guinness Storehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-guinness-storehouse.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson jumps in the air in front of the Guinness Storehouse&quot; title=&quot; The gates of the Guinness Storehouse in Dublin&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; The gates of the Guinness Storehouse in Dublin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;temple-bar&quot;&gt;Temple Bar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Self-proclaimed as, “the friendliest watering hole in Dublin,” might be just about right, but for sure this is at least &lt;strong&gt;the most famous of all the bars in Dublin&lt;/strong&gt;. So what better place to end our day? One of the best things about this bar is that they have live Irish music 7-days a week from 2:00 pm until closing time. I stopped in here a few times during my stay in Dublin and I was blown away each time by the amazing music being performed. There is no cover charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Temple Bar restaurant is also quite good and this is a great place to try a &lt;strong&gt;traditional dinner of oysters and Guinness!&lt;/strong&gt; If you feel like trying some more whiskeys, Temple Bar has Ireland’s largest selection of whiskey (more on that next). So no matter what is on your list of things to do in Dublin tonight, you can find it all at Temple Bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Evening&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 1+ hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetemplebarpub.com/&quot;&gt;thetemplebarpub.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-temple-bar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two musicians perform Irish Music in the corner stage of the Temple Bar&quot; title=&quot; Live music at the Temple Bar in Dublin Ireland&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Live music at the Temple Bar in Dublin Ireland&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;temple-bar-distillery-store-and-taste-testing&quot;&gt;Temple Bar Distillery Store and Taste Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right next to Temple Bar is a small whiskey shop called the Temple Bar Distillery Store. They have a wide array of whiskeys on display and for sale. They have everything, ranging from Temple Bar whiskey which is made in-house, all the way up to the rarest hundred-plus-year-old whiskeys which cost more than $2500 a bottle. &lt;strong&gt;Their knowledgeable staff is super friendly and happy to give you a history tour around the room.&lt;/strong&gt; I highly recommend this. They also have a whiskey tasting menu which I found to be quite comprehensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part, though, at least on my visit, is that there was a TV in the back of the room playing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LS-ErOKpO4E&quot;&gt;Nick Offerman’s ‘Yule Log’&lt;/a&gt; for the whole evening. &lt;strong&gt;Clearly, these people are amazing.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Evening&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 10 minutes - 1 hour&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thetemplebarpub.com/&quot;&gt;thetemplebarpub.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-temple-bar-distillery-store-tasting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Four bottles of whiskey lined up and ready to be tasted&quot; title=&quot; Whiskey Tasting at the Temple Bar Distillery Store&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Whiskey Tasting at the Temple Bar Distillery Store&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-3--a-hike-along-the-coast&quot;&gt;Day 3 – A hike along the coast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you are not yet tired of walking because everything else has just been a warmup to get to today! As great as the last days’ activities have been, I think this day is the most rewarding. Be aware that &lt;strong&gt;good weather is necessary&lt;/strong&gt;, so if you need to rearrange your schedule to accommodate this on day one or day two, go for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will take the train to &lt;strong&gt;explore the Irish coastline&lt;/strong&gt; and get our hiking boots a little dirty. At the end of the day, we will be well rewarded with some of the best fish and chips in all of Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tip about today, if you will fly out of Dublin tonight, then &lt;strong&gt;you should take your luggage to the DART station&lt;/strong&gt;. They have luggage storage there. Just be sure to pick up your luggage after hiking in Greystones while on your way to Howth. From Howth, it is much easier to go directly to the airport than it would be to go back to the city center and then to the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-map-day-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
(https://goo.gl/maps/YDsvv4pj4922) Click on image to open interactive map on Google.” %}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dart-train-to-greystones--cliff-walk&quot;&gt;DART train to Greystones + Cliff Walk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the best things to do in Dublin is to get out of Dublin! The DART is Dublin’s regional train for commuters. The main station in Dublin is Connolly Station, which has the best options for luggage storage and other services. The endpoints of the DART line following the coast are Greystones to the south and Howth to the north. You will need to &lt;strong&gt;buy a day pass for the train&lt;/strong&gt;. As of this writing, it costs €12.00 per person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your day pass and have stored any luggage you need to put away, &lt;strong&gt;hop on the next southbound train to Greystones&lt;/strong&gt;. The ride lasts about an hour and the views are spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you arrive at Greystones, head over toward the beach, and when you are ready, walk along the coast back toward the north (so that the water is to your right side). Within a few minutes, you will come to a path marked with a sign, “Cliff Walk / Bray.” &lt;strong&gt;Bray is the next town to the north and is your destination.&lt;/strong&gt; If you don’t find this sign, no worries, just take the sidewalks and paths closest to the water until you get there. This cliff walk is really popular, so you can also look for the stream of people walking toward you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cliff walk is a well-maintained trail along the coast. &lt;strong&gt;The views and the fresh air are a great reprise from the city life.&lt;/strong&gt; Just enjoy and go at your own pace! When you arrive at Bray, there are a number of coffee shops and takeaway cafes. Just don’t ruin your appetite, because in a few hours you will be eating the best fish and chips!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Morning&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 3-4 hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.irishrail.ie/fares-and-tickets/dart&quot;&gt;irishrail.ie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-cliff-walks-greystones.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Judson stands on the cliffs of Greystones with the ocean behind him &quot; title=&quot; View from the Cliff Walks of Greystones&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; View from the Cliff Walks of Greystones&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dart-train-to-howth-for-fish-and-chips&quot;&gt;DART train to Howth for Fish and Chips&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train from Greystones to Howth &lt;strong&gt;takes about two hours&lt;/strong&gt;. If you need to stop off in Dublin to pick up luggage you stored there, then expect to have to wait for a little for the next train to Howth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon arrival in Howth, you have a few options. You can explore the peninsula which forms the northern border of the Bay of Dublin. The area is very walkable and there are a lot more hiking opportunities if time and daylight allow. Howth is a fishing community and so this is &lt;strong&gt;a really authentic place to get fish and chips&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly under the train station is a restaurant called The Bloody Stream. The atmosphere is cool, the location is very convenient, &lt;strong&gt;the prices are much more reasonable&lt;/strong&gt; than some of the other nearby restaurants, and the fish and chips are the best I have ever had. While you wait for your food, read the history on the back of the menu to learn about why they are called The Bloody Stream. Hint: Vikings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When to visit:&lt;/strong&gt; Afternoon or evening&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time to Budget:&lt;/strong&gt; 1-2 hours&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Website:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bloodystream.ie/&quot;&gt;bloodystream.ie&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/dublin-weekend-itenerary-howth-fish-chips.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The traditional fish and chips at The Bloody Stream in the Howth Railway Station&quot; title=&quot; Fish and Chips at The Bloody Stream in the Howth Railway Station&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt; Fish and Chips at The Bloody Stream in the Howth Railway Station&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;back to top&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;relax-smile-you-did-it&quot;&gt;Relax. Smile. You did it!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mix and match a schedule that works for you and the weather you encounter. Of course, this list of things to do in Dublin is not fully comprehensive and it fully omits any mention of what will really make your trip to Dublin special: you! &lt;strong&gt;Just relax, have a good time, and live every moment to the fullest.&lt;/strong&gt; That is the only thing you need to make sure that whatever you do in Dublin, it will be a trip to remember!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have I missed any major attractions which you think should be on this list? Have you been to any of these sites? &lt;strong&gt;Please share your experience&lt;/strong&gt; and provide any feedback, tips, or questions in the comments below. You may also reach me directly on Twitter at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/judsonlmoore&quot;&gt;@judsonlmoore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 13:00:51 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dublin-weekend-itinerary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dublin-weekend-itinerary/</guid>
        
        <category>adventure,</category>
        
        <category>itenerary,</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>guide,</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>tips</category>
        
        
        <category>ireland</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Visiting the Guinness Storehouse in Dublin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Guinness Storehouse in Dublin&lt;/strong&gt; is the traditional home of the world’s most famous stout beer: Guinness. This 200+ year-old &lt;em&gt;city within a city&lt;/em&gt; is a major contributor to modern Irish history and to the island’s economy and world fame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Guinness is known the world over as a premium stout. It’s not the kind of beer you drink every day or in large quantity. It stands out as being quite different from any other beer you will find because it is black, creamy, and served on nitro, which means &lt;strong&gt;you also have to have a fairly sophisticated setup&lt;/strong&gt; just to pour it properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how does a beer with so many complications and which is so limited in drinkability end up being a global powerhouse business? &lt;strong&gt;That is exactly what I came to the Guinness Storehouse in Dublin to find out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional reading: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/jameson-distillery-tour-dublin/&quot;&gt;Jameson distillery tour and whiskey tasting experience&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;In A Nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights -&lt;/strong&gt; The facilities are recently renovated but still have that industrial-era charm. The experience is about much more than just beer but also helps visitors understand the history of beer in general. The experience is extraordinarily well curated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowlights -&lt;/strong&gt; The Guinness Storehouse is a museum and not a brewery. The start of the tour is a bit chaotic without a clear start point. Most of the experience is self-guided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line -&lt;/strong&gt; The space which the Guinness Storehouse occupies is very impressive and will leave visitors more knowledgeable about Guinness, beer, Dublin, and Ireland. A perfect way to spend 3-4 hours in Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-guinness-storehouse-is-the-worlds-largest-beer-glass&quot;&gt;The Guinness Storehouse is the world’s largest beer glass&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will notice when you walk into the Guinness Storehouse is that it is very (I mean VERY) large. It is a tall building, 7-stories of museum, which is hollow on the inside, plus a rooftop panoramic bar. Modern renovations have lined the interior atrium with glass panels, effectively forming &lt;strong&gt;the world’s largest beer glass&lt;/strong&gt;. If filled, it would hold something like 17 million pints of Guinness! Unfortunately, this design was impossible to photograph, so you will have to check it out yourself to see what I am talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guinness-storehouse.com/en/tickets&quot;&gt;We booked our tickets online&lt;/a&gt; so we had a specific time to arrive. Something to note, however, is that this is more for capacity management and NOT a reservation. The experience starts with a welcome speech which takes place &lt;strong&gt;every 15 minutes&lt;/strong&gt;. You could even skip this and walk straight into the first exhibit if you wanted. So, if you are on your way here and are running late, don’t sweat it! You will be just fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the introduction speech, we were directed to the start of the experience. The first exhibit is all about the ingredients which make Guinness. Of course, these are the standard four ingredients of all beer: &lt;strong&gt;barley, hops, yeast, and water&lt;/strong&gt;. What was so interesting about the way Guinness displays these items were simply by their scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The barley was a field of grains probably 30’ x 30’ with multimedia displayed on screens in the center as well as projected onto the ingredients. As you walk around the field, the wall to the outside covers agricultural and historical facts about barley in society. The next little section were stalks of hops growing out of the ground from below where we were walking and stretching out of sight above us into the floors above. When we came to the water, &lt;strong&gt;it was a massive waterfall&lt;/strong&gt; pouring into a vast pool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this was to set up what came next: &lt;strong&gt;the brewing process&lt;/strong&gt;. (Step 11 is an on-going theme throughout the Guinness Storehouse.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/guinness-storehouse-dublin-brewing-process.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;guinness-as-an-industrial-revolution-leader&quot;&gt;Guinness as an industrial revolution leader&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A phrase which came up many times at the Guinness Storehouse was that this space was a &lt;em&gt;city within a city&lt;/em&gt; which shaped Ireland’s position in the world &lt;strong&gt;during the Industrial Revolution&lt;/strong&gt;. The whole space has a strong vibe resonating with Industrial Revolution-era aesthetic and machinery. Though much of this has been updated to modern machines and materials, it is super interesting to see some of the original brewing machinery which made it possible for Guinness to be brewed at scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must say that &lt;strong&gt;of all the breweries I have visited around the world&lt;/strong&gt;, none have showcased their industrial roots quite like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/guinness-storehouse-dublin-brewing-machinery.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;detail-and-impressive-scale-at-every-step-of-the-way&quot;&gt;Detail and impressive scale at every step of the way&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The exhibit which I found most interesting&lt;/strong&gt; was the area pictured below with all of the wooden casks which Guinness is aged in. I don’t often think about beer as being aged in oak, but that actually is fairly common. In Düsseldorf, where I live now, it is common to get alt beer directly from the cask (but that story is for another day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What most impressed me&lt;/strong&gt; here was a demonstration of how the barrels are made. The tradesmen which make wooden barrels are called coopers. Coopers are a great example of how to make something exceedingly complicated look super easy when you have the right tools and the right skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit area features a large stack of Guinness barrels, a display of original cooper tools, and a video which shows the whole process, start to finish, of a cooper making one of these barrels. &lt;strong&gt;Fascinating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/guinness-storehouse-dublin-barrels.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cultural-impacts-of-guinness&quot;&gt;Cultural impacts of Guinness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a whole floor dedicated to Guinness advertising. Apparently, &lt;strong&gt;Guinness has some hilarious ads&lt;/strong&gt;. Many of the ads depict exotic animals like seals and toucans propping up a Guinness on their noses. There actually was a real circus seal that could run around the room while balancing a full glass of Guinness on its nose without spilling it. I imagine that practice has ended, but the videos were quite funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably my favorite ad said “A woman needs a man like a fish needs a bicycle,” which then, of course, had a fish riding a bicycle, followed by “not everything in black and white makes sense,” and then some call to drink Guinness. &lt;strong&gt;Attention-grabbing, to say the least.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the claim in the advertising section of the museum is that these &lt;strong&gt;Guinness ads changed the advertising landscape&lt;/strong&gt; by making a shift away from simply stating facts about a product, and instead focusing on humor, emotion, and merely alluding to the qualities of their product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The culture piece which I gravitated to was the one which impacts my daily work in the technology sector: &lt;strong&gt;the constant availability of beer at work&lt;/strong&gt;. Every day at 10am, the official taste-testers at Guinness have to take a drink. This is only about quality assurance, of course, but hey, someone has to do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/guinness-storehouse-dublin-tasting-time-clock.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-little-taste-of-the-black-stuff&quot;&gt;A little taste of the black stuff&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of taste testing, &lt;strong&gt;it is time for us to get a bit of the black stuff!&lt;/strong&gt; We get ushered into a room which is nearly identical to The Television Room in Willy Wonka where he makes his television chocolate. This space is a stark difference from what we have experienced so far: plain white walls, no branding, just a white room which bright lighting and a bar with some Guinness taps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a guide which welcomes us to the room and asks us to walk around the room to smell the four “aroma chambers” which are each &lt;strong&gt;emitting a gentle fog&lt;/strong&gt; and smell of Guinness at different stages of brewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are asked to describe what we smell. The room responds with all sorts of “notes of..” and “hints of..” and other pallet terminology which &lt;strong&gt;mostly just annoy me&lt;/strong&gt; when describing beer, but hey, we are at a tasting, so what do you expect?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then finally, we get to drink some Guinness! Unfortunately, as you can see from this image, &lt;strong&gt;it is the world’s smallest beer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/guinness-storehouse-dublin-tiny-taste-testing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-achieve-a-perfect-pour-of-guinness&quot;&gt;How to achieve a perfect pour of Guinness&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the drinking isn’t over yet! The last stop on the tour is the Guinness Pouring Academy. Here, we learned what makes a Guinness tap different from a normal beer tap. I already knew that &lt;strong&gt;Guinness is served on nitro&lt;/strong&gt;, rather than CO2, but there is more to it than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The perfect pour of Guinness&lt;/strong&gt; demands that you first fill the glass about 2/3 by pulling the tap toward you. Then you let this settle for a minute and when you continue filling the glass you &lt;em&gt;push&lt;/em&gt; the tap &lt;em&gt;in&lt;/em&gt; which actually pours Guinness &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; nitro! It is this combination that creates the trademark creamy head on top of the glass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../assets/images/2018/01/guinness-storehouse-dublin-perfect-pint-certification.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plan-a-visit-to-the-guinness-storehouse&quot;&gt;Plan a visit to the Guinness Storehouse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A visit to the Guinness Storehouse will set you back &lt;strong&gt;about $20&lt;/strong&gt; and is a great way to fill a rainy afternoon in Dublin. Learn about the Storehouse and all of their ticketing options at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.guinness-storehouse.com/en&quot;&gt;guinness-storehouse.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you been to the Guinness Storehouse before? &lt;strong&gt;I would love to know your thoughts about the experience!&lt;/strong&gt; Please leave a comment below, or feel free to reach me directly on Twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/judsonlmoore&quot;&gt;@judsonlmoore.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 17:08:37 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/guinness-storehouse-dublin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/guinness-storehouse-dublin/</guid>
        
        <category>alcohol,</category>
        
        <category>craft</category>
        
        <category>beer,</category>
        
        <category>dublin,</category>
        
        <category>europe,</category>
        
        <category>museum,</category>
        
        <category>tours</category>
        
        
        <category>ireland</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jameson distillery tour and whiskey tasting experience in Dublin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When visiting Dublin&lt;/strong&gt; there are a few staple must-do activities and tourist traps you simply have to fall in to. Drink a Guinness? Check! Go for a hike? Check! Have a whiskey distillery tour and whiskey taste testing? Check check! Welcome to the home of Ireland’s most famous whiskey: &lt;strong&gt;The Jameson Distillery on Bow St.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of activities and tours you can take while visiting The Jameson Distillery but &lt;strong&gt;I am going to focus on two:&lt;/strong&gt; The Jameson Distillery Tour, and the Premium Whiskey Tasting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, don’t get me wrong, I was raised in Kentucky (hint, that is foreshadowing..) but I have never been to a proper whiskey taste testing. I have done more than my share of vineyard weekends and even a tequila tasting at the Jose Cuervo distillery in Tequila, Mexico, but &lt;strong&gt;this is my first sit down to learn how to fully appreciate the finer side of whiskey.&lt;/strong&gt; A dear and lifelong friend has called me “Jameson” for about as long as I can remember, so it feels about right that I should have this first experience at The Jameson Distillery!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further Reading: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.judsonlmoore.com/guinness-storehouse-dublin/&quot;&gt;Visiting the Guinness Storehouse in Dublin. Tour and experience review.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-a-nutshell&quot;&gt;In A Nutshell&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Highlights -&lt;/strong&gt; The facilities are recently renovated but still have that industrial-era charm. The location of The Jameson Distillery make it easy to get in and out of. There are lots of opportunities to eat and drink in and near The Jameson Distillery. The experience is about much more than just whiskey but also helps visitors understand the history of Irish whiskey in general and interesting facts about Dublin’s history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lowlights -&lt;/strong&gt; The tour omits any active area of The Jameson Distillery, so it is not really a functional space in any way, just a really nicely themed museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line -&lt;/strong&gt; The Jameson Distillery on Bow St. is a great way to spend a few hours in Dublin during poor weather or after the sun sets. It offers something for everyone regardless of whiskey appreciation and to understand the history of Jameson, is to understand the history of Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-the-jameson-distillery-bow-st-tour-in-dublin&quot;&gt;Take the Jameson Distillery Bow St. Tour in Dublin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tour of The Jameson Distillery is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamesonwhiskey.com/ie/visit-us/jameson-distillery-bow-st/jdbs-our-experiences/bow-st-experience&quot;&gt;The Bow St. Experience&lt;/a&gt;. I think this is for two reasons. The obvious one is that the distillery is located on Bow St. The second is that &lt;strong&gt;it is not a distillery anymore&lt;/strong&gt;, rather it is a museum of the original distillery, thus, it is an “experience” and not really a distillery tour. According to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamesonwhiskey.com/ie/visit-us&quot;&gt;the Jameson website&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;every drop of Jameson is produced in Midleton, Cork,&lt;/em&gt; about a 3-hour drive away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The tour consists of four parts.&lt;/strong&gt; The first part is mostly about waiting for the second part, but you wait along a wall with a very nice timeline of Jameson history. Much of this is to understand the origins of Jameson, the life of the founder, John Jameson, and the impact that this &lt;em&gt;city within a city&lt;/em&gt; has had on Dublin, Ireland, and the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you work your way down the timeline, you find yourself in a small theater in the round where the “Jameson Ambassador” will tell the story of Jameson Whiskey with the aid of some astoundingly well-engineered visual and audio aids. &lt;strong&gt;Walt Disney would be proud!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/jameson-distillery-bow-st-dublin-tour.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image full&quot; loading=&quot;auto&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2304&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have gained a theoretical knowledge of all things related to Jameson Whiskey, we move into another room where we get to put our hands on what makes Jameson, Jameson: &lt;strong&gt;the ingredients!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;em&gt;process room&lt;/em&gt;, our ambassador guides us through an interactive explanation of the distilling process. We get to touch the ingredients, smell the stages of distillation, and even come to appreciate the difference between different woods used to make the barrels which infuse whiskey with their smokey quality. Turns out that all &lt;strong&gt;Jameson whiskey is aged in recycled bourbon barrels&lt;/strong&gt; from American bourbon makers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/jameson-distillery-bow-st-dublin-ingredients.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image full&quot; loading=&quot;auto&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2304&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all of this, we make our way into yet another room where we get &lt;strong&gt;a free taste testing of whiskey!&lt;/strong&gt; Guests are taught how to properly drink whiskey, what qualities to look (and taste) for, and we got to compare three kinds of whiskey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first two whiskeys were not labeled and so we were asked to guess what they were. I was surprised that &lt;strong&gt;I correctly nailed exactly which whiskeys they were.&lt;/strong&gt; The first was Johnny Walker Red Label. When I said this, the ambassador asked, “what qualities of the pallet and nose helped you determine that?” I simply said, “because it is bad!” Everyone laughed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the second unknown whiskey, I gave it one smell and shouted out, “Jack Daniel’s!” Which was correct. When again asked what gave it away for me, I said, “because it is amazing!” Again, everyone laughed. I don’t know if it is because of my Kentucky roots, but Jack Daniel’s has always been my favorite. I don’t pretend to say it is &lt;em&gt;the best&lt;/em&gt; whiskey, but &lt;strong&gt;it is my drink of choice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then moved on to the third tasting, which was, of course, Jameson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think having back to back whiskeys is pretty rough on the pallet&lt;/strong&gt; and I am not so convinced that tasting them like this is really the best idea, but still, I appreciated the opportunity and it was a great way to round off the end of the Jameson Distillery Bow St. Tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about this tour and book tickets for your visit on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamesonwhiskey.com/ie/visit-us/jameson-distillery-bow-st/jdbs-our-experiences/bow-st-experience&quot;&gt;the Jameson website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/jameson-distillery-bow-st-dublin-tour-taste-testing.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image full&quot; loading=&quot;auto&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2304&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-premium-whiskey-tasting-at-the-jameson-distillery-bow-st&quot;&gt;A premium whiskey tasting at the Jameson Distillery Bow St.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now on to part two of my experience: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamesonwhiskey.com/ie/visit-us/jameson-distillery-bow-st/jdbs-our-experiences/the-whiskey-tasters&quot;&gt;the premium whiskey tasting at the Jameson Distillery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tasting was actually a pretty amazing experience. For one, the location is in John Jameson’s original office. It has been renovated but keeps the general essence of the original office. &lt;strong&gt;John Jameson had a pretty awesome office&lt;/strong&gt; apparently because it has a full bar in it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space is limited to 18 people per tasting. This is a great activity to organize for small groups, team events, and bachelor parties, which is what I walked in to. I was the one man out in a room full of dudes celebrating the pending marriage of one of their friends. But I would say this made the tasting &lt;strong&gt;even that much more fun.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this tasting, we were provided four whiskeys to try, &lt;strong&gt;all of which come from Jameson.&lt;/strong&gt; They were (in order of testing):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jameson Original&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jameson Crested&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jameson Distillery Edition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jameson Black Barrel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will quickly share what I learned about each of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jameson-irish-whiskey-original&quot;&gt;Jameson Irish Whiskey (original)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Triple distilled, twice as smooth, one of a kind. Jameson Irish Whiskey is a blended Irish whiskey which has been aged in oak casks for a minimum of 4 years. The base Jameson pot still whiskey is blended with a delicate grain whiskey, allowing them to mature and inherit the nuttiness of sherry casks balanced with the fragrant vanilla of bourbon casks (see the ingredients image above). The final product is sold in the Jameson iconic green-glass bottle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; - A light floral fragrance, peppered with spicy wood and sweet notes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taste&lt;/strong&gt; - The perfect balance of spicy, nutty and vanilla notes with hints of sweet sherry and exceptional smoothness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.jamesonwhiskey.com/collections/whiskeys/products/jameson-irish-whiskey&quot;&gt;Learn More and buy Jameson Original&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jameson-crested&quot;&gt;Jameson Crested&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until the 1960s, Jameson could be purchased by the barrel. This allowed for “bonders” to bottle the whiskey on their own, but the temptation to water down the product proved to be too tempting for too many. Therefore, the practice of selling barrels was ended. The Jameson Crested edition is a celebration of the whiskey from those earlier times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jameson Crested is created in much the same way as the original but it is left to mature longer in the sherry casts than in the bourbon barrels.  The high proportion of sherry casks in the blend delivers vivid sherry &amp;amp; hearty pot still notes with some spice and a hint of melon &amp;amp; ginger. Full bodied with soft delicate sherry undertones, toasted wood, perfectly balanced with fruit, spice and some chocolate notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; - Vivid sherry pot still aroma.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taste&lt;/strong&gt; - Delicate sherry undertones &amp;amp; toasted wood, with fruit, spice &amp;amp; chocolate notes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; - Warm lingering sherry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.jamesonwhiskey.com/collections/whiskeys/products/crested-10&quot;&gt;Learn more and buy Jameson Crested&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/jameson-distillery-bow-st-dublin-premium-whiskey-taste-testing.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image full&quot; loading=&quot;auto&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2305&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jameson-distillery-edition&quot;&gt;Jameson Distillery Edition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The distillery edition is only available for consumption and purchase directly from the Jameson Bow St. Distillery in Dublin. I found the flavor to be similar to the original Jameson but slightly more citrusy. This whiskey has a bit more of a refined taste with a smoother finish. The initial bite is also dampened a bit, probably by the addition of a little extra single malt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; -  Mango, cream, ginger, buttered corn, sugarcane&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taste&lt;/strong&gt; -  Orange, brown sugar, ginger, peach, salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; - Corn, sugar, arugula, oak, vanilla, ginger ale, butterscotch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Jameson Distillery Edition is available only on-site in the Bow St. Distillery.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jameson-black-barrel&quot;&gt;Jameson Black Barrel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stuff is like lighter-fluid. Really, it is the moonshine of Jameson whiskeys. We tasted it first straight, and then with a few drops of water. There was a huge difference. The name comes from the twice-charred bourbon barrels which this whiskey is aged in. This gives the finished product a much richer flavor and a lot more intensity than the other bottles of Jameson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; - Time spent maturing in these barrels leads to intensified aromas of butterscotch, fudge, and creamy toffee.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taste&lt;/strong&gt; - Nutty notes are in abundance alongside the smooth sweetness of spice and vanilla.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; - Enjoy the richness and intensity of toasted wood and vanilla.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.jamesonwhiskey.com/collections/whiskeys/products/jameson-select-reserve&quot;&gt;Learn more and buy Jameson Black Barrel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/images/2018/01/jameson-distillery-bow-st-dublin-behind-the-bar.jpg&quot; class=&quot;post-image full&quot; loading=&quot;auto&quot; style=&quot;height: auto&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; description=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;2304&quot; height=&quot;1536&quot; crossorigin=&quot;anonymous&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts-on-the-taste-testing&quot;&gt;Final thoughts on the taste testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the conclusion of the tasting, our ambassador asked everyone in the room to declare which was their favorite. No one said that the black barrel was their favorite. There was probably a fairly equal split among the other three bottles for being the class favorite, with a possible leader of the &lt;strong&gt;Jameson Crested&lt;/strong&gt;, which I also favored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, &lt;strong&gt;this was a really nice experience and one I am glad to have had.&lt;/strong&gt; It was worth the 30 Euros and 4o minutes. To top it off, the taste testing also came with a really nice book about Jameson with the full history and recipes for whiskey cocktails you can make at home. &lt;strong&gt;Unlike the distillery tour&lt;/strong&gt;, participants of the taste testing also received a 10% discount at the gift shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about this taste testing and book tickets for your visit on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jamesonwhiskey.com/ie/visit-us/jameson-distillery-bow-st/jdbs-our-experiences/the-whiskey-tasters&quot;&gt;the Jameson website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sláinte-cheers-in-irish-gaelic&quot;&gt;Sláinte! “Cheers!” in Irish Gaelic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed my review of the Jameson Bow St. Experience and the premium whiskey taste testing. Please feel free to leave a comment below with details of your own experience, thoughts on my experience, or any followup questions that you have for me. You can also connect with me directly on twitter &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twitter.com/judsonlmoore&quot;&gt;@judsonlmoore&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 16:42:41 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/jameson-distillery-tour-dublin/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/jameson-distillery-tour-dublin/</guid>
        
        <category>alcohol,</category>
        
        <category>dublin,</category>
        
        <category>museum,</category>
        
        <category>tours</category>
        
        
        <category>ireland</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
